.
Pod 2 Dash has arrived at mission altitude. Now entering plan orbit.
Pod 8 still attempting to stabilize orbit. Insufficient altitude confirmed.
Continue operation as solo mission. Pod 2 Dash on point.
Roger. Pod 8 holding in support position. Shift to sub plan 7.
Pod 2 Dash has now breached PNR. Entering area 88.
Roger. Commence
operation US.
Roger. Pod 2 dash shifting into final mission orbit. Prepare for deceleration maneuver.
RCS in sync. Firing confirmed.
Igniting all stage 1 engines. Initiating burn.
Couplers preparing for separation. Confirming deceleration.
Jettisoning stage 1
booster units.
Separation confirmed. Electronic systems check.
Purging
remaining propellant.
Roger that. Burn timing on auto. Igniting all stage 2 engines.
Stage 2 decouplers preparing for separation. RCS syncing
reaching burn.
Jettisoning
stage 2 booster units.
Deceleration maneuver complete.
Preparing
to achieve final mission orbit. Begin RCS rollover burn. Commencing rotation.
Angle of
descent confirmed. No change in contact area.
Rechecking coordinates and altitude.
Rechecking values.
No
damage.
Orbit adjustment successful. Orbit initiating.
RCS rollover complete.
Roger. Pod 2 beginning transfer into intercept trajectory. Operation
will now commence. Disengaging
all remote guidance systems. All further control
will be local. Good luck.
On intercept orbit
to target. T-80 to contact. Target object
confirmed.
Do change to point
of contact.
Maintaining shift
M. No anomalies detected. Pod 2 prepare for
rendezvous.
Pod 8 has insufficient altitude and can only provide backup for the 96 seconds before re-entry.
Wrap it up quick.
Reflective waves from target area.
Hostiles incoming.
That's the automated defense system's kinetic weapon.
Not a problem.
Multiple
explosive flags.
Time to contact.
Three, two, one.
Second wave in the sky.
Pattern blue.
Stronger than a redback check.
Identifying.
Confermed as code 4A.
An anti-AT field!
Or you a little prick!
Damn it!
Screw this!
Help it!
Fine crony!
Quit that singing! You're kissing me off!
Some cover, Fire! You're two seconds late!
Then you shouldn't move into position three seconds early.
I'm going with a plus
improvise!
Damn it. The Princess beckons.
Your noble wish is my commit.
I've cleared the Fullerene Shift.
Reaching Final Defense is Area 89.
The
target object is
moving!
Hey!
Hospital Correction can't keep up!
I'm gonna go for a drop!
Decelerating!
8, 7, 6, 5, 4, 3, 2, 1, burn complete!
Fon 2 dash has jettison final boosters.
Minimum safe re-entry window secure.
Target seized and secure.
Ready to return Roger
we'll be waiting at the retrieval point
We're just about to attend three entry here
Boy, crony, cover me!
Sorry, no can do.
I've got insufficient altitude and I'm out of here.
You'll have to get your own back on this one.
Good luck.
Thanks for nothing.
Damn persistent jerk! This wasn't part of the mission briefing!
What is this, boy?
The AT field is a neutralizing engine!
I have got to take out that damn core block!
Where are you going? Come back here!
- Caution! The high angle of attack is ending. - Dammit!
I can't maintain my angle of descent!
At this rate, my aim is gonna burn up!
Two dash! Operational objective has top priority.
Do not release the target object!
Even if it means losing the agent, you don't think I know that already?!
Come on!
Do something, anything!
Idiot Shinji!
Please!
I've been waiting for you, Shinji Ikari.
Welcome home.
All cardio functions appear normal.
No signs of paralysis either.
Yes, his eyes are open.
Can you understand what I'm saying to you?
Where am I?
What's going on?
He's speaking clearly.
Seems fully cognizant.
I think I...
I
saved Ray, didn't I?
Yes.
He's exhibiting signs of a continuity of memory.
Um, is Ray here?
Do you recognize this person?
Uh, what?
You mean me?
He's self-aware.
He seems to be fine.
What's on my neck?
Do you feel comfortable or you should urinate?
Cargo loading 86% of ship.
N2 reactor in operation.
Maintain output at 90%.
No service
contact within a radius of 12.
Manly open the pressure vent.
Sky's all clear as well.
You don't have to
worry about the defense.
Make the D-block ship to the top priority.
We don't have enough
manpower
on the food restock.
Initializing gyro.
Get some more people on it.
ASAP.
Stabilizers show all green.
Workflow status for outfitting the ship.
Armament work is behind schedule by 3%.
There.
Subject, BM-03, now in custody.
Roger, undo the restraints.
You may leave now.
Unit number
106, supply operation.
-
- Check the wiring of the synchronized gun directors.
Number three in reporting errors.
- Misato?
- Shinji Ikari.
Can we call him that?
- Yes.
According to the physical analysis, he's a perfect match to the third child.
Every last detail, even his dental work, is an exact biological reproduction of him at N3I.
The deep synchronization test results are still being processed, though.
And what about the DSS Joker?
It's already been applied, Captain Katsuragi.
Captain Katsuragi?
So you are Misato.
What the...
It's operational.
And it's set to the captain's access code.
Understood.
What is this thing?
Will you please get it off of me?
Please?
You will never be allowed to take it off.
Not ever.
The interview's over.
Take him to quarantine.
Decoy 0-1 and 0-5 lost.
Wave
pattern detected.
Huh, what is that thing?
It's another pattern blue.
Target ID'd. Code 4C.
The Nemesis
Series.
They don't give up.
It's widening its formation.
All sides. They must want to pen us in before it attacks.
We're not ready to move yet.
Halt all operations except main engine outfitting.
All hands.
Battle stations condition 2.
Target all Nemesis Series entities.
Roger. All hands.
Battle stations condition 2.
Ready. AAA anti-surface, anti-sub.
Stats! Halt all supply ops! Crew transfer gets priority.
Ready anti-air, anti
-surface, anti-submersible ordnance systems!
Ready remote-controlled gun turrets and torpedo launch tubes!
All aircraft clear out of current airspace immediately.
Please proceed to assembly area.
Be all of the loaded cargo. Transfer of crew gets top priority.
Continue operations to element the ship.
Keep the assembly work going right up until we engage the enemy.
All turrets, prepare to fire.
Remote control activated. Initiating SDS system. Prepare for sudden engagement.
Hurry! Continue supplying power to the main engine conductors.
Crank it up. N2 reactor at 99%.
Continuing power injection. Vals up to number 90 have been opened.
Power pipeline connected.
N2
reactor first. Number three
and number four. All green.
Roger.
Vals up to number 90 have all been opened. Resuming power injection.
Power supply
to the
N2 reactor. APU is holding steady.
Insecting LCL circulation pumps.
Checking filtration.
Battle stations.
That means now, people.
You there, get it in
gear.
We're doing the best we can here, Chief.
We've got a makeshift crew,
and half these guys are civvies with no training.
Give us a break.
No excuses.
Run your station, not your mouth.
Damn whiners.
I hate these young men.
Let's
see.
Outfitting operations are suspended.
So next, close the bulkheads?
Is that it?
Okay, so aerial attacks show up here, and here's the sonar.
Kotakami, how's the deck maintenance coming?
The deck? I'm not in charge of that too, am I?
Yeah, among other things. Get to it!
What? Seriously?
There we go.
It won't be safe to
transport you.
We'll just stay put for now, okay?
Wow, to be here on the bridge during a
battle alert?
Talk about exciting!
All anti-air systems. Protect Unit 1 at all costs.
Unit one?
It's here!
Target pillars of light confirmed!
Um,
it looks like their numbers are increasing!
Unable to detect target's core blocks, it's most likely concealed within its camouflage cocoon.
This is serious. If we stay here, they're going to overwhelm us.
T-minus 600 seconds to contact!
Captain Katsuragi, I propose that we immediately disperse the fleet.
We're understaffed and our crew is inexperienced.
The ship isn't even fully outfitted.
And unless we're able to get a fix on those core blocks, we'll be fighting blind.
In other words, we have a 0% chance of winning.
Our only option is to retreat.
There's no other choice.
Captain Katsuragi!
We stop running.
We change the game and stop second-guessing ourselves.
XO, let's fly.
Wait, why? You don't mean not the main engine.
Oh, personnel,
prepare for takeoff.
Pride, main engine!
What?
Taking this ship into combat is complete madness, Captain.
I agree. We still need a test run.
It's too dangerous.
I have no experience with gravity control, and I'm not optimistic.
Can we stick to fighting battles we can win?
I'm not quite ready to die yet.
Nobody's ready to die when they die, kid.
I'd rather burn out than fade away.
What?
How did you get this old making decisions like that?
Damn the risks.
We will use the ship as bait to draw out the target.
Time we find out if this ship is capable of deicide.
But the ignition system hasn't even been installed yet.
Unless you're using an
Ava.
Mari?
Unit eight still not ready.
Asuka.
Asuka?
Yeah, yeah, I'm on it.
All I've got to do is punch the igniter in there, right?
It's up to you.
But the
containment field is dangerously strong near the main engine.
And your Ava is still being refitted.
Eh, whatever.
Like the Colonel always says, mission first, safety last.
No time to worry about it.
Unit two improved.
Go!
Ava, unit
two high.
Launch.
Roger. Unit two
improved in process of launching.
Next.
Motoring underwater motor and left container number one.
Drop.
Man, they give me this awesome new decked out unit,
and then they put me on maintenance duty.
It really is Unit 2.
Thank goodness.
Asuka pulled through.
Misato, what about me?
All hands, condition one, battle stations.
All
hands, condition one, battle stations.
I repeat, all hands. Condition one battle stations.
Engaging battle command system.
Essential personnel to battle bridge.
Prepare gravity ballasts for launch.
Roger. Now checking ventilation.
Centralized main ship controls in the anchoring plug.
Roger. Preparing for descent.
Injector, check. Starting countdown.
Ready, Kiernstam
tower movement.
Misato, put me in! Where's Unit 1?
I'll pilot it! Let me help Asuka!
You do need me to pilot it, don't you?
Misato!
You're
wrong. We have no need for you to pilot an Ava.
You have no need for me?
But then, what else can I do to help?
Misato!
Listen closely, Shinji.
From this moment on, you do nothing.
LCL gas build. Ionization density reached.
Start entry sequence.
LCL ionization state is normal.
Initiating all processing systems.
Status. Personnel headcount complete.
Crew transfer confirmed.
Primary launch checklist complete.
Closure of all bulkheads confirmed. Pressure check complete.
APU power output increasing.
Ignition
power in section to main engineering completion.
Five percent to threshold.
Initializing gyro compass. Stabilizers show all green.
Initiating visual display data processing. Activating main monitor.
Target still inbound. It's taking up an encircling formation.
Unit to improve now discarding UPV.
Switching out left arm.
It's showtime.
Yeah.
All right, then.
Let's do this.
AT field, deploy.
Shift and pillars of light.
Energy levels are rapidly increasing.
Entire formation closing in.
We lost a cruiser! Vaporized!
It's
a full-on blitz.
If it makes it to the ship, it's all over.
T-minus 360 seconds to contact.
Here goes nothing!
Unit 2 improved. Pracking ignition.
Injection pressure at 300%.
Ignore it! Direct all energy to the flywheel.
Priority one!
The seventh converter array has exploded!
Disregard the lines that have gone down.
Continue the forced injection.
Just ignore the damn pressure gauges.
Releasing pressure plate lock on flywheel.
Beginning rotation!
Main engine energy pump now operating.
Adjusting APU rotation power to 80%.
Drive in the cantilegation.
That just leaves.
T-minus 35 seconds.
Rotation rate increasing.
Unit
to improve an ignition position.
We've hit critical.
Flywheel energy at 102%.
Threshold reach.
Main engine priming.
Final stage.
Roger. Change helm systems.
Roger.
Time-space controls.
Switching to tri-axis helm systems.
Simultaneously deploy AT field with ignition.
36,000 RPM. All green.
Reactor contact. All green.
Skip countdown! Initiate contact!
Engage now!
Ignition!
Flight path, all clear!
All sectors check in! Evacuate escort ships!
Here we go.
Volnder, lift off!
*Eight rings penetrating! Damage unknown!
Never mind! Annihilate the enemy! Pitch down 90 degrees! Go astern!
Go astern! Aye aye, Captain!
DRAG THE CORN BLOCKS INTO THE OPEN!
HOLD THEM OUT OF THE CAMOUFULOUS COCOON!
VISSERS HOLDING IN RIGHT MAIN WINGPAPE!
HAL, MAINTAIN COURSE! TACA HOLD, GIVE ME FULL POWER!
ALL BACK SLOW!
MAXIMUM BATTLESPEED!
We got it!
The core blocks!
Now!
Turn hard to port! Swing them around!
Roger!
Emergency stock! Full thrusters!
Target inactive!
Main guns, prepare to fire!
Load energy AP routes. All turrets enable direct feed for main engine. Engage reload circuit!
Roger! Circuits engaged!
Refining measurements,
pinpointing max accuracy!
Range keeper synchronization on!
All turrets still have direct visual targeting. Manual tracking enabled.
That's good enough!
Fire!
Targets annihilated.
All stations, stand down to condition two.
Prepare to retrieve unit two improved.
Expedite repairs to main wings.
Amazing.
Wow, we
actually won.
That was absolutely insane.
Kaji said she was nuts, but I think he sold her short.
So this is the God Slayer's power.
Wunder.
A fitting name for a ship of hope.
*Loud
sound*
Subject BM-03. Tentative name Shinji Ikari. The XO is here to explain some things.
That's
Unit 1?
Correct. Unit 1 is being utilized as the main engine for this ship, which is why we don't need a pilot anymore.
I guess you really don't need me.
Also, your deep synchronization test results have come in.
The synchronization rate is 0.00.
Even if you did board an Ava, it wouldn't activate.
That's wonderful.
Isn't that great, Mr. Hikari?
Despite this, we cannot overlook the fact that you went into a state of awakening for 12 seconds earlier.
To avoid further incident, we've equipped you with a DSS choker.
Which is what exactly?
Call it an insurance policy.
It's a safety device that suppresses any potential awakening from occurring.
A symbol of our distrust.
And your punishment as well.
What do you mean, my punishment?
If you're ever to board an Ava while wearing that,
and your emotions begin to inexorably consume you to the threshold of an awakening,
that contingency will be suppressed at the cost of your life.
So that means...
You're saying it will kill me?
I won't deny it.
But that's... you'd...
Misato, you'd really let me die?
What the hell is going
on here?
This is so messed up, it doesn't make any sense!
I know this must be disorienting. Lieutenant?
Yes, ma'am.
State your name and rank to him.
It's, um, kind of late for this,
but I'm your attending medical officer.
Second Lieutenant Sakura Suzahara.
It's nice meeting you.
Oh, likewise.
Wait, Suzahara?
Toji's...
Yep. Thanks for being such a good friend to my brother.
I'm his little sister, Sakura.
His little sister? Don't you mean older?
Nope. I'm younger.
But that doesn't... How could you...
Because it's been 14 years since you've opened your dumb eyes.
Idiot, Shinji.
Asuka!
Thank goodness. I was so worried about you.
But you're okay.
I can't do it.
It won't stay back.
I can't hold it in any longer.
You can't
hold what in?
A whole lot of pent-up anger and sorrow.
I don't understand what you're...
Wait, Asuka, your left eye.
It's none of your damn business.
Asuka.
If 14 years have passed, how come you haven't changed except for your eye?
The curse. The curse of the Avas.
What does that mean?
Wait a minute! You gotta tell me!
Please! Please just tell me where Rey is!
No idea.
What do you mean, no idea?
I saved her! I know I did!
It doesn't even matter if you did.
We don't have time to worry about one measly person anymore.
Not in this world.
Isn't that right?
Colonel Katsuragi
Asuka!
Misato, tell me where Rei is
Please tell me!
If you must know
Rei Ayanami no longer exists in this world
That can't...
I know for a fact I saved her
She's probably still inside Unit 1's plug
You've got to check
she's in there
Shinji, we carefully searched every single inch of Unit 1
The only things left inside were you and this
We don't know why, but this was reconstructed.
The tests we ran on it were clean, so you can have it back.
This was my father's.
Ray had it on board with her.
Which means I must have saved her.
What's happening?
Talk to me.
The target's on the afterdeck. It just latched onto
us.
This must be the real deal.
All hands, Condition One, battle stations.
- Our tactic unit for the priority!
- Unit! Are you back in the game?
You bet
I am.
I'm on
it,
your highness.
But first things first, how was our little puppy?
Did he sit like a good little boy?
He's the exact same! Same stupid face topped with bedhead!
That goofy face of him, that's what you wanted to see, Brian.
Shut up! I went there to bat him one! And I feel better!
Misato!
Ritsuko! Tell me what's happening! Is it an angel attack?
Shinji Ikari, where are you?
That was Rey. Did you hear that?
That was Rey's voice! Risa!
Come on, what the hell?
We're ready, Mr. Ikari. You need to come with me.
Tell me, Shinji, where are you?
That is Rey.
Rey's looking for me!
Mr. Ikari, please hurry!
I've had enough.
Rey! I'm here!
Dammit! The central soldier!
This is the current attack.
Why the hell should I be, Sato?
You made it very clear that you don't need me!
Regardless, you're to remain in our custody!
Why? Just because you say so?
Stop it! Why are you letting them shoot an Eva?
Because it's an Eva! We'll destroy every last one of Nerve's Eva's.
Nerve's Eva's? But isn't this a part of Nerve 2?
No, we are Vilea. Our whole objective is to annihilate Nerve.
But that's... No!
Don't you realize that's Reya there?
It's not. I told you she no
longer exists.
You're lying!
She's there! Inside Unit Zero!
How can you be so blind? Just forget it!
No! Wait!
Do whatever you think is best!
As long as you never get in an A-bug!
I'm begging you, just anything but that!
Don't let him escape, all right, crony?
Sure thing, boss.
When I set my sights on a target, I never miss.
All right, come on.
How do you like that?
Is this the vessel of the atoms?
Hey, I'm talking to you! Come back here, jackass!
They didn't care about Unit 1, they just wanted him!
Which means they know he can still be used as the trigger!
Misato, use the choker now!
This is a director from the EXO. No need to pursue.
All personnel, resume emergency repairs and finish outfitting the ship.
Roger.
No need to pursue.
I've changed my mind.
He's not an idiot. He's a brat.
The
End
See, I knew I saved her, I knew it.
You lied, Misato.
Come with me.
So, um...
Isn't this the geofront?
Why can you see the sky?
Is that Nerve HQ?
What happened here?
She wasn't lying when she said 14 years have passed.
We're here.
What is that?
An Eva?
That's correct.
Father?
This is Evangelion Unit 13.
You will share this unit with your co-pilot.
Weren't you the one playing the piano?
When the time comes, the two of you will pilot the Ava.
This talk is over.
Wait! Where are you going, Father?
I need to talk to you! Tell me what's going on here!
Father!
There's no dial pad.
I guess they only want me to receive calls then.
Oh, yeah.
I really need to go thank her.
Hey Ray!
Where are you?
Ray!
Yay!
I wonder what this place is.
Is that Ray?
I didn't think I was going to find her.
Ray!
I've been looking everywhere.
Whoa!
Clothing!
Where are your...
Will you put some clothes on?
Is that an order?
I'm going to come in now.
Um, so, uh, I just wanted to say thanks for this.
Thanks for keeping it safe.
So I guess you got a new plug suit, huh?
Black is an interesting choice.
It's so strange.
Everything changed so much since yesterday.
None of this makes sense.
Why are Misato and the others fighting nerve now?
And what the hell is my dad up to?
And what happened to everyone?
Come on, Rey. Catch me up here.
I don't know.
I see.
I guess you wouldn't.
So, how did you make it out of Unit 1, anyway?
This place...
It's not even a proper room.
I know you've always been a minimalist, but still...
It's not like there's a school left.
So what do you do?
I wait for orders.
You don't even have any books.
Jeez, don't you get bored?
Books.
Does Rei Ayanami read books?
Yeah.
You used to read all the time.
You loved reading.
I see.
Tell you what, I'll try to find some books in the library and bring them to you.
Um, are English books okay?
You like those, right?
You always seem to have one with you.
Like?
Yeah.
At least I thought you did.
What is... like...
No word from Sele?
I take it they're still maintaining their silence?
The human instrumentality project will be enacted as per the Dead Sea Scrolls.
At this point, there is no further need for them to speak.
Ikari, do you intend to employ Unit 13 for the next mission?
Well, I...
No matter, I'll go along with whatever you have planned.
For Yui's sake, at least.
Huh.
I guess it's broken.
You do nothing.
It's none of your
damn business.
As long as you never get in an
Ava!
Pilot the Ava.
I don't know.
Why don't you come down here, Shinji?
Let's talk.
I thought you wanted to talk.
This isn't exactly what I thought you meant.
Playing piano with four hands is a conversation,
just in scales.
Yeah, but I don't think I can do this.
If you want to live your life,
you can't be afraid of the change
that comes with trying new things.
It's easy.
You just take your hands and use them to play these keys down here
Go on you've just got to jump in
This is great.
I like playing music with you.
Sounds are so much fun.
Isn't it nice what two people can do?
Thank you.
That's the first time I've had fun in forever.
Yeah, me too.
Let's do it again.
Anytime you want.
Sound good, Shinji?
What's your...
Kaworu Nagisa, I'm a child burdened with a predestined fate just like you.
She's still not here. And she didn't even touch the books.
Hey, good morning, Shinji.
You're here bright and early.
I don't really have anything else to do.
*music*
Are there any
techniques I can learn to get better?
Don't worry about playing well.
Just create sounds that feel good to you.
Well, I think what would feel good is if I could get better at playing.
Then keep practicing.
Just repeat the same thing over and over
until you're finally happy with the way it makes you feel.
That's all you can do.
*music*
Sure, no problem. I know I can get it working again.
Really? Thank you.
I feel bad asking you on top of everything else you've done.
Don't feel bad about it. We're friends, after all.
It's starting to get dark, huh?
Guess we should call it a day.
Hey, wait. Let's stay a little longer.
We can hang out and look at the stars.
The stars?
So you like looking at the stars.
Yeah.
Taking in the vastness
of this universe.
It's given me this feeling of serenity
ever since I was a little kid.
In 14 years, nothing out there has changed,
which is comforting.
It makes me feel like the things that happen to me
don't really matter,
and there's something peaceful about that.
I mean, if that even makes sense.
The sentiment came across just fine.
Shunning change.
You prefer the empty, indifferent world of the abyss.
That's so like you.
This is nice, the two of us lying here talking.
Who knew something so simple would feel so good?
Thank you for asking me to spend time with you.
Oh, no, it's nothing.
I just figured that, you know, that it might be fun to look at the stars.
It is fun.
I now realize I was born to meet you, Shinji.
That's different.
This one's a little big on me.
Here. It should work just fine.
Thank you.
You're amazing, Kaworu.
It's like you can do anything.
It's nothing but applied knowledge.
I've just had more time on this world
to pick these things up than you.
Well, it's still
amazing.
You seem rather deflated.
Is something wrong?
I just can't stop thinking about my friends.
Your old friends?
Yeah.
There used to be a city above Nerve headquarters,
and everyone
lived up there.
Toji and Kinsuke, all of my classmates.
I was apparently catatonic inside Unit 1 for an entire 14 years,
and everything changed.
It changed so much while I was in there.
and those changes are too much for you.
You're in pain.
I'm just kind of worried
of what's happened
to the city and everyone in it.
It's the not knowing,
the wondering.
It...
It scares me to death.
Do you want to know?
Oh, fuck!
Come on, we're almost there.
There'll be a break in the clouds,
and you'll get all of the answers you're looking for.
What is all this?
This is the result of your assimilation with Unit 1.
The result of the third impact.
You mean...
everyone I knew?
This planet is no stranger when it comes to mass extinctions.
They actually help to spur on evolution.
After all, most life forms transform themselves to adapt to the world.
The Lilin are unique in that regard.
They labor to transform the world instead of themselves.
They instituted a ritual that would expedite the process and artificially evolve them.
A ritual that sacrifices an older life form in order to give the fruit of life to a new one and make way for its reign.
It's a programmed extinction devised and pursued since ancient times.
Nerve labeled this ritual the Human Instrumentality Project.
The Nerve did this?
My father, what is he doing?
Listen, Shinji.
Once it awakened,
Ava Unit 1 opened the gates of Gaff,
and it became the catalyst for the third impact,
what the Lillan called the near third impact.
Someone brought all of this about.
You were the one.
No.
I didn't mean to.
I just...
I just wanted to save Ray.
Perhaps.
But you were still the trigger.
This can't be.
You can't put this on me.
You blame me for this, but I can't do anything about it.
You're right.
You can't do anything to change the past.
But this is the truth you wanted to know.
As a consequence, the Lilin have forced you to bear the wages of that sin.
Isn't that what this thing around your neck represents?
My sin?
I didn't do anything!
This has got nothing to do with me!
I'm afraid the others don't see it that way.
However, all sins can be atoned for.
There is still hope, Shi-ji.
There will always be hope.
The Sele boy seems to have made contact with the third child.
He's even revealed the outside world to him.
I can only imagine how he must be taking it.
You're okay with this, Ikari?
We'll take it upon ourselves to rewrite Sele's script.
The whole of existence is nothing more than a tool for revision.
And you feel opening up to your son,
telling him about your life's work won't help?
I can't honestly say I believe that.
Why did this happen?
Things weren't supposed to end up this way.
I mean, I saved Ray, didn't I?
Isn't that good
enough?
She's not here again.
She still hasn't read them.
What the hell? Ray too? How can she treat me this way?
Tell me, third child, do you know how to play Shogi?
Well, sure, I know the rules.
That's good enough.
Let's
play a game then.
I'll even spot you the rook and bishop.
You have to quiet your mind and make it calm.
It's a necessary task in order to win battles.
You have only 31 moves before you're in checkmate.
This should be more enjoyable.
Noel, thank you for taking the time to humor an old man with his hobby.
I'm easily daunted as well, you see.
Without some sort of pretext, I doubt I would have been able to speak with you like this.
Tell me, do you remember much of your mother?
No.
I was so little when she...
And then, my father, he got rid of all of her belongings.
She looks just like...
Is that Rey?
That woman is your mother.
Her name was Yui Ayanami.
She was a student of mine at the university.
And now she serves as the control system for Ava Unit 1.
It seems the power has finally been restored.
This is the prototype of the Ava's control system.
Yui devised the method of direct entry into the core,
and she attempted it with herself as the test subject in this very system.
You watched it happen, too, although your memories have since been erased.
Upon entry, she disappeared within the system.
All that remains of her is the data used for the Ayanami series.
The Rei Ayanami that you came to know was nothing more than a replicant of your mother.
And like your mother before her, that girl is now stored and within the system of Unit 1.
And it's all part of your father's plan.
This can't be true.
It's shocking how simple it is to tear the world apart.
Although, rebuilding it from scratch is not so easy.
Like time itself, the course of the world cannot be reversed, nor can people's hearts.
Which is why, in order to make his wish come true, Ikari is making a bounty of sacrifices, including his very own soul.
I felt it was only right that you know some of the truth, and to know about your father.
Such a painfully unpleasant role.
Yui.
I hope this is what you wanted.
The time of the final covenant is near.
We'll see each other soon, Yui.
Why haven't you read any of the books I've left for you?
I haven't been
ordered to.
Ordered to?
Then just forget it!
Tell me.
You are Rei, right?
Yes. Rei Ayanami.
Then I... I did save you, didn't I?
I don't know.
Shinji?
I didn't really save her.
I lost Rey.
Father.
Mother.
Misato.
What have I been doing
with
my life?
*Screams*
So, the final executor is at last complete.
Yes, we now possess all the
tools we need.
The moment has arrived.
It's finally time, Shinji Ikari.
I won't!
I'll never pilot an Eiba again!
I couldn't even save Rei!
Nothing good could come from piloting an Ava.
I'm done. I won't do it.
You hear me?
And replaying the same traumatic refrain in your mind over and over again?
What good can possibly come of that?
Nothing good comes from anything.
You were the one who showed it to me.
That lifeless red world.
The changes that were inflicted by an Ava can be changed once again with an Ava.
It doesn't matter.
Eva's father, Misato.
I can't trust anything anymore.
But you can trust me, Shinji.
I don't know that.
Misato and the others locked this thing around my neck.
I can't get it in Eva again.
They told me it'll kill me if I do.
I just don't want anything to do with Eva's.
I understand.
The Lilin's curse and the risk of an Eva awakening.
I'll bear this burden for you.
But Kawaro...
Don't let it bother you.
The Lilin actually made this choker because they were afraid of me.
I've been planning on doing this anyway.
Listen to me, Shinji.
Your only hope is to retrieve the two spears from the heart of Central Dogma.
They're the key to initiating the human instrumentality project.
The two of us can wield those spears.
Without them, Nerve will be incapable of triggering the fourth impact.
But in our hands, together with Unit 13, they will grant us the power to restore the world.
You're right.
Yeah.
I know you can pull it off.
But not by myself, with you.
Ava Unit 13 is equipped with a double-entry system.
Together, we can restore the hope of the Lillan.
And that's what you need most right now.
Above all else, you need hope.
Atonement and peace of mind will help you get that.
You're amazing.
You really have me figured out.
That's because the only thing I do is think about you.
Kaoru, thank you.
Of course. We're friends.
Yeah. You really are a great friend.
It'll be like playing the piano.
Good things happen when we're together.
Right, Shinji?
Right.
Let's go, Kaoru.
I don't know.
Evangelion Unit 13, go!
It's the signal.
A new avi unit has been activated.
I thought this was just you and me.
What, you mean Mark
9?
She's here for backup, just in case Vila tries to intervene.
But why?
We could handle them on our own.
She's not even the real Rey.
I'm not Rey, so I'm...
The walls!
Yes, the remains of those who fell short of infinity.
It's nothing for you to worry about.
We're almost at Lilith's seal.
The main shaft is completely blocked by it.
Not once in 14 years has it allowed anyone to pass it.
Oh.
It looks just like a giant lid.
It'll be okay. Unit 13 was specifically designed to overcome it.
The two of us can get past it.
We need to be in sync, just like playing the piano together.
All right, Shinji, here we go.
*Squeak
We made it.
The lowest level of central dogma.
The epicenter of the third impact.
Is that Lilith?
What remains of her.
You're looking at her corpse.
Poor Misato.
She risked her life to protect it.
Is that an Ava?
It
is.
What's
left of Ava Mark VI.
The Lilin modified it to be autonomous.
And that's the wreckage left from their attempt.
Those things sticking out of Lilith.
That's what we're here for?
Exactly.
Bonginus and Cassius.
Removing them requires two souls.
That's the only way they can even be retrieved.
Hence the necessity of the double entry system.
Well, if that's all,
couldn't she just as easily have taken my place?
Not at all.
A replica can't take a Lilin's place.
Its soul resides in a different place than ours.
Now then, let's begin.
Hold on a second.
Something's off.
What's the matter, Kaworu?
This isn't right.
They seem to have shifted in form.
They're matching now.
Let's just hurry and pull them out.
That's what we came down here for now, isn't it?
Let's...
What the hell is going on?
Unit 2?
Asuka!
What are you doing?
Stop, Asuka!
Idiot,
Shinji!
Don't tell me you're dumb enough to pilot Naeva!
I guess I am.
But it's different.
I'm gonna change the world!
You damn brat!
Haven't you changed enough?
Late
again! Can
you try to be on time?
My bad!
Well, hello there, vessel of the atoms.
I know I can't blow your head off, but I can at least keep you on the ground.
*Bang*
You've already caused one impact!
Listen to me!
With those spears, we can redo everything!
We can save the world with them!
You are so damn naive.
You just don't get it!
How about a little help, Kaworu?
Cassius and Longinus.
It's imperative we get both Spears.
But these two look identical, like they're one and the same.
Hey, come on!
So that's it.
Now I understand.
Lillan!
Hey, little Miss Provisional Sailor Pilot.
You can hear me, right?
I think about getting out of that Ava
before it goes all vessel of the atoms.
I can't. Those aren't my given orders.
Man, you are uptight.
I miss your original version.
She was a whole lot friendlier.
Original?
A different me?
Kauru!
What's wrong with you?
No!
Asuka!
I'm begging you!
Please let me do this!
Just lie down and take your punishment!
Quit fighting!
Are you serious?
Moron Crony, the spear!
Now's our chance to grab them!
You hit a woman when she's not looking, you bastard.
Here's your spear, Highness.
We should turn around, Shinji.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
You can't be serious, Kaworu!
After everything we've gone through to get them?
You don't get
it.
Those aren't the spears we need.
They're not!
But how?
You're the one who said we needed these spears!
That's the only reason that I'm even in this damn Ava!
The control system!
I'm doing this for you, Kaoru.
For you and everyone else I know.
I have to make everything right again.
If I can restore the world, then even Misato will...
Oh, no.
Four-eyed crony, I've cleared all the obstacles.
Permission to use AA ammo.
I was hoping you'd say that.
Here's my ace in the hole.
There's no AT field.
Their unit.
It can be.
Don't do it, Shinji.
Stop it, you crap!
Ahhhh!
Fieldski, let's begin.
Ava Mark 6?
Hold on, pattern blue?
What the hell is going on?
Oh no!
The 12th Angel is showing signs of life!
Corrid, Colonel!
Container 3!
On the way!
I'm not letting the third impact start back up!
This
thing is dead!
This was my order.
An angel!
Hey, highness.
You're wasting ammo blasting away like that.
That thing is all core.
It's pointless. We can't even make a dent in it.
Besides, even if we defeat the final angel, who knows what'll pop out next?
That'd be a real sight.
Is that...
It is.
It's me.
What am I?
I can't...
It's not responding!
What's wrong with it?
Kaoru!
Are you okay?
To think that I could have been so easily ensnared.
Me, the first angel, utterly defeated by the 13th.
What are you talking about?
What do you mean?
It means that the end and the beginning are one and the same.
All devised by the king of the Lilin.
All devised by your father.
The
DSS choker's detecting a pattern blue?
But the 13th isn't supposed to exist.
So this is what Gendo was after all this time.
The time has come to revise the covenant of the Dead Sea Scrolls.
Now we say farewell.
Though you may have transformed the shapes of your souls,
you are still life forms gifted with the fruit of knowledge.
You might be capable of living for eternity, but just like the rest of us, you cannot evade death when it comes for you.
You assisted the evolution of those burdened with mortality by granting us the sophistication of civilization.
On behalf of all mankind, I'm deeply grateful.
In granting your demise, we honor your souls by returning them to their rightful place.
Be assured your human instrumentality project
And the deicide you've long sought
Will be carried out for you
Please rest peacefully
Our wish for mankind has already come to pass
And behold, it is good
All is very good
May the instrumentality of humanity come about
As well as the peaceful purification of souls
*Gunshot*
We're too late. It's going beyond
the pseudo-DNS phase.
That thing's awakened already. Must be a straggler, Adam.
*Mario screams*
What's happening?
What the hell is this?
Is this my fault?
because I pulled out the spears?
This can't be.
It's the fourth impact.
You're witnessing the opening rites.
Kado!
The collar!
Misato!
18 field at maximum!
Distill the EVA inside!
All main guns ready Solveld!
Load high angle rounds!
We're preventing the fourth impact at all costs!
Fire!
We've been hit!
Main gun down!
The vessel of the atoms!
Citral block hit!
Damage unknown!
New
model A-bet is breaking free!
We're not responding.
We're going down.
*Emergency crash
*
Oh, man!
Holy crap.
This situation is
right
on the verge of Boobar.
You cover the brats, Ava.
I'll do what I can to help Wunder.
Roger, we can't shake the vessel of the atoms!
An identified data
infiltrating the main control system.
It's taking over control of the entire ship!
You have to stop today!
No fair! Of course, Zaley's playing dirty!
After mode!
Come triple seven!
Who the hell are you?
Report from observation deck. It's Unit 2. She's engaging the vessel.
I'm counting on you, Asuka.
*Squeaking
We're gonna go!
This bastard's whole body is the car!
We're out of time!
Unitube, please! Forgive me!
The control system's back on, Marek!
I can't! Emergency takeoff!
Immediately pursue the target, Eva!
Captain, we can't do
that while the main engine is down.
Shinji!
Is this really my fault?
Because
I...
Because I...
It's not your fault, Shinji.
This is happening because I've become the 13th angel.
I'm the trigger, not you.
What do I do?
Kaoru.
What should...
What should I do?
Even after a soul is gone,
Its wishes and curses still cling to this world.
Its will will hew to the world's information
and transform it.
In time, we rewrite the very nature of who we are.
I'm sorry.
This is not the happiness you wanted and deserved.
I'll close the gates of Goth.
I don't want you to worry anymore, Shinji.
Kaoru.
I don't understand what you're telling me!
I don't understand!
Keep looking, Shinji. I know you'll find peace in a place where you belong.
Let the ties that bind be your guide.
Hey, try not to look so sad.
We'll meet again, Shinji.
Kauru!
The gates of Goff still aren't closing.
Puppy
boy must be
Sele's insurance!
Everything is wrapped up here!
Snap out of it! Pod together!
Stop being a baby!
You can at least save the princess!
Get up, King!
Hear me? And while you're at it, quit being so
damn naive!
What a horrific mess.
Almost precisely following Sele's designs.
Not true.
We did eliminate Sele's child,
and we successfully led Unit 13 to its awakening.
Even Colonel Katsaragi acted as expected.
This will do fine for now.
All hands, maintain alert status condition two.
No pattern blue readings detected.
Monitored airspace remains clear.
Emergency repairs to midship area complete.
We've managed to avert a fourth impact.
No idea why.
Misato, let's just call this a win for now.
*BOOM
*
*Sigh*
All you do is think about yourself.
You think shutting up is the answer.
Still acting like a baby
Even after all these years you're the same old annoying brat come on put this on I
Swear can't you even stand up on your own damn feet?
You're that pilot right from the first batch of Iyanami types
The L containment field density is too strong for them to rescue us here.
We've got to move somewhere the Lilin can get close to.
Come on!
The flower that was just opened
The flower that was just shining
This year is too early
In the end
You are the one who
I am the following steps
Everybody might be alive
In the end
No one can't wait
I can't believe it
I can't wait
I'm sorry.
I love you.
teaches him what it means to hope.
The instrumentality project is finally set in motion.
Phile makes a bid for one last showdown
to prevent the final impact.
The Wunder cleaves to the skies.
Ava unit eight plus two tears across
the red wasteland of the earth.
Next time, Sheen Evangelion, theatrical edition.
And as always, we'll keep the fan service
coming to the very end.