Speaker 1: The old man like a poor man,
Speaker 1: the young man,
Speaker 1: the story of the young man.
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now
Speaker 1: Even if you're in the door, you're smiling and smiling.
Speaker 1: It's so easy to touch, but I'm not sure how to reach.
Speaker 1: I don't know what you're still knowing.
Speaker 1: I don't know what to do.
Speaker 1: It's hard to see, right?
Speaker 1: The back of your back is a way to see the future.
Speaker 1: The hell of a god of the天使,
Speaker 1: I will soon fly away from the window.
Speaker 1: I will be able to fly with hot dogs,
Speaker 1: I will be afraid of the memories.
Speaker 1: I'm going to
Speaker 2: Retrieve it! Hurry!
Speaker 3: The target has gone silent!
Speaker 3: What's Shinji's status?
Speaker 2: He's alive!
Speaker 4: Unit 1 has been recovered. Send him to the 7th cage.
Speaker 2: I'm going to the cage. Take over for me, please.
Speaker 5: Unit 1 secured.
Speaker 5: The pilot's brainwaves are extremely erratic.
Speaker 5: His cardiac readings are very weak!
Speaker 5: Increase the power to the life support systems.
Speaker 5: Give him a heart massage.
Speaker 5: Roger.
Speaker 5: Heartbeat stabilized.
Speaker 5: Force eject the
Speaker 2: entry plug.
Speaker 2: Hurry!
Speaker 2: Emergency LCL discharge.
Speaker 2: Roger.
Speaker 2: Come on, open the hatch.
Speaker 2: Come on!
Speaker 6: *Bang
*
*Evil*
Speaker 3: Its accelerated particle beam cannon has hit the balloon. The decoy's been vaporized.
Speaker 2: Next one.
*Squeak*
Speaker 3: The Type 12 Mortar has been vaporized!
Speaker 2: Yeah, I see that.
Speaker 3: From the data we've collected, we're assuming
Speaker 7: the Angel automatically attacks any opponents
Speaker 7: that come within a certain range.
Speaker 7: Hmmm...
Speaker 7: that range will be targeted.
Speaker 7: It's too risky for close range combat in an Ava, isn't it?
Speaker 2: What's the status of its AT field?
Speaker 7: It's still active.
Speaker 7: It's strong enough that the spatial changes in phase are visible.
Speaker 7: And needless to say, using conventional means of attack,
Speaker 7: guided missiles, artillery, and bombs
Speaker 7: would inflict more damage on us than on the Angel.
Speaker 2: Yeah,
Speaker 7: offensively
Speaker 2: and defensively, it's almost perfect.
Speaker 2: A real flying fortress.
Speaker 2: What's the Angel's current location?
Speaker 8: At this moment, the target is directly above us,
Speaker 8: penetrating the Tokyo-3 null zone.
Speaker 8: A giant shield with a diameter of 17.5 meters
Speaker 7: is boring towards Nerve HQ.
Speaker 7: That's it then. It appears the enemy is going to attack Nerve headquarters directly.
Speaker 2: Sassy bastard! What's its estimated time of arrival?
Speaker 7: 6 minutes, 54 seconds AM,
Speaker 8: just after midnight.
Speaker 8: By that time, it will have breached all 22 levels of defense armor,
Speaker 8: and will penetrate headquarters itself.
Speaker 2: Less than 10 hours.
Speaker 3: The shield has contacted the first armor plate.
Speaker 9: What kind of condition is Unit 1 in?
Speaker 9: Well, Unit 1's defensive armor was melted down to the third layer.
Speaker 9: But the good news is that the central control unit sustained no damage.
Speaker 9: Given three more seconds, it would have
Speaker 4: shot right through the
Speaker 7: Ava.
Speaker 7: It'll take three hours to install replacement parts.
Speaker 4: Understood. What's Unit Zero's status?
Speaker 4: The reactivation of Unit Zero shouldn't prove a problem,
Speaker 4: but there's still a feedback error remaining.
Speaker 4: So it wouldn't...
Speaker 4: Survive combat.
Speaker 4: What's the
Speaker 2: condition of Unit One's pilot?
Speaker 7: No physical damage.
Speaker 7: However, nerve pulses are up by 0.8.
Speaker 7: That's still within the acceptable limits.
Speaker 3: Enemy arrival, 9 hours, 55 minutes.
Speaker 2: Talk about high-pressure situations.
Speaker 7: Why don't we raise a white flag?
Speaker 2: Before we do that, there's just one more little thing that I'd like to try.
Speaker 3: You want to use a sniper to shoot the target from outside its firing zone?
Speaker 2: Yes, sir. Instead of trying to neutralize the target's AT field, I believe a pinpoint shot with a focused high-energy beam is the only way.
Speaker 5: What do the Magi say?
Speaker 5: The
Speaker 2: responses from the Magi supercomputers were two affirmative and one conditional affirmative.
Speaker 5: Our probability of success is
Speaker 7: 8.7%.
Speaker 2: It's the highest value we could get.
Speaker 2: I
Speaker 7: see no reason to reject your plan. You may proceed, Captain Katsuraki.
Speaker 9: Yes, sir.
Speaker 9: You know how crazy this whole operation is, don't you? Operations Director Katsuraki.
Speaker 9: Don't
Speaker 2: be rude. It's not crazy. It can be done within nine hours and has the highest chance of success.
Speaker 9: It does? Really?
Speaker 9: But our positron rifle can't handle such a high output. What are you going to do about
Speaker 2: that?
Speaker 2: If ours won't work, we'll borrow one.
Speaker 9: We'll borrow one?
Speaker 2: You don't mean...
Speaker 2: Yeah, the SSDF's new prototype.
Speaker 2: I've come on behalf of NERV to hereby requisition the prototype self-propelled positron cannon as of 1500 hours today.
Speaker 10: But this is just... so ridiculous!
Speaker 2: We'll do our best to return this in as close to its original condition as we can.
Speaker 2: Thank you for your cooperation. Have a nice day.
Speaker 2: It's all yours, Ray! Take it away!
Speaker 2: What the?
Speaker 2: Be careful, that's a piece of precision machinery!
Speaker 2: Can I believe
Speaker 10: this? I cannot believe this.
Speaker 7: But ma'am, our latest calculations show that it'll take at least 180 million kilowatts to penetrate that Angel's AT field.
Speaker 7: Just where exactly are you planning on getting that much electricity?
Speaker 2: Where do you think I'll get it? All over Japan!
Speaker 2: We apologize for interrupting our regular programming for this emergency bulletin.
Speaker 2: From 11.30pm tonight until tomorrow morning, there will be a large-scale power blackout throughout most of Japan.
Speaker 2: We
Speaker 11: appreciate your cooperation.
Speaker 11: Repeat, from 11.30pm tonight until tomorrow morning, there will be a large-scale power blackout throughout most of Japan.
Speaker 11: We appreciate your cooperation.
Speaker 11: *Bell rings*
*Bell rings*
Speaker 10: The shield
Speaker 11: has just broken
Speaker 2: through the seventh defensive layer.
Speaker 2: What's the status on the energy supply system?
Speaker 7: Um, we're running about 3.2% behind schedule, but we should be finished by 2310.
Speaker 2: And the positron rifle?
Speaker 7: For the honor of Technology Development Department Section 3,
Speaker 8: we bet that we'll have it built in 3 hours!
Speaker 9: And how's our defense coming?
Speaker 9: Well, a shield is about the best we can come up with.
Speaker 9: So, is this the shield?
Speaker 9: Yes, it was sort of part of the space shuttle.
Speaker 9: It may look ugly, but it's got an electromagnetic base coating
Speaker 9: that Section 2 guarantees will stand up to the enemy's particle beam
Speaker 9: for at least 17 seconds.
Speaker 9: Pretty impressive, huh?
Speaker 9: Good work, Ritsuko.
Speaker 2: What about the sniper position?
Speaker 7: Taking geographical features and access to power transformers into consideration,
Speaker 7: this is our best choice.
Speaker 2: Right, everything's looking good.
Speaker 2: Our sniper will attack from the top of Mount Futago.
Speaker 2: We will commence at zero hours tomorrow morning.
Speaker 2: From this point on, this operation is called Operation Yashima!
Speaker 10: Roger.
Speaker 2: Now the only remaining problem is the pilot.
Speaker 12: Unit 1's pilot is conscious now. His examination results look normal.
Speaker 2: Good. Then the operation will proceed as planned.
Speaker 12: Roger.
Speaker 2: But I wonder if he'll pilot it again.
Speaker 12: Let's
Speaker 2: get to Mt. Vuntago now!
*phone rings*
*cough*
Speaker 13: *phone
rings*
Speaker 13: Ayanami.
Speaker 13: Pilot Ikari, I've been sent here to brief you on the Operation Yashima timetables.
Speaker 13: The operation will begin at midnight zero hundred hours.
Speaker 13: Prior to that, pilots Ikari and Aionami will arrive at the cage by 17:30.
Speaker 13: At 1800, Unit 1 and Unit 0 will activate.
Speaker 13: At 18:05, both units will be deployed.
Speaker 13: They will arrive at the temporary base at Mount Futago at 18:30.
Speaker 13: There, they will await further orders.
Speaker 13: Here, this is a new one.
Speaker 13: Oh?
Speaker 13: Don't show up looking like that, Pilot
Speaker 14: Ikari.
Speaker 14: Oh...
Speaker 14: Oh!
Speaker 14: Sorry.
Speaker 14: I've been apologizing since yesterday.
Speaker 14: Your meal.
Speaker 13: I don't feel like eating anything.
Speaker 13: We will be departing in 60 minutes.
Speaker 14: Do I really have to pilot Ava again?
Speaker 14: Yes, you do.
Speaker 14: I don't want to!
Speaker 14: You can be so cool about it because you haven't had the kind of experiences I've had yet.
Speaker 14: I don't want to go through it again!
Speaker 14: Then you can just stay here
Speaker 13: in bed.
Speaker 13: What do you mean by that?
Speaker 13: I will pilot Eva Unit 1.
Speaker 13: Dr. Okagi is already prepared to rewrite the personal data files for Unit 1.
Speaker 13: Ritsuko is?
Speaker 13: Captain Katsuragi and Dr. Okagi will be waiting for me in the cage.
Speaker 13: Hey!
Speaker 13: Goodbye.
*Sigh*
Speaker 7: They're really late.
Speaker 3: We ought to evacuate to the shelter.
Speaker 3: No way! I hacked into my dad's data files!
Speaker 3: I'm absolutely sure this is the time it's said.
Speaker 3: Well, okay then. Where in the heck are they?
Speaker 3: Oh!
Speaker 3: The entire mountain is moving!
Speaker 3: There they are! The Evangelions!
Speaker 9: Totally awesome!
Speaker 6: Go
Speaker 10: for it, Evangelions!
Speaker 10: We believe in you!
Speaker 10: Go, we believe in you! Yeah!
Speaker 10: Go Evangelion! Yeah!
Speaker 3: The shield has penetrated through the 17th layer of armor.
Speaker 3: It will reach headquarters in 3 hours, 55 minutes.
Speaker 7: Power supply stations from Shikoko and Kyosho areas completed.
Speaker 2: Beginning test of each cooling system.
Speaker 9: That's a very delicate piece of machinery. Handle it carefully.
Speaker 9: This thing wasn't built for field operations.
Speaker 9: Will it really work?
Speaker 9: Point taken, but we have no choice. This was the most expedient way of achieving our goal.
Speaker 9: Are you sure it's safe to use?
Speaker 9: Theoretically, yes. However, we're not sure if the cannon barrel and accelerator will be able to handle the stress or not.
Speaker 9: This is the first time it's ever been fired with such a high power output behind it.
Speaker 9: Listen up. Here are the battle plans for the operation. Shinji.
Speaker 9: Yes?
Speaker 9: Your Unit 1 will be the gunner.
Speaker 9: Right.
Speaker 9: Rei, you will cover him with Unit 0.
Speaker 9: Yes.
Speaker 9: The reason for this arrangement is because Shinji has a higher sync ratio with Unit 1,
Speaker 9: and this operation will require an exceptionally high degree of precision.
Speaker 9: Since the positron beam will be influenced by the Earth's gravity, magnetic fields, and rotation,
Speaker 9: it will not fire in a straight line.
Speaker 9: You must remember to adjust for these deviations.
Speaker 9: You must penetrate the core precisely.
Speaker 9: But Ritsuka, I've never practiced with this before.
Speaker 9: Don't worry. Just do what the manual says.
Speaker 9: As soon as the indicators in the center converge, just pull the trigger.
Speaker 9: The computers will handle the rest.
Speaker 9: Also, be aware that before you can fire the rifle a second time,
Speaker 9: you will first have to wait for the unit to cool,
Speaker 9: then replace the fuses and reload.
Speaker 9: You've got to hit it the first time.
Speaker 9: What if I miss? Or the enemy shoots back?
Speaker 9: Shinji, don't even think about something like that.
Speaker 9: You've got to destroy the Angel with your first shot.
Speaker 14: So I have no choice.
Speaker 13: I... I'm just to defend Unit 1, is that correct?
Speaker 13: Yes.
Speaker 13: Understood.
Speaker 2: It's time. Get geared up.
Speaker 2: Right.
Speaker 14: Maybe this will be our last day alive.
Speaker 14: Why would you say something like that?
Speaker 13: You won't die.
Speaker 13: I'll be protecting you.
*music*
Speaker 14: Ayanami, just why do you pilot this thing?
Speaker 14: Because I'm bonded to it.
Speaker 14: You're bonded?
Speaker 13: Yes. It's a
Speaker 14: bond.
Speaker 14: You mean to my father?
Speaker 14: To all people.
Speaker 14: You're very strong, Rei.
Speaker 14: I have nothing else.
Speaker 14: What do you mean you have nothing else?
Speaker 14: It's time.
Speaker 13: Let's go.
Speaker 13: Goodbye, Shinji.
Speaker 11: The time is approaching zero hundred hours.
Speaker 7: Commencing operation.
Speaker 2: Listen, Shinji.
Speaker 2: We're entrusting you with the energy of the entire nation of Japan.
Speaker 2: I'm counting on you.
Speaker 7: Roger.
Speaker 2: Initiate primary connection. Do it!
Speaker 7: Initiating power transmission from districts numbers 1 through 803.
Speaker 11: Voltage is rising. Water exchange unit reaching pressure zone.
Speaker 7: All cooling systems operating on full power.
Speaker 11: Temperature's stable. No problem is detected.
Speaker 11: Roger. Positron charge is nominal.
Speaker 11: Initiate second connection.
Speaker 11: All accelerators are engaging.
Speaker 11: Activate the convergence unit now.
Speaker 8: Transmitting all power to Mount Futago, temporary substation.
Speaker 8: No problems reported with third connection.
Speaker 12: Release final safety systems.
Speaker 7: Release final safety lock.
Speaker 12: Air correction for Earth rotation and gravity is 0.0009.
Speaker 12: Voltage is 0.2 short of critical.
Speaker 6: Seventh
Speaker 5: and tenth connections engaged!
Speaker 5: Transmitting all energy to the positron rifle!
Speaker 5: Nine, eight, seven, six, five,
Speaker 6: four, no! Not again!
Speaker 10: Three, two, one!
Speaker 10: Fire now!
*Evil Scream
Speaker 3: The shield has broken into the geo front.
Speaker 5: - Hurry, second shot.
Speaker 5: - Replacing fuses, initiating recharge.
Speaker 5: - Barrel cooling in progress.
Speaker 5: - We've got another high energy reading building
Speaker 5: inside the target.
Speaker 4: - Not now.
Speaker 4: - Ah!
Speaker 4: - Look
Speaker 6: out,
Speaker 2: Shinji!
Speaker 2: - Ah!
Speaker 10: - Oh!
Speaker 5: - Ayunami!
Speaker 5: The shield can't last long!
Speaker 5: Are we ready?
Speaker 5: 10 more seconds!
Speaker 5: Arrgh!
Speaker 5: Hurry up!
Speaker 10: Hurry up!
Speaker 10: Arrgh!
Speaker 10: Yeah! We made
Speaker 2: it!
Speaker 10: Ayanami!
Speaker 10: *Gunshot
Speaker 10: Ayanami! Are you alright? Ayanami!
Speaker 14: Don't ever say that. Just don't say that you have nothing else. Just don't say that.
Speaker 14: And don't say goodbye when you leave on a mission. It's just too sad.
Speaker 14: *crying*
Speaker 14: Why don't you just try smiling?
Speaker 10: Fly me to the moon and let me play among the stars
Speaker 10: Let me see where spring is like going Jupiter and Mars
Speaker 10: In other words, hold my hand
In other words, do me, kiss me
Speaker 10: Feel my heart with sound and let me sing forevermore
Speaker 10: You are all I long for, though I won't supernate all
Speaker 10: In other worlds, please be true.
Speaker 10: In other
Speaker 6: worlds, I'm going to be...
Speaker 2: When a giant humanoid-type robot created by a civilian corporation
Speaker 2: goes out of control during its official test trial,
Speaker 2: it's up to EVA Unit 1 to catch the rampaging jet alone.
Speaker 2: Will Misato be able to stop its nuclear reactor from melting down?
Speaker 2: Find out in the next exciting episode!