Speaker 1: The young man like a man like a man,
Speaker 1: you're a young man, you're a man.
Speaker 1: The wind is now on the door,
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at you
Speaker 1: 微笑んでるあなた
Speaker 1: そっと触れるもの
Speaker 1: 求めることに夢中で
Speaker 1: 運命さえまだ知らない
Speaker 1: 痛いけな瞳
Speaker 1: だけどいつか気づくでしょう
Speaker 1: その背中には
Speaker 1: 遥か未来目指すための羽があること
Speaker 1: 残酷な天使のテーゼ 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
Speaker 1: ほとばしる熱いパトスで 思い出を裏切るなら
Speaker 1: This moon shining in the sky
Speaker 1: You're a man, you're a fairy tale
Speaker 2: Are you ready, Shinji?
Speaker 2: Um, yeah?
Speaker 2: Final safety locks! Release!
Speaker 2: Evangelion Unit 1! Move out!
Speaker 3: Shinji, just concentrate on walking for now.
Walk?
Speaker 1: He's walking
Speaker 1: Walking
Speaker 4: Shiji, are you okay?
Speaker 4: Hurry, hurry
Speaker 4: You've got to get up
Speaker 4: - Whoa!
Speaker 4: Shinji, calm down!
Speaker 5: That's not your real arm!
Speaker 5: Where is defense system? The signal's not working!
Speaker 5: His field's not up! It's not unfolding!
Speaker 5: It's not up!
Speaker 5: Left arm damaged!
Speaker 5: The circuits have snapped!
Speaker 5: Shinji, move!
Speaker 4: Ah!
Speaker 6: There's a crack on the front of the brain case!
Speaker 6: That armor won't take much more!
Speaker 7: The head is damaged!
Speaker 7: Extended damage, unknown!
Speaker 7: The control nerves are breaking up!
Speaker 4: We're
Speaker 1: not getting
Speaker 7: any readings on the pilot!
Speaker 7: No, Shinji!
Speaker 4: Ah!
Thank you.
Speaker 8: Unfamiliar ceiling.
Speaker 9: So, the angels have returned. It's rather sudden.
Speaker 10: It's the same as it was 15 years ago.
Speaker 10: That's the way of disasters, they come without warning.
Speaker 11: On the positive side, our previous investments would appear to be not such a waste after all.
Speaker 10: You can't be sure about
Speaker 9: that yet. If it doesn't pay off, it's still a waste.
Speaker 12: Correct. Now that news of the Angels has become common knowledge,
Speaker 12: Nerve must take steps to control the manner in which this information is received by the general public.
Speaker 13: You may rest assured that it's already been taken care of. Don't worry.
Speaker 14: Government officials have announced that in regard to the declaration of this incident...
Speaker 2: Public scenario B-22. Just like we thought.
Speaker 3: So we're covering up the truth again?
Speaker 3: Well, at least the PR people are happy. They finally got something to do.
Speaker 3: We're being pretty casual about it.
Speaker 3: I don't think so. Actually, I think we're all pretty scared.
Speaker 3: Of course we are.
Speaker 9: Well, we must acknowledge that.
Speaker 9: But still, I wonder,
Speaker 12: Mr. Ikari, were Nerve and Ava used efficiently?
Speaker 12: Repair costs for Unit 1 added to the development costs for Unit 0 are simply staggering.
Speaker 11: We also understand that you gave that toy to your own son.
Speaker 11: Time, money, and manpower. How much more will be wasted by you and your family?
Speaker 11: And that is not your only responsibility.
Speaker 11: The Human Enhancement Project.
Speaker 12: That should be your top priority.
Speaker 12: Correct.
Speaker 12: Under these desperate circumstances,
Speaker 12: that project may be the only real hope for the future of mankind.
Speaker 12: Do you understand?
Speaker 12: In any event, the Angels are no excuse for the delay in the
Speaker 9: schedule of that project.
Speaker 9: We may consider adjusting the budget.
Speaker 9: The rest of the meeting does not concern you.
Speaker 12: Your presence here was... appreciated.
Speaker 12: Ikari, you do know that there can be no turning back.
Speaker 13: I know. Mankind has no time left.
Speaker 2: - Man, air conditioning's the greatest thing.
Speaker 2: Man's triumph over nature!
Speaker 2: Shinji's finally woken up!
Speaker 2: And...
Speaker 3: how is he?
Speaker 3: Well, his memory seems a bit muddled, but...
Speaker 3: You don't think it could be contamination, do you?
Speaker 3: I don't think we should worry.
Speaker 3: Really?
Speaker 3: You're right. He did have a pretty hectic day.
Speaker 3: Poor little kid. His cerebellum must have taken a lot of stress.
Speaker 3: Cerebellum? Don't you mean his heart?
*Bell rings*
Speaker 2: If Ava and this city both operated their full potential,
Speaker 2: we might make it through this.
Speaker 2: You're such an optimist.
Speaker 2: Hey, sometimes you need a little wishful thinking
Speaker 2: just to keep on
Speaker 3: living.
Speaker 3: I see your point.
Speaker 3: It's nice to hear a positive attitude.
Speaker 3: I'll see you later.
Speaker 3: Okay,
Speaker 15: see ya.
Speaker 15: Dr. Ugai, internal department one.
Speaker 15: Please
Speaker 4: call Dr. Azuma
Speaker 15: of the first surgical department immediately.
Speaker 15: The medical conference regarding the B experiment will
Speaker 4: be held
Speaker 15: as scheduled.
Speaker 15: All supervisors, please proceed to conference room 2.
Speaker 3: They don't want to live together?
Speaker 3: Are you sure?
Speaker 10: I think that living apart is natural to them.
Speaker 3: And being together is unnatural?
Speaker 2: He'll be living alone?
Speaker 9: That's right. His room will be on the sixth block beyond this one. Is that alright?
Speaker 2: Yes, sir.
Speaker 2: Shinji,
Speaker 8: are you sure about that?
Speaker 8: Living alone is fine with me. I'm alone anyway.
Speaker 2: What did you say?
Speaker 2: You heard me! I said I'll be taking Shinji home to live in my place, okay?
Speaker 2: It's already been approved.
Speaker 2: And don't worry, I'm not gonna be making any passes at him.
Speaker 2: Of
Speaker 4: course you're
Speaker 3: not! How could you even think of such a thing?
Speaker 3: You've got no shame at
Speaker 2: all!
Speaker 2: Some people don't have any sense of humor.
Speaker 2: Well, I guess we have to have a party tonight, huh?
Speaker 2: Why is that?
Speaker 2: It's a welcoming party in honor of my new roommate, of course.
Speaker 16: - This city would become a battlefield.
Speaker 2: - Yeah,
Speaker 16: my husband's saying that at least
Speaker 16: the kids and I should move.
Speaker 16: - Don't I know it.
Speaker 16: This city may be a fortress,
Speaker 16: but that's no guarantee of safety.
Speaker 16: Just thinking about
it.
Speaker 2: I hope you don't mind if we make a little stop on the way.
Speaker 8: A stop where?
Speaker 2: Oh, it's a really cool place.
Speaker 8: It's so desolate.
Speaker 8: The city seems so lonely.
Speaker 8: Here we
Speaker 2: go.
Speaker 14: *Sigh*
Speaker 2: The city is a fortress designed to stand against the angels.
Speaker 2: This is Tokyo 3.
Speaker 2: This is our city, and it's the city that you saved.
The End
Speaker 2: Your things ought to have been delivered already, Shinji.
Speaker 2: I just moved here myself, you know?
Speaker 2: Hey, come in!
Speaker 8: Uh...
Speaker 8: - True.
Speaker 2: - Shinji, this is your home now.
Speaker 8: - I'm, I'm home.
Speaker 2: - Welcome home.
Speaker 2: - Um, as you can see, the place is just a little bit messy,
Speaker 2: but go ahead and make yourself comfortable.
Speaker 8: - This is a
Speaker 2: little messy?
Speaker 2: Oh, sorry, could you put the food in the fridge, please?
Speaker 8: Uh, yes, ma'am.
Speaker 8: Ice, snacks, and 50 gallons of beer.
Speaker 8: What kind of life does she lead?
Speaker 8: Huh.
Speaker 5: Uh, excuse me.
Speaker 2: What's
Speaker 5: in the other fridge?
Speaker 5: Oh, don't
Speaker 2: mind that.
Speaker 2: He's probably still sleeping.
Speaker 8: Sleeping?
Speaker 8: Let's eat!
Speaker 8: Yeah, let's eat.
Speaker 2: Woo! Yeah! Good stuff!
Speaker 2: You know, life just doesn't get any better than this.
Speaker 2: Hmm? Not hungry?
Speaker 2: It's good, even if it is all instant.
Speaker 2: I'm sorry. I'm just not
Speaker 8: used to food like this.
Speaker 8: What?
Speaker 2: Are you finicky?
Speaker 2: Um, no, that's not what...
Speaker 2: Isn't this nice?
Speaker 2: Having two for dinner sure beats eating alone, huh?
Speaker 2: Here we go. Let's go for the next one.
Speaker 2: Paper, scissors, stone.
Speaker 2: Three, two, one, go!
Speaker 2: I'm sorry, Shinji.
Speaker 2: Okay, that was a really fair way to split up the chores, wasn't it?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: This is your home, so feel free to take advantage of everything here.
Speaker 2: Except, of course, of me, that is.
Speaker 2: Uh, yes, ma'am.
Speaker 2: Yes, yes, yes. Is that all you can say?
Speaker 2: It's getting on
Speaker 4: my nerves! You're a bully!
Speaker 2: Act like one!
Speaker 2: Yes, ma'am!
Speaker 1: I guess that's just the way you are.
Speaker 2: Why don't you go take a bath?
Speaker 2: Yeah, wash away your
Speaker 4: troubles
Speaker 2: bathing cleans the mind and soul
Speaker 2: What
Speaker 2: Huh, oh yeah, he's one of those new warm water penguins
Speaker 2: *cough
*
Speaker 8: *Gasp*
Speaker 8: Ah, Misato Katsaragi.
Speaker 2: She's
Speaker 8: not a bad person.
Speaker 2: Bathing cleans the mind and soul.
Speaker 8: But bad memories always seem to find me in the bath.
Speaker 8: Like my father.
Speaker 8: And that girl,
Ray.
Speaker 3: So how was Ray today?
Speaker 3: You did see her at the hospital today, didn't you?
Speaker 13: She can work again in 20 days.
Speaker 13: By then we'll be ready to reactivate Unit Zero from cryostasis.
Speaker 3: It's so hard on these children.
Speaker 13: There is no one else who can pilot the Evas.
Speaker 13: As long as they survive, that is what I'll have them do.
Speaker 3: With no regard to what they may want?
Speaker 2: Yeah, after all the horrible stuff he went through, I don't think he'll pilot again.
Speaker 3: Maintaining him is part of your job.
Speaker 3: I'm just scared.
Speaker 3: I don't know
Speaker 2: how to deal with him.
Speaker 3: Grumbling already?
Speaker 3: But it was your idea to take him in, you know.
Speaker 2: Oh, shut up!
Speaker 2: I was just thinking of Shinji as a tool.
Speaker 2: I'm as shameless as Ritsuko.
Speaker 2: We destroyed the angel, but...
Speaker 2: I don't feel happy.
Speaker 8: Another unfamiliar ceiling.
Speaker 8: Of course.
Speaker 8: In this whole city, there's no place that's familiar.
Speaker 2: This is your home now.
Speaker 8: Why am I here?
Speaker 5: *Extended
Speaker 5: Pulses are flowing
Speaker 4: backwards!
Speaker 4: Break the circuit
Speaker 5: now!
Speaker 5: Do it!
Speaker 5: We can't!
Speaker 5: It's not accepting the signal!
Speaker 5: What about
Speaker 7: Shinji?
Speaker 7: His monitors aren't reacting.
Speaker 7: His
Speaker 2: condition's unknown.
Speaker 5: Unit
Speaker 11: 1's gone completely
Speaker 2: silent.
Speaker 2: Misato!
Speaker 2: We've got no choice.
Speaker 2: Abort the operation!
Speaker 2: We've got to rescue the pilot!
Speaker 2: Eject the entry plug!
Speaker 2: We can't!
Speaker 2: It's
Speaker 5: completely out of control!
Speaker 5: What did you say?
Speaker 15: The Eva's reactivating.
Speaker 15: I don't believe it! This can't be!
Speaker 15: My god! Berserker.
Speaker 12: We've done it.
Speaker 3: It's an AT field!
Speaker 3: No,
Speaker 2: not now! As long as that field is
Speaker 3: up!
Speaker 3: He can't get
Speaker 7: near that angel!
Speaker 7: The left arm's regenerated itself!
Speaker 7: No way!
Speaker 6: Unit 1's expanding its own AT field!
Speaker 6: It's neutralizing the base space!
Speaker 6: No! It's breaking through it!
Speaker 2: It went through the AT field like it wasn't there!
*Sounds of
Speaker 2: Is the Ava?
Speaker 3: That must be...
Speaker 3: Ava's true form.
Speaker 6: Circuits
Speaker 4: reconnected.
Speaker 4: System's
Speaker 6: restored. Graf's back to normal.
Speaker 6: Pilot life science confirmed!
Speaker 2: Preserving the pilot's life is our first priority!
Speaker 2: Send out the recovery team!
Speaker 2: Hurry!
*Gunshot*
Speaker 17: *Sigh*
Speaker 17: Hang in there.
Speaker 14: In other words, darling, kiss me.
Speaker 14: Fill my heart with song and let me sing forevermore.
Speaker 14: You are all I long for, all I worship and adore.
Speaker 14: In other words, please be true
Speaker 14: In other words,
I love you
Speaker 2: Shinji's life is busier than ever, but he keeps to himself friendless until it's revealed that he's an Ava pilot.
Speaker 2: However, this new hero status brings both embarrassment and the rap of one boy in particular.
Speaker 2: Don't miss the next episode, and I'll sneak in a little bonus, okay?