Speaker 1: I guess we'll be in Japan by this time tomorrow.
Speaker 1: Misato said she'd pick me up by lunch.
Speaker 1: Oh, Misato's the person who was in Germany before Yukaji.
Speaker 1: I don't like her much, though.
Speaker 1: She's just so affected in the way she lives.
Speaker 1: So, I guess this'll be goodbye for a while.
Speaker 1: That's so boring.
Speaker 2: Oh,
Speaker 3: I'm sure you'll make lots of new boyfriends once you get to Japan, Asuka.
Speaker 3: And let's not forget that the third child is a boy, too.
Speaker 1: I'm not interested in children.
Speaker 1: You're the only one I love, Kashi.
Speaker 3: Well, that's quite an honor.
Speaker 1: I mean it, Kashi! If it's with you, then all of that stuff is totally okay!
Speaker 1: Kissing, and what's after that, even?
Speaker 3: Asuka, you're still a child.
Speaker 3: Those things can wait until you've grown up a little.
Speaker 1: Huh? But why?
Speaker 1: Can't you see that I've already grown enough?
Speaker 1: I am a grown up!
Speaker 1: Just look at me, Tony! Please, please!
Speaker 4: So the fiction has become the reality.
Speaker 4: How ironic that the experiment's advocate should become its victim.
Speaker 4: So, you believe that the contact experiment was the
Speaker 5: direct cause?
Speaker 5: You mean was the mental breakdown the result of the contact?
Speaker 5: Yes. Killing herself and leaving such a young girl behind is so awful.
Speaker 5: Perhaps, but I believe there may have been some additional causes.
Speaker 4: Asuka, darling, Mama cooked your favorite for you.
Speaker 4: Oh no, you mustn't complain about what you like and dislike,
Speaker 4: For that girl over there will laugh at you.
Speaker 4: She just sits there
Speaker 1: every day, talking to that doll as if it were her real daughter.
Speaker 6: I think it's because of the guilt she must feel.
Speaker 6: She devoted her entire life to her research, not to taking care of her own daughter.
Speaker 1: Oh, I feel your grief.
Speaker 6: It's like looking at porcelain figures of a mother and her child.
Speaker 6: Perhaps there really isn't much difference between humans and dolls.
Speaker 4: Mankind creates dolls in our own image.
Speaker 4: If God exists, perhaps we're all just a bunch of dolls to him.
Speaker 6: Hearing you say something like that makes it hard for me to believe that you're a modern physician.
Speaker 4: I may be a doctor, but I'm a human being.
Speaker 4: And a woman first.
Speaker 1: You're a strong girl, Oscar.
Speaker 1: But it's alright if you have to cry.
Speaker 1: I'll never cry, Grandmother.
Speaker 1: I have to take care of myself now.
Speaker 1: - Asuka,
Speaker 7: your sink ratio has dropped an entire eight points.
Don't think about anything else.
Speaker 2: Just concentrate the way you used to.
Speaker 2: - I'm trying to!
Speaker 7: - Asuka's sink ratio is getting lower and lower.
Speaker 7: - What does it mean, ma'am?
Speaker 7: - It means trouble. We don't have a spare.
Speaker 7: Let's concentrate our efforts on fixing Unit Zero.
Speaker 7: We can't waste time on the one we might not be able to use.
Speaker 7: - Hmm.
Speaker 4: The litosis process in the left arm of Unit 2 has
Speaker 8: cleared the numerical requirement.
Speaker 4: Code 3.
Speaker 4: Development of
necrosis is currently under 0.5.
Speaker 1: The current status of Unit 0's regeneration is stable.
Speaker 1: Connecting receptors to the secondary terminal.
Speaker 4: The Avas were created from the angel known as Adam.
Speaker 4: Now, in order to defeat the angels,
Speaker 4: We are employing the same forces which caused the second impact and wiped out half of the human race.
Speaker 4: Only humans could be so foolish as to attempt to harness the engine of our own destruction.
Speaker 4: I hate the Avas. Is our revenge worth this?
Speaker 4: Major
Speaker 3: Katsuragi!
Speaker 4: They've started construction on all the Avas through Unit 13?
Speaker 4: At seven different locations around the world?
Speaker 9: Yeah. This information came from Shanghai. It's reliable.
Speaker 4: So why are they speeding up the construction process now?
Speaker 9: Well, we've lost two Avas and two more are severely damaged.
Speaker 9: I'd assume they're trying to create a reserve force.
Speaker 4: Perhaps.
Speaker 4: But we've been receiving spare parts from Germany that were originally intended for AVA Units 5 and 6.
Speaker 4: They've been spending an awful lot of money
Speaker 9: lately.
Speaker 9: And that's after they've doubled the existing budget.
Speaker 9: The executives are being driven by something.
Speaker 4: Yeah. I can almost feel the committee's impatience behind this.
Speaker 9: - Hmm, do you think they're doing this in anticipation
Speaker 9: of having to intercept multiple angels at once?
Speaker 4: - Huh, except that there's no reason for them
Speaker 4: to be doing that outside of the official channels.
Speaker 4: There's got to be some other reason for this.
Speaker 7: - I'm sorry, the telephone number you just dialed
Speaker 7: is currently not in use.
Speaker 7: Please try again.
Speaker 1: - That's weird, I still can't get through.
Speaker 1: I wonder if he went somewhere again.
Speaker 1: *BEEP*
Our train will presently be arriving in Terminal 2.
Speaker 1: For your safety, please wait behind
the white line until the train has come to a complete stop.
Speaker 1: That idiot Shinji's Eva just swallowed him for a whole month.
Speaker 1: And now, he's acting like nothing ever happened.
Speaker 1: Okay, so I lost this time.
Speaker 1: That doesn't change the fact that you're a little...
Speaker 1: I'll smoke!
Speaker 4: This is the first time we've gotten together in a while.
Speaker 4: Why is there such an air of gloom?
Speaker 4: I'm finished now.
Speaker 4: Asuka?
Speaker 1: Why should I get it? It's probably just Kashi calling for you.
Speaker 1: You should answer your own phone.
Speaker 1: That's not likely.
Speaker 7: Oh, fine.
Speaker 1: Ah, the invincible Shinji stoops to answering the phone.
Speaker 1: He doesn't just save the world.
Speaker 1: Damn him! I hate the way he ignores me.
Speaker 1: It's a call for you from Germany, Asuka.
Speaker 1: I think it's your mother.
Speaker 1: A call for me? My mother?
Speaker 1: Give me that!
Speaker 1: Hello?
Speaker 10: Hello,
Speaker 1: Moody!
Speaker 10: Aha!
Speaker 1: When she speaks in a language I can't understand,
Speaker 1: Asuka seems to be a different
Speaker 10: person.
Speaker 10: Ja, ja. Ich bin mit die Jungen sehr populär.
Speaker 10: Ach ja, niemals!
Speaker 10: Er ist ein selber Mensch.
Speaker 10: Ja?
Speaker 10: Yeah?
Speaker 10: Asuka's mother.
Speaker 10: Really?
Speaker 10: Ah, so.
Speaker 10: Das ist aber toll.
Speaker 10: Ich werde jetzt in Bett gehen.
Speaker 10: Auf Wiederhauen.
Speaker 10: Gute Nacht.
Speaker 1: Wow, you two were on the phone quite a while.
Speaker 1: Well, it was just a routine communication.
Speaker 1: I wish I talked to my family.
Speaker 1: It's totally overrated, and it's all just for show.
Speaker 1: She's not my real mother anyway.
Speaker 1: Oh?
Speaker 1: It's not my real mother anyway.
Speaker 1: I don't feel like I hate her or anything.
Speaker 1: I just feel like...
Speaker 1: And why in the hell am I telling all of this to you?!
Speaker 1: I'm sorry.
Speaker 1: Ha! I've really hit rock bottom
Speaker 1: when I get sympathy from a loser like you!
Speaker 1: It just makes me sick.
Speaker 1: There's no way I'm bathing in water
Speaker 1: that Misato and stupid Shinji have used.
Speaker 1: I won't use a washer that Misato and Shinji the dork have used for washing underwear.
Speaker 1: And I don't want to have to sit on a toilet that's been used, not by the two of them.
Speaker 1: I don't even want to breathe the same air they do, not the two of them.
Speaker 1: I hate Misato, and I hate Shinji, and I hate that first child,
Speaker 8: bitch,
Speaker 1: Rei!
I hate my dad! I hate my mom! But mostly, most of all, I hate my...
I hate him! I can't do it anymore! Why do I have to do this? Why me?
Speaker 4: Synchrograph, minus 12.8. It's barely over the starting indicator.
Speaker 4: That's pathetic. That's an even worse score than yesterday.
Speaker 4: Asuka's not feeling well
Speaker 7: today. It's her period.
Speaker 7: Sync ratios aren't influenced by physical changes.
Speaker 7: The problem's deeper, in her subconscious.
Speaker 7: It looks like we may have to replace Unit 2's pilot.
Speaker 7: Asuka?
Speaker 7: You're finished now.
Speaker 7: You know,
Speaker 4: Asuka's pride has been badly damaged.
Speaker 4: It's hard to blame her after she was defeated so badly.
Speaker 4: But what's worse is that she feels like she was beaten by Shinji.
Speaker 4: Maybe it's time the three of us stopped living together.
Speaker 4: So you've hit your limit?
Speaker 4: Your nice synthetic family is falling apart?
Speaker 4: I don't have to take that from someone who tries to fill the holes in her own empty life with a bunch of cats.
Speaker 4: Hmph.
Speaker 4: I'm sorry. I'm just upset.
Speaker 1: Why do I have to suffer through this just because I'm a girl?
Speaker 1: It's not like I want to have children anyway!
Speaker 1: The Route 7 loop is currently closed due to an accident.
Speaker 1: Please close Route 12 at the gate door.
*Clap*
*throwing*
*Sigh*
Speaker 1: This is my fault? I'm blocking myself?
Speaker 1: - Yes, Ava has its own mind.
Speaker 1: - It's just a big toy.
Speaker 1: - Then you don't know?
Speaker 1: - Now I know something's up
Speaker 1: when Wonder Girl starts talking to me.
Speaker 1: What's up?
Speaker 1: Are you happy that I'm having trouble with my Ava now?
Speaker 1: Well, don't worry, 'cause when the next angel comes,
Speaker 1: our invincible Shinji will ride out and destroy it!
Speaker 1: We little girls want how to fight anymore!
Speaker 1: They only need that pathetic Shinji!
Speaker 1: I thought it was bad when Shinji was nice,
Speaker 1: but when an emotionless, wind-up doll like you starts being sympathetic, I'm doomed!
Speaker 1: I am not a doll.
Speaker 1: You are! You'd do anything you're ordered to, don't you?
Speaker 1: You'd kill yourself if your commander told you to, wouldn't you?
Speaker 1: Of course.
Speaker 1: Then you are a robot, just like I thought!
Speaker 1: You're an unthinking, emotionless pup, and I hate you!
Speaker 1: I hate you! I hate everyone!
Speaker 1: Oh!
Speaker 11: Man, it looks like Shinji didn't show up again today.
Speaker 11: Rei misses class all the time, but...
Speaker 2: Asuka's gone too, and Suzuhara's still in the hospital.
Speaker 11: The situation must be really bad. They're all gone.
Speaker 7: The connection and fusion of VAs are within normal limits.
Speaker 7: The field of proliferation is within the expected range.
Speaker 1: So, after losing like that, you're finally fixed, are you?
Speaker 1: You're my doll, and you're supposed to do whatever I tell you to
Speaker 1: without arguing, do you understand?
Speaker 1: And why does a weapon need a mind anyway?
Speaker 1: It just causes more trouble.
Speaker 1: Anyway, you've got to obey all of my orders, do you hear?
Speaker 1: This is stupid.
All personnel go to first stage alert.
Speaker 3: Prepare for Angel Assault.
Speaker 1: An Angel? Another one?
Speaker 3: We have visual confirmation on the Angel.
Speaker 3: Maximum magnification.
Speaker 3: Its orbit is just outside our defense envelope.
Speaker 3: And it's maintaining a constant distance from us.
Speaker 4: So does that mean it's looking for a nice comfy place to land?
Speaker 4: Or that it's going to destroy us from way up there?
Speaker 3: We can't attack it from this
Speaker 9: distance.
Speaker 4: Yeah, and unless it decides to come into our range, there's not much we can do offensively.
Speaker 4: The Avas weren't designed to combat an enemy that's still in orbit.
Speaker 4: How's Ray?
Speaker 4: Ray and Unit Zero are both ready and waiting.
Speaker 4: Understood.
Speaker 4: Roll out unit zero. Equip it for long-range firing.
Speaker 1: Oscar, be ready to back her up in unit two.
Speaker 1: You want me to back up unit zero?
Speaker 1: That's right. Take the rear guard position.
Speaker 1: You can't be serious.
Speaker 1: Ava, unit two, launch now!
Speaker 1: Oscar!
Speaker 7: It's okay. Let her take the point if that's what she wants.
Speaker 7: Are you sure,
Speaker 3: Major?
Speaker 7: If she screws this up, that bitch won't be piloting anymore.
Speaker 7: You mean this is her last chance?
Speaker 7: Start preparing her replacement just to be safe.
Speaker 7: Right.
Speaker 3: Excuse me, aren't we gonna use Unit 1?
Speaker 4: Unit 1 stays in cryostasis.
Speaker 4: Those are Commander Ikari's orders.
Speaker 4: And after what's happened, we better accept that.
Speaker 1: If I fail this time, they won't let me pilot anymore.
Speaker 1: You can do it, Oscar.
Speaker 1: You must.
Speaker 1: The target is still out of range.
Speaker 1: Damn! Why are you so slow? Come and fight, Angel!
Speaker 3: The enemy has a particle beam weapon?
Speaker 3: No! No thermal emissions detected!
Speaker 3: Abnormal reading on Asuka's psychograph.
Speaker 12: Mental contamination imminent.
Speaker 12: An eco-border attack?
Speaker 12: The angels understand our psychology that well.
Speaker 3: Pulsatron beam disengaged.
Speaker 3: It's not working.
Speaker 3: It's too far out.
Speaker 3: No more!
Speaker 3: - No!
Speaker 3: - Damn, her rifle is out of ammunition.
Speaker 3: - What's that thing made of?
Speaker 3: - It's some kind of energy oscillation
Speaker 3: using visible wavelengths.
Speaker 3: It's
Speaker 12: similar to an AT field.
Speaker 12: - How's Asuka?
Speaker 12: - The mental contamination is crossing
Speaker 12: her ego borderline.
Speaker 12: - No!
Speaker 12: Don't come into me,
Speaker 8: don't!
*Screams*
Speaker 2: Get out of my mind!
Speaker 2: Please, get out of my mind!
Speaker 7: - Asuka! - Let the breath critical!
Speaker 7: We've got to get Asuka out of there immediately.
Speaker 7: Her mind is going to be permanently damaged.
Speaker 2: - Asuka, retreat! - No!
Speaker 2: That was an order, Asuka! I'm ordering you to retreat!
Speaker 1: No! Never! I'd better die than admit defeat now!
Speaker 1: Asuka!
Accelerator synchronization initiated.
Speaker 3: Voltage is increasing. Approaching pressure zone.
Speaker 1: Compulsory focus
convergence activated.
Speaker 3: Compensation
for the Earth's rotation and gravity 0.03.
Pressure in the chamber is at maximum.
Release the final safety locks.
All personnel, prepare for firing.
Speaker 3: It's no good.
Speaker 3: There wasn't enough energy to penetrate
Speaker 12: its AT field.
Speaker 12: It's too far for our weapons.
Speaker 12: But we're at maximum power output.
Speaker 12: We can't get any more power.
Speaker 12: Unit 2's cycle graph is getting weaker.
Speaker 12: What's the status on the LCL mind barriers?
Speaker 12: Negative.
Speaker 12: If we can't even hope for a buffering effect!
Speaker 12: Switch to life support only.
Speaker 12: Don't let it feed back into her.
Speaker 12: I'll try.
Speaker 7: Somehow that ray is scanning into Asuka's mental wavelength.
Speaker 7: Are the angels trying to analyze what's inside a human mind?
Speaker 1: Why am I crying?
Speaker 1: I swore that I wouldn't cry.
Speaker 1: *Screams*
Speaker 1: Please don't
kill me!
No! I'm not Mama's doll! I'll think for myself and I'll live for myself!
Speaker 1: No! Don't make me remember that! I wanted to forget those things!
Speaker 1: Don't uncover them! I don't want those terrible memories anymore!
Speaker 1: Stop this! Please stop it now!
Speaker 7: Please, Asuka, die with me.
Speaker 1: If that's what you want, I'll tie with you, Mama.
Speaker 1: Just please, please don't stop being my mother!
Speaker 1: Mama! Mama!
Speaker 1: Mama?
Are you...?
Speaker 1: Huh?
Speaker 1: I'm Asuka, Asuka Langley Soryu. Charmed, huh?
Speaker 1: What are you, stupid?
Speaker 13: Now's my chance.
Speaker 1: Look at me, dammit! Look at me!
Speaker 13: No!
Speaker 1: None of this is the real me!
Speaker 1: I'm Asuka, Asuka Langley Soryu. Charmed, huh?
Speaker 1: What are you, stupid?
Speaker 1: Now's
Speaker 13: my chance...
Speaker 1: LOOK AT ME DAMMITS LOOK AT ME!
Speaker 1: No! None of this is the real me!
Speaker 1: Hm? Huh?
Speaker 1: I'm Asuka. Asuka Langley Soryu! Charmed, huh?
Speaker 1: What are you, stupid?
Speaker 1: Now's my chance...
Speaker 1: LOOK AT ME
Speaker 2: DAMMITS LOOK AT ME!
Speaker 1: No! None of this is the real me!
Speaker 1: Hm? Huh?
Speaker 1: I'm Asuka. Asuka Langley Soryu! Charmed, huh?
Speaker 1: What are you, stupid?
Speaker 13: Now's my chance...
Speaker 1: Look at me, dammit! Look at me!
Speaker 1: No! None of this is the real me!
Speaker 1: Hmm? Huh?
Speaker 1: I'm Asuka. Asuka Langley Soruyu.
Speaker 1: Charmed, huh? What are you, stupid?
Speaker 13: Now's
Speaker 1: my chance.
Speaker 1: Look at
Speaker 2: me, dammit! Look at me!
Speaker 2: No!
None of this is the real me!
I'm sorry.
Oh my god, help me!
Why are you there, damn you!
You don't do anything! You won't help me! You won't even hold me!
Speaker 2: You're no one! No
one! No one!
Why are you again?
Speaker 1: I is only...
Speaker 1: Are you alone?
No!
Stay away from me!
I'm going to live on my own!
Speaker 2: Do you love me?
Speaker 2: I won't rely on anyone!
Speaker 2: Do you feel you love me?
Speaker 2: I can't live on my own!
Speaker 1: But you're lying.
No!
Speaker 10: *Evil
Speaker 1: Scream
Speaker 14: Pilot's mind entering danger zone!
Speaker 3: Position constant! The target hasn't moved yet!
Speaker 3: The possibility of the target coming into Unit Zero's range is 0.02 percent!
Speaker 3: Could we airlift Unit
Speaker 4: Zero and try an airborne attack?
Speaker 4: No, that
Speaker 15: wouldn't work. If the Angel attacked, we'd be defenseless.
Speaker 15: Let
Speaker 4: me
Speaker 15: go out in Unit One!
Speaker 15: Forget it! This Angel's ability to attack the Pilot's mind is way too dangerous!
Speaker 5: Yes, we cannot allow Unit One to be touched by an Angel.
Speaker 5: But
Speaker 12: that can't happen as long as
I'm not defeated!
Speaker 5: There is no guarantee of that.
Speaker 12: If we don't do something, Asuka will die!
Speaker 12: That is
Speaker 5: true. Rey, go to Dogma and get the lance.
Speaker 5: Use the lance of Loginous! You can't do that, Akari!
Speaker 5: There is no other way to destroy a target that remains in orbit beyond the reach of our AT fields. Proceed.
Speaker 4: But I thought that if Adam and Ava were to come into contact, it would cause the third impact!
Speaker 4: We can't take that chance, Commander! It's too dangerous!
Speaker 4: So that story was another lie.
Speaker 4: But if contact with an angel didn't cause second impact,
Speaker 4: then what did?
Speaker 4: Opening
Central Dogma barriers 10 through 15.
Speaker 7: Unit Zero has passed the 6th Malmogé Trench.
Speaker 7: Now opening barriers 16 through 20.
Speaker 4: If something like this won't cause third impact,
Speaker 4: then what really caused second impact?
Speaker 5: Ikari, it's too early to use the lance.
Speaker 5: The committee has already started to mass produce Avis.
Speaker 5: This is our chance, Fyutsuki.
Speaker 5: Our chance, but...
Speaker 5: We cannot make time run backwards,
Speaker 5: but we can spur its course forward with our own hands.
Speaker 5: The old man won't allow this, Ikari.
Speaker 5: Therefore, we must finish this before Sele has time to act.
Speaker 5: After all, it is not acceptable to lose Unit 2 at this time.
Speaker 5: But you just can't
Speaker 15: use the Lance of Longinus without getting Sele's approval first.
Speaker 15: You're asking for trouble!
Speaker 15: The need is the justification. There are no other factors to consider.
Speaker 15: The need?
Speaker 15: You've just been looking for a convenient excuse, haven't you?
Speaker 3: Pilot's EEG dropping to 0.06!
Speaker 3: We're past the limits of the life support system!
Speaker 3: Unit zero's passing through vent two.
Speaker 3: She'll be coming in over the surface!
Speaker 4: So that's the Lance of Longinus.
Speaker 4: Unit zero's in position
Speaker 3: to throw!
Speaker 3: Right in sighted. Error corrections have been made.
Speaker 3: Starting countdown.
Ten seconds till zero.
Nine.
Eight.
Seven, six, five, four, three, two, one, zero.
Speaker 3: Target annihilated.
Speaker 3: AVA Unit 2 has been released.
Speaker 15: I need a status update on the Lance.
Speaker 3: The Lance reached escape velocity.
Speaker 3: It's now moving into a lunar orbit, sir.
Speaker 15: So it's almost impossible to recover now.
Speaker 16: Right. There are no methods available
Speaker 16: for recovering something of that much mass.
Speaker 1: Unit 2 psychograph returning to normal.
Speaker 1: Return
Speaker 3: the body to the second cage.
Speaker 1: Returning body via access path 67.
Speaker 4: What's Oscar's status?
Speaker 16: We've confirmed that the pilot's alive.
Speaker 16: Should we put her in quarantine because of the contamination?
Speaker 16: Yeah.
Speaker 1: Hey,
Speaker 3: Asuka?
Speaker 1: I'm-- I'm glad you're okay.
Speaker 1: Shut up!
Speaker 1: Who the hell is okay?
Speaker 1: How could it get any worse?
Speaker 1: That little bitch!
Speaker 1: That little bitch, Ray, rescued
Speaker 8: me!
Speaker 1: Don't you know that I'd rather have died?
Speaker 8: I hate her!
Speaker 8: I hate you, Gigi!
Speaker 1: I hate everything!
Speaker 4: In the next episode, AVA Unit Zero and its pilot are possessed and violated by another
Speaker 4: But even as Rei's mind and body are eaten away,
Speaker 4: she never loses sight of her inner self.
Speaker 4: As the angel's corrosive essence eats into her Ava's core,
Speaker 4: Rei chooses to make the ultimate sacrifice.
Speaker 4: To protect Shinji from the angel, she surrenders her own essence,
Speaker 4: taking with her a huge section of Tokyo 3 in a wave of heat and light,
Speaker 4: and leaving behind only memories in people's souls.
Speaker 4: It all happens in tears.
you