Speaker 1: The young
Speaker 2: man
Speaker 1: I just saw you, just looking and smiling.
Speaker 1: You are so close to touching the touch.
Speaker 1: I'm still in awe of your dreams.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure you'll notice that your back is still in the back.
Speaker 1: The future is the only way to the future
Speaker 1: The endless endless endless
Speaker 1: The window from the end of the world
Speaker 1: The hot-pastus is the only way to the world
Speaker 1: The memories of the world
Speaker 1: The sky will be shining
Speaker 1: Shonen, Yoshiwa-ni-nare!
Speaker 3: Hello? Are you done with the Magi's checkup yet?
Speaker 3: Almost finished. Didn't
Speaker 4: I promise you I'd be done before today's experiment?
Speaker 4: There's something else, Ritsko.
Speaker 4: Three impossible things to do and you still beat the schedule.
Speaker 4: That coffee's cold.
Speaker 5: All three Magi systems have entered self-diagnostic locally.
Speaker 5: One hundred
Speaker 6: twenty-five team maintenance
Speaker 3: has been completed.
Speaker 3: Confirmed. Well done, guys.
Speaker 3: Go ahead and take a break until the test begins.
Speaker 3: Everything checked out.
Speaker 3: As usual, Mother's in good shape, but...
Speaker 3: Is it just me getting older?
Speaker 7: What? Do you want me to take my clothes off again?
Speaker 7: The next chamber is an ultra-clean room environment.
Speaker 7: Just taking a shower and changing your undergarments is insufficient.
Speaker 7: Why do I have to go through all this for a dumb autopilot test?
Speaker 3: With the advance of time comes the need for AVA technology to advance as well.
Speaker 3: To do so, we need a constant influx of new data.
Speaker 3: Now get undressed.
Speaker 3: Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 7: Alright, I'm here just the way you wanted.
Speaker 7: Butt naked and run through the wash cycle 17 times.
Speaker 8: Very good. And I want all three of you to stay that way as you walk through the room and board the entry plug.
Speaker 8: What?
Speaker 8: Don't worry. The video recorders have been shut off. We do respect your privacy.
Speaker 9: Oh, sure you do, and that's not the point! This is a personal thing!
Speaker 9: The purpose of
Speaker 8: this experiment is
Speaker 7: to monitor
Speaker 8: the harmonics directly from your bodies, without the interference of your plugsuits.
Speaker 8: Aska, this is an order.
Speaker 7: Alright, but I don't want anybody peeking, okay?
Speaker 5: All
Speaker 7: pilots are ready for entry.
Speaker 3: Start
Speaker 5: test sequence.
Speaker 5: Beginning test. Initiate autopilot recording.
Speaker 5: Inserting simulation plug.
Connecting the system with the simulation bodies.
Speaker 6: The simulation
Speaker 4: plug is now under
Speaker 6: the Magi's control.
Speaker 4: Man, that was fast.
Speaker 4: The Magi are magnificent.
Speaker 4: It's hard to believe that the first test took a whole week.
Speaker 3: Test duration will be three hours.
Speaker 3: How do you feel?
Speaker 7: It feels quite hard.
Speaker 7: Yeah, it's a little different from the other times.
Speaker 7: Something's wrong with my senses.
Speaker 7: My right arm's clear. Everything else feels fuzzy.
Speaker 7: Ray, focus on moving the right hand.
Speaker 4: Right.
Speaker 5: Data collection is proceeding nicely.
Speaker 3: Everything's looking good.
Speaker 3: Return the Magi to normal.
Speaker 3: Huh? A dilemma?
Speaker 3: Huh? You can sure feel their creator's personality, can't you?
Speaker 3: What are you talking about? Aren't you the one who created them?
Speaker 4: You don't know anything, do you?
Speaker 4: That's because, unlike me, you never talk about yourself, Ritsko.
Speaker 3: No, I don't. I only created the system uplinks.
Speaker 3: The basic theorems in the mainframe were my mother's.
Speaker 10: Are you double-checking this?
Speaker 10: Yes, sir. These are the parts that were installed three days ago.
Speaker 10: The parts that are showing signs of deterioration.
Speaker 10: The 87th protein wall.
Speaker 10: With magnification, you can see some discoloration, but I can't identify it.
Speaker 11: It's got to be corrosion.
Speaker 11: There are slight variations in the temperature and conduction rate of the spots.
Speaker 11: The clean rooms have been deteriorating a lot lately.
Speaker 11: The construction schedule was cut
Speaker 10: by 60 days,
Speaker 10: so it's possible some air bubbles might have gotten inside.
Speaker 10: B-Wing's construction is rather substandard.
Speaker 10: Well, this building was thrown up after the Angels appeared.
Speaker 11: It's nobody's fault. Everyone was so exhausted back then.
Speaker 12: Well, just fix it by tomorrow, or Akari will chew our asses off.
Speaker 3: Understood.
Speaker 6: Another leak?
Speaker 6: No, it's some kind of corrosion in the protein wall above this floor.
Speaker 6: Just
Speaker 3: great.
Speaker 6: Could it affect this test?
Speaker 3: No, not at the moment, ma'am.
Speaker 3: Then let's continue.
Speaker 3: We can't abort complex experiments because of minor technical problems.
Speaker 3: Akari would chew my ass off.
Speaker 3: Understood.
Speaker 6: Synchronization position is correct.
Speaker 5: Connecting simulation entry plugs to AVA via the simulation bodies.
Speaker 5: Contact with AVA0 has been confirmed.
Speaker 9: AT field will generate R2.
Speaker 6: What's happening?
Speaker 6: Contamination alert! It's in Sigma unit on the A floor!
Speaker 6: The
Speaker 5: 87th protein wall is corroding and releasing heat.
Speaker 5: Abnormality in six pipe detected.
Speaker 6: Corrosion of the protein wall is increasing
Speaker 6: at an incredible rate.
Speaker 6: It's spreading everywhere.
Speaker 6: Abort the test.
Speaker 6: Shut
Speaker 3: off all flow through the six pipe system.
Speaker 3: Right.
Speaker 5: Numbers 60, 38, and 39 are all hermetically sealed.
Speaker 5: Corrosion present in six through 42.
Speaker 6: It's no good.
Speaker 6: The corrosion
Speaker 3: effect is spreading along the walls.
Speaker 3: Deploy polysomes.
Speaker 8: Set laser power at maximum.
Speaker 8: Snap every invasive particle.
Speaker 6: Corrosion is reached 6 through 58.
Speaker 6: It's here!
Speaker 6: Ray!
Speaker 6: Ray's simulation body, it's moving!
Speaker 6: Impossible!
Speaker 6: The corrosion is still spreading!
Speaker 6: It's invading the simulation body's active water system!
Speaker 7: How's Rey?
Speaker 7: She's alright!
Speaker 7: Eject the entry plugs immediately!
Speaker 7: Use the lasers!
Speaker 4: That's an AT field!
Speaker 4: It can't be.
Speaker 4: Is that an...?
Speaker 3: Pattern analysis is blue. ID confirmed. An angel.
Speaker 13: An angel? You let an angel get inside these facilities?
Speaker 9: I'm sorry, sir.
Speaker 13: No time for excuses.
Speaker 13: Right. Let's cut off Central Dogma.
Speaker 13: Isolate it from the Sigma unit.
Speaker 11: Initiate physical lockout of Central Dogma.
Speaker 2: Evacuate immediately.
Speaker 11: Abandon the box.
Speaker 4: What the hell are you doing? Come on.
Isolating Sigma unit from B4.
Closing all partitions.
All personnel in the area must evacuate.
Speaker 14: I know that.
Speaker 14: Take care of it.
Speaker 14: Cancel the red alert.
Speaker 14: Very good.
Speaker 14: Call the committee.
Speaker 14: Tell them there was an error in our alarm system.
Speaker 14: Daminated area is still descending, sir.
Speaker 14: It's spreading all over Sigma unit from the Privnow box!
Speaker 14: That's too close.
Speaker 14: Yes, much too close to Adam.
Speaker 14: We must stop the Angel inside Sigma unit.
Speaker 14: If necessary, sacrifice the Geo front.
Speaker 14: Ava status.
Speaker 14: They're standing by in the seventh cage.
Speaker 14: We can launch them as soon as the pilots are recovered.
Speaker 14: There's no need to wait for the pilots.
Speaker 14: Launch them immediately.
Speaker 11: What?
Speaker 14: You will launch Unit 1 first.
Speaker 14: If necessary, the other two Evangelions are to be abandoned.
Speaker 14: Unit
Speaker 11: 1 has priority?
Speaker 11: But sir, how can we possibly destroy this Angel without the Avas?
Speaker 14: If the Avas are contaminated first, we'll be finished. Get moving!
Speaker 14: Yes, sir!
Central Dogma's Sigma unit will be locked down in 60 seconds.
Thirty seconds until vacuum pump activation.
Speaker 11: So that's the new Angel. Time to take a break, I think.
Speaker 9: Central Dogma has been sealed. Megadeth facilities are all occupied by the intruder.
Speaker 12: So, how do we fight the Angels without the Avas?
Speaker 3: Look at this. The border between the normal and heavy water. There's a higher oxygen content.
Speaker 3: Yeah, their preference is pretty obvious.
Speaker 10: It looks like the place where ozone is vented in to maintain aseptic conditions isn't contaminated.
Speaker 10: Does that
Speaker 6: mean its weakness is ozone?
Speaker 4: It would seem so.
Speaker 10: Injecting ozone. Ozone concentration increasing.
Speaker 10: It's working alright. Will this work?
Speaker 6: Zero A and zero B seem to be recovering.
Speaker 6: The
Speaker 10: area around the pipes is getting back to normal.
Speaker 10: True, but the central mass is proving more resistant.
Speaker 10: Alright, inject more ozone.
Speaker 3: Huh? What the...
Speaker 11: Uh-oh. It's not shrinking.
Speaker 11: Something's wrong. Heat levels are rising dramatically.
Speaker 6: It's not working. The ozone's not working anymore.
Speaker 11: I don't believe it. It's absorbing the ozone.
Speaker 3: Stop the ozone.
Speaker 3: Amazing. It's actually evolving.
Speaker 2: What's going on?
Speaker 11: We've got an unidentified intruder.
Speaker 11: Someone's hacking into the subcomputer.
Speaker 11: Ah, not now.
Speaker 11: They're coming in C mode.
Speaker 11: We can't stop them.
Speaker 11: We've got to unfreeze the barrier.
Speaker 11: Open a decoy entry.
Speaker 1: Decoy
Speaker 11: entry has been avoided.
Speaker 11: Running barrier.
Speaker 11: Barrier has been penetrated.
Speaker 5: Opening another false entry.
Speaker 11: Trace completed.
Speaker 11: The hacker's in this building.
Speaker 11: It's under B-Wing.
Speaker 11: In the Primnow box.
Speaker 6: The optical pattern is changing!
Speaker 11: Those glowing lines are electronic circuits.
Speaker 11: It's an organic computer.
Speaker 11: I'm opening a new decoy entry.
Speaker 11: Negative. Too much interference.
Speaker 4: Cut off the main
Speaker 11: cable.
Speaker 5: Negative. It refuses to accept the command.
Speaker 6: Utilize the
Speaker 11: lasers.
Speaker 6: It's generating an AT field.
Speaker 6: There's no effect.
Speaker 11: Intruder is accessing the main security banks.
Speaker 11: It's cracking the passcode.
Speaker 11: 12th digit, 16th digit, it's in!
Speaker 11: - My God!
Speaker 11: - It's broken into the main pegs!
Speaker 11: It's reading all the files!
Speaker 11: We can't stop it!
Speaker 11: It's
Speaker 12: got all our codes!
Speaker 12: - What in the hell is it looking for?
Speaker 11: - It's scanning the main directories!
Speaker 11: Accessing codes for, oh my God!
Speaker 11: It's going after the Magi system!
Speaker 14: - Shut down the I/O system.
Speaker 14: System shutdown!
Speaker 11: Three, two, one!
Speaker 11: Quick and set it down!
Speaker 6: The Angel is entering the computers!
Speaker 6: It's made contact with Melchior!
Speaker 6: The Angel is taking over Melchior!
Speaker 6: What?
Speaker 6: Melchior is being reprogrammed by the Angel!
Speaker 6: Melchior auto self
Speaker 15: -destruct has been initiated.
Speaker 16: Overruled.
Speaker 11: Overruled.
Speaker 16: Overruled. Overruled.
Speaker 11: No! It's taking over Melchior!
Speaker 11: And it's hacking into Balthazar!
Speaker 11: Fast! Too fast!
Speaker 11: Its calculation speed is incredible!
Speaker 3: Change the login mode!
Speaker 3: Change synchronization code to every 15
Speaker 10: seconds!
Speaker 10: Roger!
Speaker 10: Yes ma'am!
Speaker 12: How much time did
we buy?
Speaker 10: At least two hours, I think.
Speaker 14: The Magi have become our enemy.
Speaker 3: This angel must be composed of a group of nanomachines, each the size of a virus.
Speaker 3: These nanomachines then group together to form colonies, and in a very short period of time,
Speaker 3: they mutate in a focused exponential series to form a sophisticated intelligent circuit.
Speaker 12: Evolution.
Speaker 3: Yes. They're continuously changing and adapting themselves to attain the best system to cope with any environment they may encounter.
Speaker 12: I understand. It's this angel survival mechanism. Total adaptability.
Speaker 12: The
Speaker 4: only effective countermeasure for an enemy that continually evolves to overcome its own weakness is to eliminate the host.
Speaker 4: If the Magi died, the Parasites died too. Therefore, Commander, I propose the physical
Speaker 3: destruction of the Magi.
Speaker 3: Impossible! Destroying the Magi means destroying headquarters itself!
Speaker 3: That's my recommendation as Head of Operations!
Speaker 3: You're out of line!
Speaker 3: This situation is the responsibility of my department!
Speaker 3: Why are you being so stubborn?
Speaker 3: This whole thing is a result of
Speaker 4: my carelessness.
Speaker 4: Why do you have to be like this?
Speaker 4: You never share the responsibility.
Speaker 4: Why won't you trust someone else?
Speaker 4: As long as this Angel keeps evolving,
Speaker 3: we still have a chance.
Speaker 14: By controlling its evolution.
Speaker 3: Yes, sir.
Speaker 14: We must structure an evolution that leads to self-destruction, death itself.
Speaker 12: We'll set it up so that absorbing the Magi will lead to an evolutionary dead end.
Speaker 12: If
Speaker 3: the Angels believe it to be their only practical means of survival,
Speaker 3: they may choose to coexist with the Magi's system.
Speaker 11: But how?
Speaker 3: What's your plan?
Speaker 3: Since this Angel is like a computer, we could hack into it by connecting it to Kaspar.
Speaker 3: Once we've done that, we could then upload some kind of auto-self-destruct program.
Speaker 3: But
Speaker 6: in order to do that, we'll have to remove the barriers that are protecting the last Magi.
Speaker 14: But if Kaspar is faster than the Angel, we'll succeed.
Speaker 4: Yes.
Speaker 4: This program, can it be ready in time?
Speaker 4: If Kaspar's taken over first, it'll be all over.
Speaker 3: I keep my promises.
Speaker 9: Red alert. Red alert.
Speaker 9: An emergency has occurred in Nerve headquarters.
Speaker 9: All D-class personnel must be back.
Speaker 9: - Fine.
Speaker 6: - What are those paper things, ma'am?
Speaker 3: - These are the developer's personal notes.
Speaker 3: - My god, they're access codes, the Magi secret codes.
Speaker 3: It's like having a map to all of
Speaker 6: the Magi's back doors!
Speaker 6: Am I allowed to see these?
Speaker 6: I can't believe this is all INTC! Schematics! Everything!
Speaker 6: With these notes, we can program much faster than we thought. Right, ma'am?
Speaker 3: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 3: Thanks, Mom. With your help, we can make it.
*Bell rings*
Speaker 3: Okay.
Speaker 3: Wrench, please.
Speaker 4: Hey, doesn't this remind you of our college days?
Speaker 4: Board number 25, please.
Speaker 4: So, why don't you tell me all about the Magi?
Speaker 4: It's a
Speaker 3: long story.
Speaker 3: Do you know about the personality transplant OS?
Speaker 4: Yeah. It's a system for implanting personality onto a seventh generation systematic computer
Speaker 4: to allow the system to think for itself.
Speaker 4: The same
Speaker 3: technology is used for operating the A-blast.
Speaker 3: The Magi's programming used one of the first test subjects.
Speaker 3: So, since my mother was the one who developed the technology...
Speaker 3: Wait. You mean it was her personality that
Speaker 4: was transplanted?
Speaker 3: That's right.
Speaker 3: In a very real sense, the Magi's brains are my mother.
Speaker 3: Is that why you want to protect the Magi?
Speaker 3: I don't think so. Actually, to be quite honest, I never really liked my mother.
Speaker 4: My
Speaker 3: decision was that of a scientist.
Speaker 11: It's happening! Balthazar is being taken over!
Speaker 11: Flash
Speaker 15: -Eye auto self-destruction sequence has been determined.
Speaker 15: It started!
Speaker 15: Will occur 20 seconds after all three AI consent.
Speaker 15: Area of destruction will include geoid depth minus 280, minus 140, and floor 0.
Speaker 15: Under special command 582.
Speaker 11: Balthazar is now invading Casper!
Speaker 11: They're faster than us.
Speaker 11: They're faster, right?
But...
Speaker 15: T minus 20 seconds to self-destruct.
Speaker 11: My God!
Speaker 11: Casper will be taking over in 18 seconds!
Speaker 11: T minus
Speaker 15: 15 seconds to self-destruct.
Speaker 15: Ritzko, hurry!
Speaker 2: Don't worry!
Speaker 11: I've got one whole second to spare.
Speaker 11: Only
one second?
Speaker 6: That's
not a zero or a minus.
Speaker 6: Maya!
Speaker 6: We can do it!
Speaker 15: Hit it!
Speaker 15: One, zero.
Speaker 15: Autonomous self-destruct has been cancelled.
Speaker 15: Special Command
Speaker 2: 582
Speaker 15: is cancelled.
Speaker 2: Mash
Speaker 1: -Eye system returning
Speaker 15: to normal mode.
Speaker 15: Red Alert has been cancelled.
Speaker 9: Red Alert has been cancelled. Red Alert has been cancelled. All hands return to
Speaker 16: first
Speaker 16: state alert. What's going on out there?
Speaker 9: How am I going to get out of here naked? Somebody
Speaker 9: Somebody help me!
Speaker 9: Sigma unit has been released. T-minus zero three to magi reactivation.
Speaker 3: I must be getting old. These all-nighters are really rough.
Speaker 3: Yeah, but at least you kept your
Speaker 4: promise again. You did good.
Speaker 4: Oh, thank you.
Speaker 3: You know, this is the first time I've ever really appreciated this paint thinner you call coffee.
Speaker 3: The night before she died, my mother told me that the Magi were the three aspects of her life.
Speaker 3: Herself as a scientist, herself as a mother, and herself as a woman.
Speaker 3: Those three aspects of her are struggling for dominance inside the Magi.
Speaker 3: She intentionally implanted the dilemmas of the human experience into it.
Speaker 3: Actually, each of the three programs are slightly different as well.
Speaker 3: You know, I don't think I'm the kind of woman who will ever have children of my own,
Speaker 3: So I don't really understand her as a mother, but I respected her as a scientist.
Speaker 3: However, when it came to her as a woman, I hated her.
Speaker 4: Well, you're rather talkative today.
Speaker 3: About some things.
Speaker 3: The program that was installed in Caspar was the one of my mother as a woman.
Speaker 3: And she stayed a woman down to the very last second.
Speaker 3: How totally like my mother.
Speaker 3: *BANG
Speaker 16: In other words, darling kiss me
Speaker 16: Fill my heart with song out, let me sing forevermore
Speaker 16: You are all I long for, all I wish you'd bend the door
Speaker 16: In other words, please be true.
Speaker 16: In other words, I
love you.
Speaker 17: Are the angel attacks and Ikari's responses actually ordained by the Dead Sea Scrolls?
Speaker 17: Sele, the secret organization that controls both Nerve and the Human Instrumentality Project,
Speaker 17: joins with Ikari to verify the events of both the past and present.
Speaker 2: Will the answers be revealed?