Speaker 1: The young man who is a sad thing
Speaker 1: You are a young man who is a fairy tale
Speaker 1: The wind is now on the
Speaker 1: I'll see you soon.
Speaker 1: I'll be shining in the sky
Speaker 1: I'll be a man, be a fairy tale!
*BANG*
Speaker 2: Shinji, did you change the soup's flavor somehow?
Speaker 3: Yeah, I used dried fish stock.
Speaker 3: Ritsuko gave it to me.
Speaker 2: *BANG*
*BANG*
Speaker 4: *BANG*
Speaker 4: It's too hot!
Speaker 3: I'm sorry.
Speaker 4: You're always apologizing!
Speaker 4: Do you really think it's your fault?
Speaker 4: Apologies are your condition reflex to any kind of confrontation, aren't they, Shinji?
Speaker 4: Don't you have any spine at all?
Speaker 3: I'm sorry.
Speaker 4: There you go again.
Speaker 4: Why do you always have to punish yourself for
Speaker 5: everything?
Speaker 5: There, there.
Speaker 4: That's just Shinji's way, you know.
Speaker 4: It's so easy for you just to accept his pathetic habits, isn't it?
Speaker 4: But don't you think you've been too easy on him lately?
Speaker 4: Have I?
Speaker 4: Maybe you and Kaji have hooked up again, but the fact that you're happy doesn't mean that you can just ignore the welfare of the rest
Speaker 5: of us.
Speaker 5: Look, there's nothing
Speaker 4: going on between me and Kaji.
Speaker 6: Hey, Katsuragi, I found a bar that serves a decent drink. How about tonight? Bye.
Speaker 4: I've never been around anyone who's been involved in such a totally indecent relationship.
Speaker 4: And you're supposed to be our guardian? What a hypocrite! It's disgusting!
Speaker 2: Meantime harmonics test, all systems green.
Speaker 6: Projected adjustment values have been cleared.
Speaker 6: You're looking pretty worn to the bone, Major Katsuragi.
Speaker 2: There's reasons why
Speaker 6: I'm worn.
Speaker 2: Private ones.
Speaker 7: Haji's bone.
Speaker 1: Shut your face!
Speaker 2: Anyway, how's the third child doing?
Speaker 2: Just take a look.
Speaker 2: Oh.
Speaker 2: Wow.
Speaker 2: I bet knowing this will boost his confidence a little.
Speaker 2: Can you hear me, Shinji?
Speaker 3: Oh, hi, Misato.
Speaker 2: So how are my
Speaker 3: test scores looking?
Speaker 3: Great, you're number one.
Speaker 4: Oh, it's not just that I lost.
Speaker 4: It's that he beat us so easily.
Speaker 4: He beat us so easily that it's really pissing me off!
Speaker 4: Oh, he's so great! He's so wonderful! He's so awesome!
Speaker 4: Shinji, he's our hero, and he used to be a zero!
Speaker 4: Okay, so that just makes our job a little easier, right?
Speaker 4: But it also means that the two of us will have to be doing double time just so that we're not left behind!
Speaker 8: I'm leaving.
Speaker 8: *Gasp
*
Speaker 5: *Gasp*
Speaker 2: Next stop is Seisho Kabusei.
Speaker 2: Seisho Kabusei.
Speaker 2: Convenient for the Bashar, used books, and video game stores.
Yeah.
*Gasp*
*Evacuation*
Speaker 2: Five minutes until the evacuation of the Western District can be completed.
Speaker 2: The target is advancing slowly at approximately 2.5 km per hour.
Speaker 2: You're late, Major!
Speaker 2: Sorry! What's going on? The Fuji observation center's--
Speaker 7: Never detected it. It just suddenly appeared right above us.
Speaker 7: The pattern is orange. No AT field detected.
Speaker 2: What is that thing? A new kind of angel?
Speaker 7: Unknown. The Magi are withholding their judgment on
Speaker 2: that.
Speaker 2: Damn! Another situation like this at Command Ikari is not here again!
Speaker 2: Can you all hear me?
Speaker 2: I've sent you all of the known target data.
Speaker 2: That's literally all we know right now.
Speaker 2: Approach it carefully and observe its reactions.
Speaker 2: And if possible, try to lure it outside of the city.
Speaker 2: I want you all to back up each other.
Speaker 2: Is
Speaker 5: that understood?
Speaker 2: Yes
Speaker 4: ma'am!
Speaker 4: But don't you think that Shinji ought to be taking the point position?
Speaker 4: Huh?
Speaker 4: Well, it's only right that a job like this should go to the highest rated,
Speaker 4: bravest, number one synchro ratio holder of them all, don't you think?
Speaker 4: Or could it be that you don't feel up to it, Shinji?
Speaker 4: I can do it.
Speaker 4: In fact, I'll show you how
Speaker 3: it ought to be done, Asuka.
Speaker 3: What was that?
Speaker 2: Will the two of you cut it out?
Speaker 3: Oh, gee, didn't you tell me, Misato, that I was number one?
Speaker 2: Well, yeah, but I...
Speaker 3: And after all, combat's a man's job.
Speaker 4: You're showing a piglet, but Unit 2 will back him off.
Speaker 4: Unit 0 will back up as well.
Speaker 9: I don't believe these kids.
Speaker 9: Shinji's hormones are kicking in, aren't they?
Speaker 9: I'm gonna have to chew him out when he gets back.
Speaker 9: Of course, you're a model guardian.
Speaker 4: Ayanami, Asuka, are you in your positions yet?
Speaker 4: Not yet.
Speaker 4: You know it, Ava can't move that fast, you twit!
Shice.
Speaker 3: Are you there?
Speaker 3: Alright, I'll stop it myself
Speaker 7: It vanished!
Speaker 7: Status!
Speaker 7: Pattern blue! Angel confirmed! It's right beneath you and I'm what?
Speaker 7: What the? A shuttle?
Speaker 7: What the hell is
Speaker 2: this? This can't be happening!
Speaker 2: It's Shinji! Get out of there! Shinji!
Speaker 2: Ikari!
Speaker 2: You idiot gets her ass again!
Speaker 2: - Ah!
Speaker 2: Misato!
Speaker 2: What's going on?
Speaker 2: Help me!
Speaker 2: Misato!
Speaker 2: - He jacked that plug!
Speaker 2: Get him out of there!
Speaker 2: No response!
Speaker 2: It's not working!
Speaker 2: Misato!
- Sh, Enji!
Speaker 4: - Aska Ray!
Speaker 4: Rescue Unit 1, hurry!
Speaker 4: - What's the point in only getting A's on Tansy?
Speaker 4: Not in the real world!
Speaker 4: It's gone again!
Speaker 4: Asuka, watch the street!
Speaker 4: The shadow!
Speaker 4: Oh no!
Speaker 4: The whole city is sinking!
Speaker 4: Asuka!
Speaker 4: Ray!
Speaker 4: Pull back!
Speaker 5: Wait!
Speaker 4: Unibun and Shinji are still in there.
Speaker 2: This is an order. Withdraw now.
Speaker 6: Major Katsuragi must feel terrible.
Speaker 6: They reeled Shinji's umbilical cable back in, but the other end was missing.
Speaker 3: Then,
Speaker 6: without power...
Speaker 6: There's not much energy left in the internal batteries.
Speaker 6: If Shinji doesn't waste it groping blindly in the dark,
Speaker 6: if he stays in the most minimal life support mode,
Speaker 6: then he can survive for 16 hours.
Speaker 3: The second tank battalion has been deployed.
Speaker 3: Roger. Hold your current positions and stand by.
Speaker 3: Confirmed. Condition green. New line transmitting data.
Speaker 4: The UN forces have surrounded the shadow.
Speaker 4: Movement?
Speaker 4: It hasn't moved. It stopped spreading once it passed a diameter of 600 meters.
Speaker 4: Speaking of which, is there a reason for moving all those ground troops in there?
Speaker 2: They're there to help us apply pressure, theoretically.
Speaker 2: Taking matters into his own hands.
Speaker 2: Defying
Speaker 4: operations.
Speaker 2: I guess he
Speaker 4: got what he was asking for.
Speaker 4: Just because he got a little better score than mine,
Speaker 4: why'd he have to go and try to show me how it ought to be done?
Speaker 4: Ein großer Dumpkopf, nicht?
Speaker 4: What?
Speaker 4: Oh, were my comments about Shinji pissing you off, Wonder Girl?
Speaker 8: I wonder, do you only pilot a Neva for the praise of others?
Speaker 8: What
Speaker 4: in the hell are you talking about?
Speaker 4: I don't need to have anybody's approval but my own!
Speaker 4: Cut it out, you two.
Speaker 4: Asuka's right. He acted arbitrarily and without consulting anyone.
Speaker 2: So I guess I'll just have to punish him when he comes back.
Speaker 3: I never thought that doing nothing could be this exhausting.
Speaker 3: Still nothing but white noise.
Speaker 5: No radar
Speaker 3: data or sonar reflections.
Speaker 3: It's been 12 hours since I switched to life support mode.
Speaker 3: My life will end in 4 or 5 hours.
Speaker 3: I'm hungry.
Speaker 2: So that shadow is actually the
Speaker 6: angel's body?
Speaker 6: Correct. It's 680 meters in diameter with a thickness of 3 nanometers.
Speaker 6: Sustained within that ultra-thin space is an inverted AT field.
Speaker 6: Inside of that field is a region of space that can only be defined by abstract mathematics.
Speaker 6: A sea of Dirac. It could be another universe.
Speaker 6: What about the sphere?
Speaker 6: It disappears when the imaginary circuit of the body closes.
Speaker 6: This implies that the object in the sky is a kind of shadow.
Speaker 6: So the black shadow that swallowed Unit 1 is the real target.
Speaker 6: Then there's no way we
Speaker 2: can fight it.
Speaker 3: The water is getting cloudy.
Speaker 3: The purification system is breaking down.
Speaker 3: It smells in here.
Speaker 3: Blood.
Speaker 3: This lake smells like blood.
Speaker 5: No, I hate
Speaker 3: this place.
Speaker 3: Let me out.
Speaker 3: Why can't I open this log?
Speaker 3: Open up.
Speaker 3: Let me out.
Speaker 3: He's not going to tell me what's going on.
Speaker 3: He's not all.
Speaker 3: Asuka, I know he needs to go.
Speaker 3: Father.
Speaker 3: Please.
Speaker 3: Someone help me.
Speaker 6: You're gonna blow the shadow up?
Speaker 6: I'm afraid it's the only possibility that might work.
Speaker 6: The plan is to drop all 992 existing N2 mines into the target center, while simultaneously
Speaker 6: activating the AT fields of both remaining Avas in such a way as to disrupt the hypothetical
Speaker 6: circuit that encloses the Angel's pocket interior.
Speaker 6: If we concentrate enough explosive power during that same microsecond, we could destroy the
Speaker 6: Angel along with the Darok-C that makes up its body.
Speaker 6: But the damage to Ava would be...
Speaker 6: Shinji wouldn't...
Speaker 6: What kind of rescue operation is this?
Speaker 6: Our priority is to get the Eva back,
Speaker 6: even if it has to be destroyed in the process.
Speaker 6: Now wait a second!
Speaker 6: Under these conditions, the pilot's life is irrelevant.
Speaker 7: It's your responsibility if Shinji's lost, Masato!
Speaker 7: You seem to have forgotten
Speaker 2: that!
Speaker 2: Then why in the hell are you and Commander Ikari
Speaker 2: so worried about recovering Unit 1?
Speaker 2: What's so special about it?
Speaker 2: You've been
Speaker 6: given all the information, Major!
Speaker 6: That's a bull.
Speaker 6: Miss Otto, just trust me.
Speaker 6: I'm taking command of this entire operation, effective immediately.
Speaker 6: Forward all flights to Kansai International Airport.
Speaker 6: Contact air control and the air transport...
Speaker 6: Second
Speaker 2: impact?
Speaker 2: The instrumentality
Speaker 6: project,
Speaker 2: Adam.
Speaker 6: There's so many secrets that I'm in the
Speaker 2: dark about.
Speaker 3: Who's that?
Speaker 3: Who?
Speaker 3: Who, Shinji Ikari?
Speaker 3: That's me.
Speaker 3: I am you.
Speaker 3: This self incorporates another self.
Speaker 3: The self has always been composed of two selves.
Speaker 3: To?
Speaker 3: Yes, the self which is observed and the
Speaker 5: self
Speaker 3: which observes itself.
Speaker 3: To expound, there is the Shinji Ikari that exists in your mind, the Shinji Ikari in Misato
Speaker 3: Katsuragi's mind, the Shinji Ikari in Asuka Soryu's mind, the Shinji Ikari in Rei Ayanami's
Speaker 3: mind, and the Shinji Ikari in Gendo Ikari's mind.
Speaker 3: All are different Shinji Ikaris, but each of them is a true Shinji Ikari.
Speaker 3: What you fear is the Shinji Ikaris who exist in the minds of others.
Speaker 3: I'm just afraid of being hated.
Speaker 3: You are afraid of being hurt.
Speaker 4: Who is bad?
Speaker 3: Father is.
Speaker 3: The father who deserted us.
Speaker 4: No, I'm the one who's bad!
Speaker 4: There you go again! You're always apologizing!
Speaker 4: Do you really think it's your fault?!
Speaker 2: I'm worthless.
Speaker 2: No!
Speaker 2: You just believe that you're worthless, Shinji.
Speaker 2: Don't you trust your own father?
Speaker 3: I thought I hated my father, but now I'm not sure.
Speaker 2: That was good work, Shinji.
Speaker 3: My father called me by my name. I was praised by my father!
Speaker 3: Will you live the rest of your life regurgitating and redigesting those few pleasant memories?
Speaker 1: If I trust
Speaker 3: their words, it's enough. Enough to keep me alive.
Speaker 3: Even though you know you're deceiving yourself?
Speaker 3: Everybody does it. That's how everyone survives.
Speaker 3: If you will not accept that you are capable of initiating change within yourself, you will be unable to continue.
Speaker 3: This world is filled with too much pain and suffering to keep going on.
Speaker 3: For example, you can't
Speaker 1: swim.
Speaker 1: Humans
Speaker 3: aren't made to float.
Speaker 3: This is self-deception.
Speaker 3: I don't care what you want to call it.
Speaker 3: You have been shutting your eyes and covering your ears,
Speaker 3: making yourself blind and deaf to that which you wish to avoid.
Speaker 3: His sister was injured during the incident.
Speaker 2: Who cares what the others say?
Speaker 3: Leave.
Speaker 3: See? You're running away from the reality again.
Speaker 2: No, I don't want to hear this!
Speaker 2: No one
Speaker 3: can justify their existence
Speaker 3: by linking their happiest moments into a kind of rosary.
Speaker 3: In particular, I cannot.
Speaker 3: I cannot. I cannot.
Speaker 5: What's
Speaker 3: wrong with doing something I want to do?
Speaker 3: Why won't you
Speaker 6: leave me alone?
Speaker 2: The entry plug energy reserve should be reaching their expiration point about now.
Speaker 6: The plug sits life support system will be getting closer to redline.
Speaker 6: We'll advance the schedule by 12 minutes.
Speaker 6: Let's do it while there's a possibility that Shinji's still alive.
Speaker 3: Father, don't you want me?
Speaker 5: Father!
Speaker 4: That's right. He may be guilty of killing his own wife.
Speaker 4: He killed his own wife?
Speaker 2: No! Mother was... smiling.
Speaker 2: Shinji, you did something very important today.
Speaker 6: Shinji, you must not run away.
Speaker 2: You've got to do your best.
Speaker 3: I hate this place.
Speaker 5: I hate
Speaker 3: this loneliness.
Speaker 3: I know.
Speaker 3: The heat system and the oxygen are giving out.
Speaker 3: I'm cold
Speaker 3: The suit is giving out too
Speaker 3: So cold
Speaker 3: This is the end
Speaker 3: So tired of everything
Speaker 5: Mother?
Speaker 3: Is this enough?
Speaker 3: Well, that's good for you.
Speaker 3: Both Avas are in
Speaker 5: position and
Speaker 3: standing by.
Speaker 2: AT fields are ready
Speaker 3: to generate.
Speaker 4: Roger.
Speaker 4: T-minus 60 seconds to mine drop.
Speaker 4: What the hell is that?
Speaker 7: What's going on?
Speaker 7: We don't know!
Speaker 7: All of our meters and gauges are going off the scale!
Speaker 7: But we haven't done anything yet!
Speaker 7: You think it could be Shinji?
Speaker 7: It's impossible!
Speaker 7: Uni-1's power level must be at zero!
Speaker 7: Whoa!
My god! Is that what I'm piloting?
Speaker 2: God in heaven, what kind of monster have we made this from?
Speaker 2: I know that the Evas are more than just copies of the first angel.
Speaker 2: But what is Nerve going to do with them?
Speaker 2: What is Nerve going to do with the Evas once all the angels have been destroyed?
*Screaming*
Speaker 5: Shindy! Shindy!
Shindy! Shindy!
Speaker 2: Shindy!
Speaker 1: Are you alright?
Speaker 3: I just wanted to see them one more time.
Speaker 4: Weren't you going to punish him?
Speaker 6: I've never seen the Eva looking as horrifying as it did today.
Speaker 6: Are the Evas really on our side?
Speaker 6: Or do they hate us?
Speaker 6: There's something else.
Speaker 6: I think that Major Katsuragi may suspect something.
Speaker 2: Let her be, at least for now.
Speaker 6: If Rei or Shinji were to learn about the Eva secrets, they'd never forgive us.
Speaker 8: You can rest today
Speaker 8: We'll take care of everything
Speaker 8: But I'm
Speaker 3: I'm feeling just fine now
Speaker 3: Well, that's good for you
Speaker 2: Huh?
Oh!
Speaker 3: Ah...
Speaker 3: It still smells like blood.
I love you.
Speaker 5: I love
you.