Speaker 1: The young man like a poor man
Speaker 1: You're a young man, you're a fairy tale
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now on the door
Speaker 1: I can't wait to see
Speaker 1: 遥か未来目指すための羽があること
Speaker 1: 残酷な天使のテゼ 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
Speaker 1: ほとばしる熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
Speaker 2: It's eating the angel.
Speaker 3: Those bindings allowed us to control it, but now the Ava is removing the web that binds it to our will.
Speaker 3: The beast inside the Ava is free at last!
Speaker 4: Unit 1's awakened and been set free.
Speaker 4: Zaylay sure won't stay quiet about this, will they?
Speaker 5: This is insane.
Speaker 5: The Ava series aren't capable of generating S2 organs themselves,
Speaker 5: but we never imagined that one would be able to take one into itself this way.
Speaker 2: This incident is at extreme odds with the scenario we created.
Speaker 5: Gando Ikari.
Speaker 5: It was a mistake to
Speaker 6: entrust nerve to him, wasn't it?
Speaker 7: Hmm.
Speaker 6: But he was the only one who could achieve this project's goals.
Speaker 6: Ikari, what's going on in your mind?
Speaker 6: It's begun at last.
Speaker 6: Indeed.
Speaker 6: This
Speaker 8: is the beginning.
Speaker 9: The damage the Ava incurred is beyond the Hendlick limit.
Speaker 9: Yes. It may be a while before we can restore everything to normal.
Speaker 9: Fortunately, the Magi system can be transferred to a new location.
Speaker 9: We may be able to begin working as early as tomorrow.
Speaker 9: This place isn't going to
Speaker 10: be viable anymore.
Speaker 10: It's just a matter of time before they decide to abandon it.
Speaker 10: Most likely.
Speaker 10: But for the time being, we'll have to use the secondary control center.
Speaker 10: Without the Magi?
Speaker 10: Yes. We'll clean the dust off and be back in business by this afternoon.
Speaker 9: But the chairs are too cramped down there and the sensors don't operate smoothly.
Speaker 9: It's difficult to work there.
Speaker 11: Well, at least the layout is the same as our original control center.
Speaker 9: At least we have
Speaker 10: an alternative.
Speaker 10: We have no choice when it comes to using Unit 1.
Speaker 2: It may be restrained by the cage, but are you sure it's safe?
Speaker 11: Well, no heat emissions, free electrons, electromagnetic fields, or chemical reactions,
Speaker 11: and the S2 unit's completely inactive.
Speaker 2: Nevertheless, on three separate occasions, Unit 1 has moved without power.
Speaker 2: You can't judge this situation by just the things you can see.
Speaker 11: Uh-huh. We sure can't take any chances. That's a fact.
Speaker 11: It's as unpredictable as you are, Major.
Speaker 11: Uh... sorry.
Speaker 6: However, our concerns are not limited to Unit 1.
Speaker 6: Correct.
Speaker 7: Serious damage was sustained by Units 0 and 2. Headquarters was partially destroyed, exposing Central Dogma.
Speaker 5: We can't even estimate how much money and time have been lost.
Speaker 5: This is because we didn't put a bell around
Speaker 6: Ikari's neck.
Speaker 4: A bell was there,
Speaker 6: but it didn't ring.
Speaker 6: A bell that doesn't ring has no purpose. We'll make sure the bell works next time.
Speaker 4: My, my. What a completely unexpected situation.
Speaker 4: How will you explain this to the committee? I mean, to Sele?
Speaker 8: There isn't anything to explain. Unit 1 wasn't under our control. This was an accident.
Speaker 8: Thus, Unit 1 will remain frozen until the committee gives us further orders.
Speaker 8: Exactly.
Speaker 8: That is a very appropriate
Speaker 4: decision. However, isn't your son still trapped inside it?
Speaker 9: I knew this was hopeless. It's not accepting the eject code.
Speaker 9: What about the backup codes?
Speaker 9: Also refused. Even a direct circuit isn't getting through.
Speaker 11: But the plug's video monitor's still active. I'm channeling it to the main screen.
Speaker 10: What in the hell is this?
Speaker 10: This is the truth behind a 400% sync ratio.
Speaker 2: I can't believe it! What happened to Shinji?
Speaker 2: He's
Speaker 10: been taken into Eva Unit 1.
Speaker 10: Take it into it? What in the hell is an Ava?
Speaker 10: It's a thing created by man in man's own image.
Speaker 10: I really can't describe it any other way.
Speaker 10: Created by man?
Speaker 10: You didn't create anything.
Speaker 10: You just copied something you found in the Antarctic.
Speaker 10: What was the original? That's what I want to know.
Speaker 10: This is not just a copy.
Speaker 10: A human will is inside it.
Speaker 10: Are you saying somebody willed this to happen?
Speaker 10: Yes, the Ava did.
Speaker 2: Do something, damn it!
Speaker 2: You created this, didn't you?
Speaker 2: Take responsibility for what
Speaker 12: you've done!
Speaker 13: I'm still alive.
Speaker 13: I know that Wonder Girl's still alive!
Speaker 13: Don't bother me with trivial crap like that, Misato!
Speaker 13: I can't believe it.
Speaker 3: I couldn't do anything.
Speaker 3: I can't believe that stupid Shinji outperformed me.
I can't stand it.
Speaker 10: What do
Speaker 2: you mean you're
Speaker 10: going to salvage Shinji?
Speaker 10: Well, theoretically, Shinji's life force still exists in there.
Speaker 10: Ha! And will you be respecting that life this time?
Speaker 10: Losing Shinji is out of the question now.
Speaker 10: Oh, I don't know.
Speaker 10: What Nerve wants is Unit 1 as their tool, not Shinji.
Speaker 10: I don't deny
Speaker 9: it.
Speaker 9: Our assumption is that Shinji's body lost its ego border,
Speaker 9: and that he's now floating in the entry plug in quantum form.
Speaker 9: You're saying that Shinji has shifted into a form we can't see?
Speaker 9: Yes. The LCL has chemically altered into something very similar to the seawater of primitive Earth.
Speaker 10: In fact, it's almost identical to the primordial soup we've duplicated in laboratories.
Speaker 10: Primordial soup?
Speaker 10: Yes. All of the substances which composed Shinji are still preserved in the plug,
Speaker 10: and his soul exists there as well.
Speaker 10: In fact, his ego image is giving a
Speaker 9: sort of substance to his plug suit.
Speaker 9: In other words, this salvage operation must both reconstruct his body and return his soul into it.
Speaker 9: Is that possible?
Speaker 9: Possible?
Speaker 10: With the Magi's support? Yes, it is.
Speaker 10: This
Speaker 2: is all theoretical stuff you're talking about, isn't it?
Speaker 2: You won't know what will really happen until you do it.
Speaker 14: What is this? Where am I?
Speaker 14: The entry plug of Unit 1?
Speaker 14: But there's nobody here.
Speaker 14: Not even myself.
Speaker 14: What is this?
Speaker 14: I don't understand.
Speaker 14: These people.
Speaker 14: Yes, they're people I know.
Speaker 14: People who know me.
Speaker 14: I understand now.
Speaker 14: This is my world.
Speaker 14: What is this?
Speaker 14: This is supposed to be my world, but this I don't understand.
Speaker 14: An image from outside.
Speaker 14: A hostile image?
Speaker 14: That's right.
Speaker 14: The enemy.
Speaker 14: Enemy.
Speaker 14: Our enemies are something called angels.
Speaker 14: They have the names of the angels, too.
Speaker 14: They are the targets of Eva and Nerve.
Speaker 14: This is our revenge for the death of Misato's father.
Speaker 14: But why do I fight?
Speaker 14: Why do I do this despite all the pain and suffering?
Speaker 13: What are you, stupid?
Speaker 13: An unknown enemy is attacking us.
Speaker 13: Of course we have to fight them.
Speaker 13: Who cares what they think?
Speaker 14: Am I odd to try to find a reason to fight?
Speaker 14: Am I not supposed to think about it?
Speaker 14: Enemy. Enemy. Enemy. Enemy. Enemy. Enemy.
Speaker 14: All are my enemies.
Speaker 14: That which threatens us is the enemy.
Speaker 14: Of course, how can I be faulted for protecting my own life and those of others?
Speaker 14: Enemy. Enemy. Enemy. Enemy. Enemy. Enemy.
Speaker 14: My enemy. Enemy. Enemy.
Speaker 14: My enemy.
Speaker 14: Damn it. Damn it. God damn it.
Speaker 14: You hurt Doji and killed my mother!
FATHER!
Speaker 14: Why do you hate your father?
Speaker 14: Anyone would hate him. He's no father at all.
Speaker 14: You don't understand him, do you?
Speaker 14: Of course not. In 14 years, I've hardly ever even seen him.
Speaker 14: Is that why you hate him?
Speaker 14: Yes. My father doesn't need me.
Speaker 14: My father deserted me!
Speaker 14: Am I a substitute?
Speaker 14: Yes! That's got to be it!
Speaker 14: He abandoned me because he already
Speaker 2: had Ayanami!
Speaker 2: As if you didn't already run away yourself.
Speaker 14: No! It's all his fault!
Speaker 14: That time I was actually going to tell him I hate him!
Speaker 14: Did you make me become a pilot just to make me suffer?
Speaker 5: Correct.
Speaker 14: How can you say that?!
Speaker 14: You have to be so called! It's not fair!
Speaker 14: You didn't even need me, did you?
Speaker 4: I called you because I had a use for you.
Speaker 14: But why? Why is it me?
Speaker 8: Because there is no one else who can do it.
Speaker 14: No way. Why haven't I ever seen this before?
Speaker 14: It's not fair! It's not possible!
Speaker 14: That's right! I already knew Ava!
Speaker 14: I already knew Ava!
Speaker 14: And then I ran away, leaving my father and mother behind!
Speaker 5: Current
Speaker 10: concentration of
Speaker 1: LCL stable at 36.
Speaker 1: Oxygen concentration is nominal.
Speaker 5: Electromagnetic radiation pulse is normal.
Speaker 5: Weight pattern is zero.
Speaker 1: All counters are functioning normally.
Speaker 9: Salvage operation guidelines.
Speaker 9: It's incredible that you were able to come up with all this in just one month.
Speaker 10: Thanks for the credit, but this isn't all my work.
Speaker 10: The majority of this data is from ten years ago.
Speaker 10: What
Speaker 9: data from ten years ago?
Speaker 9: Has this happened before?
Speaker 9: Yes, but it was before I started working here.
Speaker 10: It was during my mother's time.
Speaker 10: But I can still pick her brains.
Speaker 9: Then how
Speaker 10: did it come out ten years ago?
Speaker 10: They didn't succeed.
Speaker 14: Kindness.
Speaker 14: Warmth.
Speaker 14: Is this warmth a part of being human?
Speaker 14: I was never aware of it until now.
Speaker 14: I was never aware of it before, but now I think I know what it is.
Speaker 14: I didn't know what it was, but now I think I understand.
Speaker 14: They are.
Speaker 14: Because... because I pilot an Ava.
Speaker 14: That's why they treat me so well. That's the reason I keep going on.
Speaker 14: It's the justification for my continuing existence.
Speaker 14: Who and why I am.
Speaker 14: That's why I have to pilot the Ava.
Speaker 14: To fight.
Speaker 14: I have to fight the ones that they call our enemy.
Speaker 14: That I have to win.
Speaker 14: That's right. I can't lose.
Speaker 14: I must be the pilot.
Speaker 14: I must do what they tell me to do.
Speaker 14: And I've got to win.
Speaker 14: Just like they tell me to.
Speaker 14: Otherwise, I'm nobody.
Speaker 14: Nobody.
Work hard.
Speaker 10: Work hard, Shinji.
Speaker 10: Get to work, you stupid idiot.
Speaker 10: Yeah, work hard.
Speaker 14: You gotta work hard.
Speaker 7: Good job, Shinji.
Speaker 14: Misato, Ritsuko, Asuka, Toji, Kinsuke, Father.
Speaker 14: They all respect me.
Speaker 14: They respect me when I pilot the Eva.
Speaker 14: They respect this totally worthless being.
Speaker 14: They all tell me piloted, so I'll prove to my father that I'm worth something.
Speaker 14: Work hard, Shinji.
Speaker 14: But I am working hard. I am.
Speaker 14: Somebody, please. Somebody be nice to me.
Speaker 14: I fought so much. I'm doing the best I can.
Speaker 14: Can't you treat me better? Can't you be nice to me?
Speaker 14: Why can't you be nice to me?
Speaker 2: I'm nice to you.
Speaker 2: Tell me, Shinji, do you want to become one with me?
Speaker 2: To be of one mind and body?
Speaker 2: It could be very, very nice.
Speaker 2: Ask me anytime. I'm ready.
Speaker 2: Hey,
Speaker 13: Shinji, you idiot.
Speaker 13: Don't you want to be one with me?
Speaker 13: To be of one mind and body?
Speaker 13: It would be really awesome.
Speaker 13: You ought to appreciate your good fortune.
Speaker 13: Come on.
Speaker 2: Ikari.
Speaker 2: Do you want to become one with me?
Speaker 2: To be of one mind and body?
Speaker 2: It could be very pleasant.
Speaker 2: Shinji?
Speaker 2: Do you want to become one with me?
Speaker 2: To be of one mind and body and soul?
Speaker 2: It could be very pleasant.
Speaker 2: Relax and release your soul.
Speaker 14: All of the probes have been inserted.
Speaker 14: Electromagnetic radius is fixed at zero minus three.
Speaker 9: Eagle water pulse connection is complete.
Speaker 9: Roger, start the salvage operation.
Speaker 11: Initiating program. Transmitting burst signal.
Speaker 11: Signal received. No rejection.
Speaker 9: Proceed to send the second and third signals.
Speaker 10: Affirmative. Shift the subject to stage two.
Speaker 10: Come on, Shinji.
Speaker 2: Stupid Shinji.
Speaker 11: Shinji
Speaker 2: Akari.
Speaker 11: Hey, Shinji!
Speaker 2: Yo, Shinji!
Speaker 2: Ikari.
Speaker 2: Shinji.
Speaker 2: Stupid Shinji.
Speaker 2: Shinji Ikari.
Speaker 2: Hey, Shinji.
Speaker 2: Yo, Shinji!
Speaker 2: Ikari.
Speaker 7: Shinji.
Speaker 7: Stupid Shinji.
Speaker 7: Shinji Ikari.
Speaker 9: It's no good!
Speaker 9: His ego borderline is frozen into a fixed loop!
Speaker 9: Try to radiate the wave patterns from all directions!
Speaker 3: My god!
Speaker 3: All of the radiated signals are being trapped in Klein space!
Speaker 3: What does that mean?
Speaker 3: It means we failed.
Speaker 3: Abort intervention!
Speaker 3: Reverse the tangent graph!
Speaker 3: Set the addition value at zero.
Speaker 3: Right!
Speaker 11: Distudo reaction in the Q area.
Speaker 11: Pattern is sepia.
Speaker 11: I've got a change in the core pulse 2!
Speaker 11: Plus O3, confirm!
Speaker 3: Maintaining current condition has
Speaker 9: priority!
Speaker 9: Stop that backbone!
Speaker 9: Right!
Speaker 9: Plus.5!
Speaker 9: .8!
Speaker 9: This is all wrong!
Speaker 9: I can't stop it!
Speaker 9: What's going on?!
Speaker 14: Don't you want to come back?
Speaker 14: Why, Shinji?
Speaker 14: I don't...
Speaker 14: I don't understand myself.
Speaker 14: I...
Speaker 14: What do I want?
Speaker 15: What do you want?
Speaker 15: What do you want, Shinji?
Speaker 9: The EVA is rejecting the
Speaker 15: signal!
Speaker 11: Shinji's ego formation is disintegrating in the LCL!
Speaker 11: Pressure in the plug is increasing!
Speaker 11: Aboard all operations! Power
Speaker 9: down!
Speaker 9: It's not working! The plug is being ejected!
Speaker 9: *BOOM*
Speaker 14: SHANJI!
*GASP*
Speaker 14: Where am I?
Speaker 14: Inside the Ava!
Speaker 14: Inside the Ava?
Speaker 14: Did I pilot the Ava again?
Speaker 14: But why?
Speaker 14: You won't pilot the Ava anymore?
Speaker 14: I decided that I would never pilot Ava again.
Speaker 2: But you have just piloted Evangelion Unit 1.
Speaker 2: Shinji, you are here because you have piloted the Eva.
Speaker 2: Piloting the Eva has created your present.
Speaker 2: You can
Speaker 16: never deny your past,
Speaker 2: Shinji.
Speaker 2: Nor can you deny the fact that you did indeed pilot it once more.
Speaker 2: That which is, is.
Speaker 2: It's true.
Speaker 2: I just wanted to tell you that only you can decide.
Speaker 2: It's your future.
Speaker 2: Only you can decide, Shinji.
Speaker 2: You must make a choice.
Speaker 14: I...
Speaker 2: I...
Speaker 2: I am science! It can't even save one small life!
Speaker 2: Give me back my Shinji!
Speaker 2: GIVE HIM BACK!
Speaker 14: That scent... a human smell...
Speaker 14: Misato?
Speaker 14: Ayanami?
Speaker 14: No, not that.
Speaker 14: That's right.
Speaker 14: This is the smell of my mother.
Speaker 14: The second
Speaker 8: impact has occurred. Must he live in this hell?
Speaker 15: Anywhere can be heaven, as long as you try to live.
Speaker 15: And because he is alive, for as long as he lives, he will have a chance to attain happiness.
Speaker 4: Of course. You're right.
Speaker 15: Mother? Have you decided yet?
Speaker 14: If it's a boy, Shinji. If it's a girl, I'll name the baby, Rei.
Speaker 15: Shinji, Rei,
good names.
Speaker 16: Mother.
Speaker 7: Shinji?
Speaker 7: Shinji!
Speaker 10: Well, Unit 1's restoration ought to be finished by the day after tomorrow.
Speaker 10: So even when they're given divine power, human beings still treat it as a matter of fact.
Speaker 10: I can hardly agree with that.
Speaker 10: Speaking of which, the committee is looking at freezing the Evas.
Speaker 2: The Evangelion androids.
Speaker 2: They may be man-made, but who knows what lurks inside that black box.
Speaker 2: Uh-huh.
Speaker 2: I'm just glad that Shinji's
Speaker 10: life was saved.
Speaker 10: No thanks to me. The credit probably goes to you.
Speaker 10: Hey, you want to go bar hopping tonight?
Speaker 2: Uh, sorry.
Speaker 2: I've got to go somewhere.
See ya!
Speaker 10: Shinji's just been saved and she's already running to her lover?
Speaker 10: Well, I guess I can't blame her.
Speaker 2: Ritsuko must be thinking I'm pretty disgusting.
Speaker 4: Appearing to give in to our sexual desires makes for a more realistic appearance.
Speaker 4: A good deception.
Speaker 2: Deceive the intelligence department?
Speaker 2: Or the commander in Ritzko? Or me?
Speaker 4: No, no. I meant myself.
Speaker 2: You want to fool the others?
Speaker 2: You never show interest in others, but you want their attention.
Speaker 2: You really are just like my dad.
Speaker 4: I didn't know you still smoked.
Speaker 2: I only smoke after this sort of thing, so nobody knows but you.
Speaker 2: Here's smoke in your eyes.
Speaker 4: Really? I'm honored.
Speaker 2: And how's instrumentality going?
Speaker 2: Adam could wipe out mankind.
Speaker 2: Why is he being kept there?
Speaker 4: Did you come to see me just to learn that?
Speaker 2: Yeah.
Speaker 2: Well, actually, that's one of the reasons.
Speaker 2: It
Speaker 4: would be my honor to be used as my lady's cat's paw.
Speaker 4: But I can't.
Speaker 2: I just want you to know what I want.
Speaker 2: What are Nerve and Commander Ikari really planning?
Speaker 4: I'd like to know that myself.
Speaker 2: Hey, you can't dodge my questions by doing that.
Speaker 2: No, don't put strange things in there.
Speaker 2: What are you doing?
Speaker 2: I can't believe this.
Speaker 2: What?
Speaker 7: What is this?
Speaker 4: This is for you.
Speaker 4: The first time in eight years.
Speaker 4: And maybe the last as well.
piano plays softly
Thank you.
Speaker 12: Vice Commander Futsuki is abducted by Xaeli and memories of the past pass through his mind.
Speaker 12: Memories of what started in Kyoto in 1999.
Speaker 12: Will Nerve be enough of a fortress for mankind?
Speaker 12: Next episode, the birth of Nerve.