Speaker 1: The young man like a young man
Speaker 1: The young man, you are a fairy tale
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now on the door
Speaker 1: I can only see you, but I'm smiling and smiling.
Speaker 1: I'm so sure you can touch me, but I'm not sure I can.
Speaker 1: But I'll see you soon, right?
Speaker 1: The future will be a place for the future.
Speaker 1: The crazy thing is that the world is in the window.
Speaker 1: I'm going to be a hot hot potter
Speaker 1: I'm going to be afraid of my dreams
Speaker 1: I'm going to be a light in the sky
Speaker 1: I'm a young man, you're a fairy tale
*Sexy music*
Speaker 2: There was no other choice!
Speaker 2: Because he was an angel!
Speaker 2: Koro was an angel!
Speaker 2: He was still an angel!
Speaker 2: He was still one of the enemy!
Speaker 2: He wasn't!
Speaker 3: Even though he was as human as me?
Speaker 2: No!
Speaker 2: He was an angel!
Speaker 2: Is that why
Speaker 3: you killed him?
Speaker 3: Yes!
Speaker 3: Otherwise we'd all die!
Speaker 4: We'd have all been destroyed!
Speaker 4: So that's why you killed him.
Speaker 4: I didn't want to kill him!
Speaker 4: I didn't have a choice.
Speaker 4: Help me!
Speaker 4: Please, just help me!
Speaker 4: For God's sake, help me!
Speaker 4: Somebody please help me!
Speaker 4: Is anyone
Speaker 5: listening?
Speaker 5: Somebody please help me!
Speaker 5: I'm taking you!
Speaker 6: He was much better than I am.
Speaker 6: Karu
Speaker 7: should have survived, not me.
Speaker 7: No. The one who deserves to survive is the one who has the will to make it happen.
Speaker 7: He wished for death.
Speaker 7: He ignored his will to survive and chose to die for a false hope.
Speaker 7: Survival is not a mistake, Shinji.
Speaker 6: Are you sure? Are you sure it was right?
Speaker 7: I don't understand. What can I do?
Speaker 6: What am I supposed to do?
Speaker 6: What was that?
Speaker 6: I fear myself?
Speaker 6: I fear being hated?
Speaker 6: But by whom?
Speaker 6: Who is it?
Speaker 6: It's my...
Speaker 6: My father abandoned me!
Speaker 6: He hates me!
Speaker 6: If others hate me, what will I do?
Speaker 6: What will I do?
Speaker 6: Where am I? Where am I supposed to go? I can't see anything. I don't understand what I feel.
Speaker 6: Misato? Misato!
Speaker 6: Hey! Where are you, Misato? I can't see!
Speaker 6: Hey, where am I supposed to go?
Speaker 6: Misato? Asuka? Ainami? Toji? Kintsugi? Ritsuko? Gaji?
Speaker 7: Father?
Speaker 6: Mother...
Speaker 6: Somebody please tell me what I have to do now!
Speaker 6: Evangelion Unit 1.
Speaker 6: I still have to pilot it? Even after it made me kill him?
Speaker 6: My father and the others tell me that I have to pilot it no matter what I want.
Speaker 6: Why do I have to keep fighting after all that's happened?
Speaker 6: Mother! Say something!
Speaker 5: Answer me!
Speaker 6: Because everyone tells me to.
Speaker 6: What do you mean? It's for the sake of mankind. Isn't that good enough?
Speaker 6: That's right. Is there something wrong with that? I'm doing the right thing.
Speaker 6: And when I do it, the others appreciate me. The
Speaker 8: others like me then.
Speaker 8: You're lying.
Speaker 8: Huh?
Speaker 8: Are you stupid? You know damn well that you do this for yourself.
Speaker 8: You're just making up excuses like you
Speaker 6: always
Speaker 8: do.
Speaker 6: I do?
Speaker 8: Pretending you're sacrificing yourself is just another cop-out.
Speaker 8: It makes you feel so special to play the martyr.
Speaker 6: I'm not sure that's true.
Speaker 8: You're feeling lonely and isolated, nothing more.
Speaker 8: Am I?
Speaker 8: Of course you are!
Speaker 8: You live on sympathy and you get it with your Eva, Shinji!
Speaker 8: It could be true.
Speaker 8: You love having others depend upon you.
Speaker 8: It satisfies your twisted little mind.
Speaker 8: That could be...
Speaker 8: If you want real happiness, you've got to find it for yourself.
Speaker 8: not wait for someone to give it to you.
Speaker 9: I didn't want to be in this thing again.
Speaker 9: They're forcing me to buy like this.
Speaker 9: But this piece of junk won't work.
Speaker 9: But it's only junk because of what I've become.
Speaker 9: I'm the garbage
Speaker 5: now.
Speaker 9: I'm worthless.
Speaker 9: Nobody needs me.
Speaker 9: Nobody needs a pilot who can't even control her own Ava.
Speaker 9: - You seek your own value in the perception of others.
Speaker 3: - Shut up!
Speaker 3: - Do you fear being alone?
Speaker 3: Do you fear being alone?
Speaker 3: Are you afraid that you will lose your identity
Speaker 3: if others leave you?
Speaker 8: - You pilot Ava so you'll be preyed.
Speaker 8: - Shut up!
Speaker 8: Shut up!
Speaker 8: Leave me alone!
Speaker 8: How can a wind-up doll like you dare tell
Speaker 3: me that?
Speaker 3: What?
Speaker 3: Who
Speaker 5: am I?
Speaker 3: You are Rei Ayanami.
Speaker 3: But who are you?
Speaker 3: Are you Rei Ayanami as well?
Speaker 3: Correct.
Speaker 3: I'm the thing that is recognized as Rei Ayanami.
Speaker 3: We are all things that are recognized as Rei Ayanami.
Speaker 3: How could all of those possibly be me?
Speaker 3: It is simply because the others call us Rei Ayanami.
Speaker 3: That is the only reason.
Speaker 3: You possess a false body and a fake soul.
Speaker 3: Do you know why?
Speaker 3: I am neither false nor fake. I am simply me.
Speaker 3: No. You are an empty shell with a false soul created by a man named Gendo Ikari.
Speaker 3: You are just an object that is pretending to be a human.
Speaker 3: Look deep within yourself.
Speaker 3: Do you perceive the almost intangible and invisible presence that lurks below your waking self?
Speaker 3: Inside your darkest dreams.
Speaker 3: It is there that your true identity lies.
Speaker 3: No. I am me.
Speaker 3: I became myself by the instrumentality of the links and relationships between myself and others.
Speaker 3: I am formed by interaction with others. They create me as I create them.
Speaker 3: These relationships and interactions serve to shape the patterns of my heart and mind.
Speaker 3: Yes, that is the name for what I share with those who have created the thing known as Ray.
Speaker 3: That is what will continue to shape me.
Speaker 3: But there is someone else who is your true self.
Speaker 3: You don't know her, but she exists.
Speaker 3: You deny that fact and attempt to suppress that facet of your reality.
Speaker 3: Because she might not have human form.
Speaker 3: Because then the present self might cease to be.
Speaker 3: This is what you fear.
Speaker 3: That you will become nothing.
Speaker 3: You are frightened that you will disappear from the minds of others if another exists.
Speaker 3: I'm afraid. Why is that? Because your current self will have never existed.
Speaker 3: Because you will cease to be.
Speaker 3: No, I'm not. I am happy.
Speaker 3: Because I want to die.
Speaker 3: I want despair.
Speaker 3: I want to return to nothing.
Speaker 3: But I can't.
Speaker 3: You won't let me return to nothingness.
Speaker 3: Not yet.
Speaker 3: I still exist because he needs me.
Speaker 3: But when everything is over, when I am of no use anymore, he will abandon me.
Speaker 3: I've prayed for the day he would abandon me.
Speaker 3: But now,
Speaker 10: now I fear it.
Speaker 11: Come, let us go.
Speaker 11: This is the day for which you were created, Ray.
Speaker 3: Yes, sir.
Speaker 6: What? What feeling is this? I think I've experienced this sensation before. It's as though my physical form was disappearing. It feels agreeable, as though my existence is spreading itself out to cover the entire existence.
Speaker 11: Incorrect. It is not a return to nothingness.
Speaker 11: It is merely a return to a state of beginning.
Speaker 11: It is no less than a return to the primal womb that we lost so long ago.
Speaker 11: Souls and minds will become one, attaining eternal balance.
Speaker 11: The final goal is nothing more than that.
Speaker 12: And that's instrumentality.
Speaker 12: Yes, there is an emptiness at the very core of our souls.
Speaker 12: A fundamental incompleteness that has haunted all beings since the very first thought.
Speaker 12: On a primal level, man has always been aware of the darkness that resides at the core of his mind.
Speaker 12: We have seeked to escape from this void and the fear it causes,
Speaker 12: and all man's accomplishments were made in the hope of filling it.
Speaker 7: And so you'll just crush everyone's minds together to fill the gaps?
Speaker 7: Who made you humanity's overseer?
Speaker 7: You came to us bearing an offer of help, yet your benevolence has proved to be as false as our friendship.
Speaker 7: And yet that is exactly as you wished it to be.
Speaker 7: Where am I?
Speaker 6: This is the me that exists in your mind, Misato.
Speaker 7: And yet at the same time, this is also the me which exists in your mind.
Speaker 7: Isn't it, Shinji?
Speaker 6: In order to establish my identity, I have to communicate with the minds of many people.
Speaker 6: I have to examine that which is at my core.
Speaker 6: I have to stare at Misato, who resides on the inside of my mind.
Speaker 6: What is it that you wish for, Misato?
Speaker 13: I have to be a good child.
Speaker 13: Because I have no daddy.
Speaker 13: Because I have to be good and not bother my mommy.
Speaker 13: But I don't want to become like my mom.
Speaker 13: When my father is not here, she always cries.
Speaker 13: I can't cry. I can't depend on anyone else.
Speaker 13: So I have to be good.
Speaker 13: That way maybe my father won't hate me as much.
Speaker 13: I hope. Maybe my father won't hate me if I'd be good.
Speaker 7: But I hated my father.
Speaker 7: And I hated being a good child.
Speaker 7: I hate it. I'm tired of it. I'm tired of keeping myself clean.
Speaker 7: I'm tired of pretending to be pure and noble.
Speaker 7: I'm so tired of it all.
Speaker 7: I want to disgrace myself to get so dirty that no one can stand it.
Speaker 7: I want to see my life and my reputation ruined.
Speaker 7: Is that why you slept with him? With Kaji?
Speaker 7: No, I slept with him because I love him.
Speaker 7: You did? Did you really love him?
Speaker 7: Yes, I did. He accepted me as myself for the real me.
Speaker 7: That's why I let him make love to me
Speaker 7: No, don't show Cindy this I don't want him to see that side of me
Speaker 14: Why are you still embarrassed after all that's happened?
Speaker 7: Because I'm ashamed of it
Speaker 7: Why does this embarrass you? You weren't ashamed then
Speaker 7: You were glad to show your true nature to the man you loved. In fact, you took great pleasure in it.
Speaker 7: No, don't do this!
Speaker 7: You wanted to dirty yourself.
Speaker 7: You should be happy to show this side of yourself to Shinji, shouldn't you?
Speaker 7: No!
Speaker 2: No, no!
Speaker 7: Are you sure? Or is it perhaps your father that you'd like to show this to?
Speaker 7: No!
Speaker 7: Wasn't it really peace of mind that you were seeking in Kaji's bed?
Speaker 7: You wanted peace of mind and warmth from Kaji then?
Speaker 7: No!
Speaker 7: You wanted to find your father in Kaji's embrace, didn't you?
Speaker 7: Is that true?
Speaker 7: It is true.
Speaker 7: In Kaji, I had found my father reborn.
Speaker 7: And so I fled from him.
Speaker 7: I was so afraid.
Speaker 7: He was so much like my father.
Speaker 7: But at the same time, I was also very happy.
Speaker 7: I was never happier.
Speaker 7: That was such a wonderful time.
Speaker 7: That's why I hated it.
Speaker 7: That's why I left.
Speaker 7: That's why I ran away.
Speaker 14: So, no reason was required to begin our love,
Speaker 14: but you needed a reason for ending it.
Speaker 7: Yes, you were so kind, Kashi.
Speaker 7: You were so kind to disgrace me,
Speaker 7: to dirty me,
Speaker 7: to deflower me.
Speaker 14: Just because you hate yourself
Speaker 14: is no reason to injure yourself further.
Speaker 14: Punishing yourself is simply a cheat
Speaker 14: to make you feel better for a little while.
Speaker 14: Don't do this to yourself.
Speaker 7: And now you'll tell me to take care of myself?
Speaker 7: Men always do that.
Speaker 7: They'll escape to their jobs,
Speaker 7: their own world,
Speaker 7: and leave me behind.
Speaker 7: They always leave me behind.
Speaker 6: Always.
Speaker 7: Just like our father did.
Speaker 7: They always escape from the harsh realities.
Speaker 7: Harsh reality.
Speaker 7: I am his harsh reality.
Speaker 7: Of course, I am the problem.
Speaker 7: Stop this!
Speaker 7: Misato.
Speaker 7: Why should anyone else love me anyway? I hate myself!
Speaker 10: You're vulgar and impure.
Speaker 10: You're pathetic.
Speaker 8: You're gross and disgusting! I've never seen anyone in such a
Speaker 7: disgusting relationship!
Speaker 11: Congratulations on your promotion, Major Katsuragi.
Speaker 7: The me who's recognized is the me who's performing a role in order to be appreciated.
Speaker 7: But she's not the real me.
Speaker 7: Your true self is always crying, isn't she?
Speaker 7: Yes, but I am happy.
Speaker 7: I am happy.
Speaker 7: It's true, I am happy.
Speaker 7: I'm not! This isn't the happiness I want!
Speaker 7: This isn't me! It is not
Speaker 2: the true myself!
Speaker 2: I just don't want to face our reality!
Speaker 6: But we have to. We cannot live otherwise.
Speaker 6: You know you'd be alone and afraid.
Speaker 12: Unstable.
Speaker 12: If nobody was sleeping next to you.
Speaker 10: Are you afraid of sleeping alone?
Speaker 10: Or does sleeping by yourself remind you of how empty your life is?
Speaker 14: She can't stand not having other souls around her.
Speaker 14: So, you'll sleep with anyone, won't you, Major?
Speaker 7: No!
Speaker 7: Yes, you just want to be infatuated with primal ecstasy.
Speaker 7: You want to fill the hole in your heart with temporary escape.
Speaker 7: You take advantage of men to soothe the pain in your soul.
Speaker 7: No!
No! No!
Speaker 7: Where am I?
Speaker 6: What do you want, Oscar?
Speaker 8: I want to live by myself.
Speaker 8: I don't want my papa and my mama.
Speaker 8: I'll live by myself.
Speaker 8: And then I won't cry anymore.
Speaker 8: But I'm still crying. Why am I crying?
Speaker 8: I'm a
son. I just don't like her.
Speaker 7: What happened to you with the able
Speaker 11: doctor?
I told you, I'm a human being before I was told.
Speaker 11: But how can a trained person like you?
Speaker 11: She acts too much like
a dog, and she would chase me absolutely.
Speaker 7: Sometimes she even scares me.
Speaker 7: Have
Speaker 6: you had
Speaker 7: such a feeling with her?
Speaker 7: No. And in any case, you will not become Asuka's mother.
Speaker 9: I'm your wife before that.
Speaker 11: Both duties are concurrent.
Speaker 9: In a social perspective, yes.
Speaker 9: But you can't be being her father.
Speaker 6: However, I can quit being her mother anytime.
Speaker 8: You can say that.
Speaker 8: No, Mama!
Speaker 6: Don't
Speaker 8: leave me!
Speaker 2: I'll be good! Promise!
Speaker 2: Don't stop being my mother!
Speaker 2: Don't ignore me!
Speaker 2: No,
Mama!
Don't kill me!
Speaker 15: Your Papa hates your Mama.
Speaker 15: He doesn't need me anymore.
Speaker 15: No.
Speaker 15: He didn't love me to begin with.
Speaker 15: But let's die together.
Speaker 15: Because he doesn't want us.
Speaker 15: He didn't need me at all.
Speaker 15: And he doesn't want you either, Asuka.
Speaker 15: I'm not wanted?
Speaker 15: I'm not
Speaker 8: worth anything?
Speaker 15: Die with me.
Speaker 8: No! I am not your doll!
Speaker 8: I'll think by myself and live by myself!
Speaker 8: And then my mother was hanging from the ceiling.
Speaker 8: She looked so happy.
Speaker 8: But I hated how she looked.
Speaker 8: I don't want to die.
Speaker 8: I don't want to disappear.
Speaker 8: I hate this.
Speaker 8: I hate boys.
Speaker 8: I hate my father and my mother!
Speaker 8: I hate everyone!
Speaker 8: Nobody cares about me, nobody stays with me!
Speaker 8: So I don't want to depend on anybody!
Speaker 8: But I hate it at the same time!
Speaker 8: It's a pain!
Speaker 8: I don't want to be alone!
Speaker 8: I don't want to be alone! I don't want to be alone!
Speaker 7: Don't leave me.
Speaker 7: Don't ignore me.
Speaker 8: Don't kill me!
Speaker 7: What the hell is this?
Speaker 7: This is the instrumentality which your father has initiated.
Speaker 7: This is it?
Speaker 7: This is part of it.
Speaker 7: You can't tell what the truth
Speaker 12: is, Shee.
Speaker 12: Truth is subjective.
Speaker 12: Therefore, you can barely tell that what you can feel is fact.
Speaker 12: The truth is within you.
Speaker 6: And the facts that remain in your memory are what will become your truth.
Speaker 12: Truth can be changed from time to time.
Speaker 3: Sometimes.
Speaker 3: This is all fact. This is the result of everything?
Speaker 3: This is real, but one of many realities.
Speaker 3: This is the conclusion you wanted.
Speaker 3: Wanted? Me?
Speaker 3: Yes. Total destruction.
Speaker 3: You wished for a world in which nobody would be saved.
Speaker 3: No! I didn't wish
for this! The others didn't save me!
Speaker 8: Nobody can
Speaker 12: save you from yourself.
Speaker 14: This is what you wished for.
Speaker 8: destruction, death, and return to nothingness.
Speaker 8: You wished
Speaker 6: for these.
Speaker 6: This is the reality that is.
Speaker 6: What is reality?
Speaker 6: This is your world.
Speaker 11: A world that exists solely for yourself.
Speaker 11: One without time, space,
or anyone else.
Speaker 11: A world in which every
Speaker 6: facet is determined by you.
Speaker 10: This is the world in which you just wait for others to give you something.
Speaker 10: This is your world unless you decide to change reality.
Speaker 7: This is the world that is! Nothing can change that!
Speaker 7: No. You yourself make the decision.
Speaker 7: This is the world
we remind ourselves now.
Speaker 6: Whether it is the will to survive...
Speaker 8: ...or a wish for death, it is all up to you.
Speaker 6: Are you saying that this darkness, this insane world, are what I really wish to create?
Speaker 6: Yes.
Speaker 14: You wished for a closed world that was comfortable for you.
Speaker 14: To protect your few pleasures.
Speaker 10: This is merely the result of your wish.
Speaker 7: In your closed world, in a world where only you are allowed to be, others cannot live with you.
Speaker 12: But still you wished to close off the world that surrounded you.
Speaker 12: Your wish ejected things you disliked and created an isolated and lonely world filled with nothing.
Speaker 3: This is the world your wishes have created.
Speaker 3: A private haven in the recesses of your mind.
Speaker 8: This is how it all ends. One of many possible endings.
Speaker 8: This
Speaker 3: is the ending you brought upon yourself.
Speaker 3: You choose this fate.
Speaker 3: You choose this
fate.
Speaker 1: Fly me to the
Speaker 8: moon and let me play among the stars
Speaker 8: Let me see what spring is like, oh Jupiter
Speaker 1: and
Speaker 8: Mars
Speaker 1: In other worlds, hold my hand
Speaker 1: In other words,
Speaker 5: dearly kiss me
Speaker 5: Feel my heartbeat so, and let me sing forever more
Speaker 5: You are all I know, all I want is a planet
Speaker 5: Another world, please be true
Speaker 5: Another world,
I love you
Speaker 7: An end always comes after a beginning.
Speaker 7: Will our hopes result in ultimate destruction?
Speaker 7: Is our whole existence death itself?
Speaker 7: It's our final episode,
Speaker 7: the beast that shouted,
Speaker 7: I in the heart of the world.
you