Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at it, I'm smiling, you are smiling
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to touch the things I want to make
Speaker 1: I'm not sure how many things you know, I'm still not aware of it
Speaker 1: But I'll see you soon, that's the back of the back of the future.
Speaker 1: The moon will be the way to see the future.
Speaker 1: The cruelest man of the day,
Speaker 1: the window from the end of the day,
Speaker 1: the hot-pastus will be the most popular.
If you're a man who
Speaker 2: Well, let's review it now.
Speaker 2: Normally, the EVA runs off electricity provided by an umbilical cable.
Speaker 2: In emergencies, it can switch to a built-in battery with an active life of one minute at full power,
Speaker 2: and no more than five minutes in the minimal activity gain mode.
Speaker 2: This is due to our current limit in battery capacity technology.
Speaker 2: Do you understand?
Speaker 2: Yes.
Speaker 2: Now let's continue from where we left off yesterday.
Speaker 2: Initiate induction mode.
Speaker 2: Position the target in the center, then squeeze the trigger switch on.
Speaker 2: Take it easy. Position the target in the center.
Speaker 2: Next.
Speaker 3: You know, I can't help but wonder why Shinji agreed to pilot again.
Speaker 3: It seems that he simply does what he's told to do. I suppose that's just his way of getting through life
Speaker 4: Position target in the Center and pull the switch
Speaker 4: Position target in the center and pull the switch
Speaker 4: Position target in the center and hold the switch position target in the center
Speaker 5: Miss Misato, it's morning already.
Speaker 5: I just got back from night duty a little while ago.
Speaker 5: I don't have to go to work until this evening, so please let me sleep.
Speaker 6: Okay, I'll
Speaker 5: go.
Speaker 5: Hey, is this okay Thursday?
Speaker 5: It's burnable trash day.
Speaker 5: Take it to the garbage,
Speaker 7: please.
Speaker 5: So how's school?
Speaker 5: Oh, it's okay.
Speaker 5: Okay, see ya.
Speaker 5: I'll
Speaker 6: see you later.
Speaker 5: Yes, hello?
Speaker 5: Oh, it's you, Ritsuko.
Speaker 2: How's it going? Are you getting along with him?
Speaker 5: Him? Oh, Shinji.
Speaker 5: Well, it's been two weeks since he started school,
Speaker 5: and he doesn't seem to have changed.
Speaker 5: No one ever calls him.
Speaker 2: Calls him where?
Speaker 5: Well, since I figured he'd be needing one,
Speaker 5: I gave him a cellular phone.
Speaker 5: I don't think he's ever used it, though,
Speaker 5: or received any calls.
Speaker 5: I'm not sure, but I don't think he has any friends.
Speaker 2: Well, I would guess that Shinji isn't exactly
Speaker 2: the sort of person who makes friends easily.
Mm-hmm.
Speaker 2: Do you know the fable The Hedgehog's Dilemma?
Speaker 5: Hedgehog?
Speaker 5: You mean those animals with the spiny hair?
Speaker 2: Even though a hedgehog may want to become close with another hedgehog,
Speaker 2: the closer they get, the more they injure each other with their spines.
Speaker 2: It's the same with some humans.
Speaker 2: The reason he seems so withdrawn is because he's afraid of being hurt.
Speaker 5: Well, he's just going to have to learn someday
Speaker 5: that part of growing up means finding a way to interact with others
Speaker 5: while distancing pain.
Speaker 8: What's up, class rep?
Speaker 9: Did you deliver the printout I gave you yesterday?
Speaker 8: What?
Speaker 8: Um, well, um, um, well, um, there wasn't anybody home over at Toji's place.
Speaker 8: Mr. Ida, aren't you Suzuhara's friend?
Speaker 8: Aren't you even just a little bit worried about him?
Speaker 8: You don't suppose he was injured, do you?
Speaker 8: What? You mean in that robot incident?
Speaker 8: The television reports all said that nobody was injured.
Speaker 8: No way. You saw where the explosion on Mount Takanosu was, didn't you?
Speaker 8: There were fighters scrambled from Aruma and Komatsu,
Speaker 8: and there were troops from Isawa and Kyushu.
Speaker 8: I'll bet at least 10 or 20 people were injured.
Speaker 8: And there had to be a few fatalities, too.
Speaker 8: Toji!
Speaker 2: Susahara!
Speaker 8: Where is everyone? Has our entire class disappeared or what?
Speaker 8: They've all either evacuated or they've transferred to other schools.
Speaker 8: No one wants to stay here after that last battle inside the city.
Speaker 8: Yeah, you're probably the only one who's actually enjoying the chance to see a real war.
Speaker 8: That's true.
Speaker 8: And speaking of which, where have you been, Toji?
Speaker 8: Why were you absent so long?
Speaker 8: Did you get involved in the war?
Speaker 10: No, but my little sister did.
Speaker 10: She was crushed under a pile of debris.
Speaker 10: She survived, but she's been in the hospital ever since.
Speaker 10: Both my dad and granddad are working at the lab, and there's no way they can leave their posts.
Speaker 10: So if I'm not with her, she's all alone.
Speaker 8: That robot's pilot was really dumb. It'd make me so angry.
Speaker 8: How could he wreck our own city?
Speaker 8: What did that stupid idiot think he was doing?
Speaker 8: Speaking of the pilot, have you heard the rumor about the transfer student?
Speaker 8: What transfer student?
Speaker 8: Him over there.
Speaker 8: He transferred in while you were absent, right after the giant robot incident.
Speaker 8: Don't you think that's a little bit of an odd coincidence?
Speaker 11: He's coming!
Speaker 11: All rise!
Speaker 12: And so, humankind was about to face its greatest trial.
Speaker 12: In the last year of the 20th century, the massive meteor from outer space slammed into the continent of Antarctica.
Speaker 12: The continent's ice cap was melted almost instantaneously.
Speaker 12: The water level of the oceans increased dramatically.
Speaker 12: The earth was thrown off its axis,
Speaker 12: and new devastatingly abnormal weather patterns were spawned.
Speaker 12: The lives of all living things on the planet were threatened.
Speaker 12: Several thousand species of flora and fauna,
Speaker 12: and half of the world's human population were lost in the immediate aftermath of the disaster.
Speaker 7: Huh?
Speaker 12: That was the so-called second impact.
Speaker 12: The survivors still had to live through the hell of worldwide economic collapse,
Speaker 12: ethnic conflicts, and civil wars.
Speaker 12: However, it has been 15 years since then,
Speaker 12: and in only 15 years we have restored ourselves.
Speaker 12: This is certainly proof of the human race's resilience,
Speaker 12: but even more so, it is the fruit of the blood, sweat, and tears
Speaker 12: your father and mothers have dedicated to this cause.
Speaker 12: I lived in Nebukawa.
Speaker 12: Hey, sit down, you guys! We're
Speaker 9: still in class, you know!
Speaker 9: Sit down now!
Speaker 9: You're always so
Speaker 7: bossy!
Speaker 1: Now cut
Speaker 9: that out!
Speaker 1: Well, you know...
Speaker 9: Hey, how did you get chosen? Did you have to take
Speaker 6: a test?
Speaker 9: Weren't
Speaker 6: you really scared?
Speaker 6: What's a cockpit look like?
Speaker 6: I'm not supposed to talk about classified stuff like that.
Speaker 6: Hey,
Speaker 5: what's the name of that robot?
Speaker 5: I don't
Speaker 6: know much, but everyone calls it Ava or
Speaker 5: Unit 1.
Speaker 5: What's its ultimate attack mode?
Speaker 6: Some kind of vibrating knife.
Speaker 6: An ultrasonic
Speaker 5: wave.
Speaker 5: That's amazing. We are so
Speaker 2: proud of you.
Speaker 12: And thus...
Speaker 9: Oh,
Speaker 12: that's all for the day.
Speaker 9: Ikari, where do you live?
Speaker 9: In the outer part of the city?
Speaker 9: Everybody stand up!
Speaker 9: Belle!
Speaker 9: Hey, you guys, can't you at least show some manners?
Speaker 10: - Sorry, newcomer, but I had to clobber you.
Speaker 10: I had to pop you one to work off my own anger.
Speaker 8: - He's mean, huh?
Speaker 8: His little sister was injured the last time
Speaker 8: you and your robot fought a battle.
Speaker 8: Well, that's his excuse anyway.
Speaker 8: - I didn't have a choice.
Speaker 8: They made me pilot the stupid thing.
Speaker 7: Uh-uh.
Speaker 7: Ah!
Speaker 13: There's an emergency.
Speaker 13: I'll report in first.
Speaker 13: Huh?
Speaker 2: A special state of emergency has been declared for the Kanto and Chuga regions surrounding the Tokai district.
Speaker 1: All residents must
Speaker 5: evacuate to their designated
Speaker 1: shelters immediately.
The End
Speaker 14: Our cameras have sighted the target. It's penetrated our territorial waters.
Speaker 14: Assume battle stations. Level 1.
Speaker 5: Roger! Prepare for anti-aircraft interception.
Speaker 14: Tokyo 3, transforming to battle formation.
Speaker 2: initiate accommodation of the central block.
Speaker 2: Accommodation of the Central Block in the 1st through 7th Districts has been completed.
Speaker 14: Notification of the government and other related ministries completed.
Speaker 2: Present effective rate of anti-aircraft interception, 48%.
Speaker 15: Status of civilians and non-combatants?
Speaker 14: We've received reports that civilian evacuation has been completed.
Speaker 15: Attention elementary school and
Speaker 5: junior high school students.
Speaker 7: Please form groups with your individual classes.
Speaker 8: Not again!
Speaker 8: Just text messages again?
Speaker 8: It's no censorship.
Speaker 8: The government won't let them show any of the battle to us civilians,
Speaker 8: even though it's an incredible historic event.
Speaker 16: The fourth angel would show up while Commander Ikari is away.
Speaker 16: It's a lot sooner than we expected.
Speaker 2: The last time they gave us 15 years.
Speaker 2: This time around, the break's only been three weeks.
Speaker 16: They never care about our situation, do they?
Speaker 16: They're the kind we
Speaker 5: women hate the most.
Speaker 14: It's a waste of the taxpayers' money.
Speaker 14: The committee is demanding that we dispatch an Evangelion again.
Speaker 15: They're more obnoxious than the aliens.
Speaker 15: I'd have mobilized even if they hadn't asked.
Speaker 6: Entry procedure initiated.
Speaker 6: LCL oxygenated. Releasing airlock.
-
Speaker 8: -
Speaker 8: - Hey, I need to talk to you privately for a second.
Speaker 8: - Who want four? - Come on, please.
Speaker 8: - Oh, alright.
Speaker 8: - Hey, class rep! - Now what?
Speaker 8: - We've both gotta go to the bathroom.
Speaker 9: - You were supposed to do that before you came here.
Speaker 10: So what's this all about?
Speaker 9: I've got to
Speaker 8: see it at least once in my life.
Speaker 10: You mean the battle up there?
Speaker 8: Nobody knows when the enemy will come the next time.
Speaker 8: Kensuke, are you serious?
Speaker 8: If we let this opportunity escape us, we may lose it forever.
Speaker 8: Please help me unlock the gate.
Speaker 8: But you can get killed
Speaker 10: if you go out there.
Speaker 8: If we stay here in the shelter, who's to say that the risk isn't the same?
Speaker 8: If I might be killed anyway, I'd rather see it first.
Speaker 10: You idiot.
Speaker 8: What do you think nerves for?
Speaker 8: And what is Nerve's most important weapon?
Speaker 8: It's the robot that new kid pilots.
Speaker 8: He protected us the other day, but you hit him pretty hard.
Speaker 8: Twice.
Speaker 8: If he refuses to fight, we're all going to die.
Speaker 8: Doesn't that make it your obligation to watch him fight?
Speaker 8: Okay, you're not leaving me any options.
Speaker 8: You'll do
Speaker 10: just about anything to get what you want, won't you?
Speaker 5: Shinji, are you ready?
Speaker 2: First, neutralize the enemy's AT field, then fire a volley.
Speaker 2: Do it just like we practiced.
Speaker 2: Can you handle
Speaker 3: that?
Launch, Eva!
Speaker 7: - Cool, all my efforts really paid off.
Speaker 8: I've been waiting for this moment all my
Speaker 7: life.
Speaker 7: *BANG*
*BANG*
Speaker 7: - OHH! - THERE
Speaker 6: IT IS!
Speaker 6: - The AT field has been unfolded.
Speaker 6: - Do it just like we planned, okay Shinji?
Speaker 1: - Okay!
*BANG*
Speaker 9: - Idiot! You hit the enemy with your own smoke!
Speaker 8: *Sigh
Speaker 7: *
Speaker 7: Help!
Speaker 14: The umbilical cable's been snapped off!
Speaker 8: Ava
Speaker 3: has switched to its internal battery
Speaker 8: power source!
Four minutes, fifty-three seconds of activation remaining!
Speaker 7: It's coming this way!
Speaker 5: Shinji!
Speaker 5: Are you all right?
Speaker 5: Damage report!
Speaker 5: No problem, Detective!
Speaker 5: He can make it!
Speaker 5: - Huh?
Speaker 5: - Those are Shinji's classmates.
Speaker 5: - What
Speaker 8: are they doing there?
Speaker 8: - Why isn't he fighting back?
Speaker 8: - Maybe he can't move because we're down here.
Speaker 8: - He can't because of us!
Speaker 3: - Activation time remaining three minutes,
Speaker 8: 28 seconds.
Speaker 3: - Shinji,
Speaker 5: let them
Speaker 3: into the cockpit!
Speaker 9: - Once you've got them, make a temporary retreat.
Speaker 9: We'll start again later.
Speaker 2: - What makes you think that unauthorized civilians
Speaker 2: can be allowed into the entry plug?
Speaker 9: - I'm authorizing it.
Speaker 9: - You're exceeding your authority, Captain.
Speaker 9: - Unit one's remaining activation time, three minutes.
Speaker 9: Shinji, hold Ava on your current commands and inject the
Speaker 16: entry plug.
Speaker 16: Hurry up and do it!
Speaker 1: - -
Speaker 8: - What
Speaker 8: the--? - This water! My camera!
Speaker 8: My camera!
Speaker 6: Abnormal conditions
Speaker 6: occurring in the nervous system! Of
Speaker 2: course!
Speaker 2: You've allowed two foreign bodies into the Matrix! Their noise in
Speaker 2: the nerve impulse system!
AAAAAAAH!
Retreat! Get out of there!
Speaker 9: Utilize recovery route 34. Retreat to the deep side of the mountain!
Speaker 7: Hey,
Speaker 9: Nukid! She
Speaker 6: said retreat! Nukid!
Speaker 6: I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away.
Speaker 6: I mustn't run away!
Speaker 9: The progressive knight's been engaged!
Speaker 9: Obey my order, Shinji! You've got to retreat!
Speaker 9: Shinji!
Speaker 7: NOOOOOO!
Speaker 9: That idiot!
Speaker 3: Unit 1, activation time remaining 30 seconds!
Speaker 3: 28!
Speaker 3: 27!
Speaker 7: 14!
Speaker 7: 13!
Speaker 7: 12!
Speaker 7: 11!
Speaker 7: 10!
Speaker 7: 9!
Speaker 7: 8!
Speaker 7: 7!
Speaker 7: 6!
Speaker 7: 5!
Speaker 7: 4!
Speaker 7: 3!
2!
1!
Speaker 3: AVA Unit 1 is a good one!
Speaker 3: Activation ceased.
Speaker 2: The target is completely silent.
Speaker 2: -
Speaker 10: It's been three days.
Speaker 10: You
Speaker 8: mean since we were chewed out?
Speaker 8: No, since he stopped coming to school.
Speaker 8: Who's he?
Speaker 8: The new kid. Who else would I mean?
Speaker 8: I wonder what he's been doing since then.
Speaker 8: Are you worried about him?
Speaker 8: No, not exactly worried.
Speaker 8: Toji, for someone who's so blunt and tactless, you're pretty stubborn.
Speaker 8: If you had apologized to him back then, you wouldn't have had to agonize over it for three days.
Speaker 8: Here, this is the new kid's phone number. Take it.
Speaker 8: If you're so worried, why don't you call him?
*music*
Speaker 17: Fly me to the moon and let me play among the stars
Speaker 17: Let me see what's playing, it's like on Jupiter and Mars
Speaker 17: In other words, hold my hand
Speaker 17: In other words, darling, kiss me
Speaker 17: Fill my heart with song, oh, let me sing forevermore
Speaker 17: You are all I long for, all I worship and adore
Speaker 17: In other words, please be true.
Speaker 17: In other words,
I love you.
Speaker 11: Overwhelmed and unable to cope with his weaknesses, Shinji attempts to run away.
Speaker 11: Quickly retrieved by the organization, he finds himself surrounded by unsympathetic ears.
Speaker 11: And the only overtures of friendship come from his two classmates.
Speaker 11: It happens in the next episode, where I'll be doling out another helping of fan service.