Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I just saw you just look at me
Speaker 1: I'm smiling at you
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to touch my heart
Speaker 1: I'm just curious to see you
Speaker 1: I'm still not aware of my heart
Speaker 1: But I'll never forget
Speaker 1: The back of the back of the
Speaker 1: I will be a little
Speaker 2: more
Don't hesitate. Move ahead.
If I can see you again, I will say...
Speaker 2: the words that I could not say eight years ago.
Speaker 2: Bye.
Speaker 3: Another phone that will never ring.
Speaker 4: Misato's shutting herself off again, as usual.
Speaker 4: Is Asuka going to come back today?
Speaker 5: She skipped school.
Speaker 5: She won't go home.
Speaker 5: All she does is play those games.
Speaker 5: Hikari?
Speaker 5: Uh, yes?
Speaker 6: Can I sleep here?
Speaker 6: Yeah.
Speaker 6: I'm sorry I'm inconveniencing you.
Speaker 6: You're not inconvenient.
Speaker 6: When I didn't win with my Ava, I lost whatever value I might have had.
Speaker 6: I hate. I hate. I hate everything.
Speaker 6: And I hate myself the most.
Speaker 6: I don't care about anything anymore.
Speaker 6: There's no point.
Speaker 5: There's nothing to be ashamed of, Oscar.
Speaker 5: You did the best you could. You should be proud.
Speaker 5: I'm not a child.
Speaker 7: So that child is gone.
Speaker 7: Yes, even cats die.
Speaker 7: Don't cry, Grandma.
Speaker 7: Yes, I'll come home as soon as I have time.
Speaker 7: I haven't visited Mother's grave in three years.
Speaker 7: Yes, I'll call you next time.
Speaker 7: Yeah, so even cats can die.
Speaker 8: It is impossible to retrieve the Lanch of Longiners now.
Speaker 8: Why did you use it?
Speaker 8: And what about the Ava series? We don't have them all scheduled yet.
Speaker 9: Destroying the Angels was our top priority.
Speaker 9: There was no other way.
Speaker 9: No other
Speaker 8: way?
Speaker 8: You'd better come up with a more believable excuse.
Speaker 9: Your actions these days belie a lack of respect for this committee.
Speaker 9: Fyutski, I'm in conference.
Speaker 9: Understood.
Speaker 9: Another Angel is approaching.
Speaker 9: We must finish this later.
Speaker 8: You're assuming you'll still have a seat here?
Speaker 8: Are you going to betray us, Ikari?
Speaker 3: I'll be there in 15 minutes. Sort a Unit Zero through the 32nd gate. Use Unit Two as the backup.
Speaker 3: No, I'm sorry. I don't have the authority to cancel the Commander's freeze on Unit One.
Speaker 3: That's right. Bye.
Speaker 3: It's another Angel, alright.
Speaker 10: Damn.
Unit Zero has launched. Advancing to intercept.
Speaker 9: Unit Two, remain in the launch bay.
Speaker 9: No. Move it out, sir.
Speaker 9: What?
Speaker 9: No arguments. It might be useful as a decoy at least.
Speaker 9: Right.
Speaker 9: Ava Unit 2 ready to launch.
Speaker 6: Here I am in this seat again.
Speaker 6: Am I even linked to this thing anymore?
Speaker 6: Unit 2, advance
to the 8th gate.
Stand ready to move out as soon as your launch position is determined.
Speaker 6: Even if I go, I'll just be a burden on the others.
Speaker 11: Target approaching. It's past the final intercept line at Gora.
Speaker 6: I just don't care anymore.
Speaker 11: The target is above the Wakidani Valley,
rotating in a fixed position.
Speaker 3: Target's AT field is still active.
Speaker 3: Where have you been?
Speaker 3: I'm sorry, no excuse.
Speaker 3: Status report!
Speaker 3: It
Speaker 9: looks like we're in a stalemate, Major.
Speaker 9: He's right.
Speaker 9: The target's field pattern keeps cycling
Speaker 7: from blue to orange!
Speaker 7: What's that mean?
Speaker 7: The Magi aren't able to answer that question yet!
Speaker 9: We just don't have enough solid data right now.
Speaker 7: However, I'm certain that it's capable of assuming forms
Speaker 7: besides the one we see now.
Speaker 7: So we can't attack first.
Speaker 12: Ray, let's hold back and study it for a bit.
Speaker 12: No,
Speaker 5: it's coming.
- Ray, efface of action!
Speaker 9: - She can't!
Speaker 5: There's not enough
time!
Speaker 9: Contamination! The target's affecting Unit Zero!
Speaker 7: What's
Speaker 12: the status on Unit Zero's AT field?
Speaker 12: The field's up, but it's not stopping the Angel's probe!
Speaker 7: Is the Angel trying to establish first level contact with Unit Zero?
Speaker 7: It must be.
Speaker 7: We've got biocontamination invading Unit Zero!
Speaker 7: Ava Unit 2, roll out! Take some of that
Speaker 10: heat off of Ray!
Speaker 3: *Biofusion
Speaker 12: *
Speaker 13: It's sink! Her sink ratio's under 10%!
Speaker 13: Asuka!
Speaker 3: It just won't move!
Speaker 3: It won't move?
Speaker 3: She's just the target sitting out there! Get her back! Do it now!
Speaker 5: Who is this?
Speaker 5: You. Myself. And an Ava?
Speaker 5: No, I sense somebody other than myself.
Speaker 5: Who are you?
Speaker 5: An angel.
Speaker 5: Are you one of the beings we call the angels?
Speaker 5: Don't you want to become one with me?
Speaker 5: No, I am me, not you.
Speaker 5: Hmm, but you shall.
Speaker 5: It's too late.
Speaker 5: I will share part of my mind with you.
Speaker 5: Let me share with you these emotions.
Speaker 5: This is pain.
Speaker 5: Yes.
Speaker 5: Do you feel this
Speaker 11: pain?
Speaker 11: This pain?
Speaker 11: No, it's different.
*music*
You are that sorrowful.
Speaker 5: Is this a tear?
Am I the one crying?
Speaker 9: Ray!
Speaker 9: I want Evangelion Unit 1 taken out of cryostasis.
Speaker 9: Launch it immediately.
Speaker 9: What?
Speaker 9: I said launch it!
Speaker 6: Yes, sir.
Speaker 6: Why for her?
Speaker 6: Am I so worthless you couldn't do this for me?
Speaker 3: Spread your AT field to full!
Speaker 3: Get way out of there now!
Speaker 14: Right!
Speaker 5: Shikari!
Speaker 3: Shinji! You've got to use your progressive knife!
Speaker 3: *Gunshot*
*Screaming*
You are Akari!
Speaker 5: This is my mind and soul, to become one with Akari.
Speaker 5: *Gunshot*
Speaker 5: You will not!
Speaker 5: Her AT field's
Speaker 10: been reversed!
Speaker 10: She's got biocontamination everywhere!
Speaker 13: She's trying to contain the angel!
-
Speaker 12: -Her field is at its limit. Her core won't be able to hold at this rate. -Rey abandon
Speaker 5: unit zero!
Speaker 5: -I cannot. If I leave unit zero the AT field will cease to be. I will not let it.
Speaker 5: -Rey, don't do
Speaker 10: it.
*Gunshot*
Speaker 14: The targets
Speaker 12: disappeared.
Speaker 12: This operation is over.
Speaker 12: Downgrade alert status to condition yellow.
Speaker 9: Roger. Shifting alert status to condition yellow.
Speaker 3: What's the status of Unit Zero?
Speaker 3: I don't think the entry plug ejected.
Speaker 3: So now to rescue team.
Speaker 7: If there's anything left to rescue...
No antibiotic substances from the 16th Angel have been located as of yet.
Speaker 2: We'll continue to search.
Speaker 7: The traces of Level C spread out to the southwest.
Speaker 2: Dr. Akagi, we've located the plug!
Speaker 9: Dr.
Speaker 7: Akagi...
Speaker 7: Here is top secret. Clean out the plug and destroy everything.
Speaker 7: Understood. Do it now!
Speaker 8: At last, we have defeated all of the Angels up to the Sixteen.
Speaker 8: Now there is only one left.
Speaker 8: As it is written in Xela's Dead Sea Scrolls.
Speaker 8: Promised time is at hand. The road has been long and the sacrifices have been great.
Speaker 8: True. We have lost the Lance of Longinus. And now Unit Zero.
Speaker 8: That is sufficient reason for
Speaker 1: removing Ikari.
Speaker 8: Surely he must have understood what release of Fielitski
Speaker 11: meant.
Speaker 8: We shall have to find another Katspor to use against Ikari.
Speaker 8: And this one must know the truth.
*Bell rings
Speaker 4: Misato, I can't cry anymore.
Speaker 4: I feel the pain, but the tears won't come.
Speaker 4: Why is that?
Speaker 4: Shinji,
Speaker 12: I don't know what to do or say.
Speaker 12: All I can do is be here for you.
Speaker 12: Don't
Speaker 4: touch me!
Speaker 4: Just leave me alone, Misato.
Speaker 4: I'm sorry.
Speaker 3: I know how lonely he must be.
Speaker 12: Does the fact that I'm a woman frighten him?
Speaker 12: Or is he afraid of getting close to anyone?
Speaker 3: Pen-pen, come here.
Speaker 12: It's true.
Speaker 3: Anything is better than being alone.
Speaker 3: And I'm the one who's lonely.
Speaker 15: Ray, the product of my despair,
Speaker 15: and yet at the same time, the vessel of your hope.
Speaker 15: In the end, I suppose it was unreasonable to expect to forget.
Speaker 12: Hello?
Speaker 12: Yes? What?
Speaker 12: Shiji!
Dr. Godai, internal medicine one.
Speaker 13: Dr. Goddai, please call conference room two immediately.
Speaker 14: Ray!
Speaker 14: I'm so glad.
Speaker 14: I can't believe you're alive.
Speaker 14: Why isn't my father here?
Speaker 14: Um, I...
Speaker 14: Thanks for saving my life.
Speaker 5: For doing what?
Speaker 14: You saved me.
Speaker 14: By sacrificing Unit Zero.
Speaker 5: Oh, did I save you?
Speaker 14: Don't you remember?
Speaker 5: I just don't know.
Speaker 5: I think I must be the third one.
Speaker 5: *BOOM*
Speaker 9: *Clocking*
Speaker 9: is likely to cause a great deal of trouble with Chairman Keel.
Speaker 9: I've given the old men of Sele something else to look at.
Speaker 9: There is no problem.
Speaker 9: It is our intent to carry
Speaker 8: out this Inquisition
Speaker 9: in a dignified
Speaker 8: manner.
Speaker 8: It is not our intent to bring any shame upon you.
Speaker 7: I don't feel any shame.
Speaker 8: She's a strong woman.
Speaker 8: I can see why Ikari wants to keep her next to him.
Speaker 8: However, were you aware that the one who sent you here
Speaker 11: was none other
Speaker 8: than Ikari himself?
Speaker 8: He refused our request for the pilot of Unit Zero and has sent you here in her stead, Dr. Akagi.
Speaker 7: He sent me instead of her?
Speaker 7: The way to the truth, which you wanted, was sent by
Speaker 16: 36 other methods.
Speaker 16: But they won't reach you. The only way that is guaranteed is this capsule.
Speaker 16: This is all I have. Now it's completely up to you as to how to use this.
Speaker 16: The passcode is our first memory.
Speaker 16: Goodbye.
Speaker 16: And take care.
Speaker 12: The silence from you no longer hurts as much as it once did.
Speaker 12: Not since you gave me your heart and soul.
Speaker 8: So, has Dr. Akagi's deposition proved acceptable?
Speaker 8: She is not like Fiutsuki.
Speaker 8: It is more beneficial for us to release her.
Speaker 8: The woman has rendered remarkable service to the Eva series.
Speaker 8: Let it continue to be of use for a while.
Speaker 9: For the future of mankind.
Speaker 8: As for the Evangelions themselves, there are now eight under
Speaker 9: construction.
Speaker 8: And four that are not.
Speaker 8: The disappearance of Tokyo 3 will prove to be a boon to the project.
Speaker 8: We must accelerate the completion of that day.
Speaker 8: The promised time will be at hand.
Speaker 4: Hello?
Speaker 4: Listen
Speaker 7: to me carefully. For the next few minutes, you'll be free from the Secret Service.
Speaker 7: Come here now while you can.
Speaker 4: Rizko?
Speaker 3: Sorry, it won't work without my password.
Speaker 7: I see. Did Kaji arrange this?
Speaker 12: Show them to me. All the secrets you buried here.
Speaker 7: All right, but this one will see them as well.
Speaker 7: Agreed.
Speaker 14: This looks just like Rey's room.
Speaker 7: That's not surprising. This is the place where Rei was born.
Speaker 14: She was what?
Speaker 7: She was born here.
Speaker 7: The visions of light and water that stream through her consciousness are merely reflections of this place.
Speaker 12: Dr. Akagi, this isn't what I came to see.
Speaker 7: I
Speaker 12: know that,
Speaker 7: Misato.
Speaker 7: Is that... on Ava?
Speaker 7: The first one. A failure. We abandoned it ten years ago.
Speaker 4: A graveyard for Avis?
Speaker 7: Nothing that elaborate. Just a dumping ground.
Speaker 7: It's also the place where your mother was taken from you.
Speaker 7: You may not remember it, but you were watching at the very moment when your mother disappeared.
Speaker 7: Do you remember that, Shinji?
Speaker 7: Doctor!
Speaker 12: So, this is the core of a dummy plug?
Speaker 12: This is
Speaker 7: where we produce the
Speaker 14: components.
Oh my god, it's Rey.
Speaker 7: They're all Rey? You mean the dummy plugs are?
Speaker 7: Uh-huh. These are the cores of the dummy plugs.
Speaker 7: They're what makes the system work.
Speaker 7: Who are they?
Speaker 7: These? These are empty vessels.
Speaker 7: Nothing but spare parts. Spare rays.
Speaker 7: Mankind found a god and man.
Speaker 7: in his folly, tried to make the god his toy.
Speaker 7: For that arrogance, mankind was punished.
Speaker 7: That happened 15 years ago,
Speaker 7: and the god that man found was lost.
Speaker 7: But man continues to attempt to resurrect the god,
Speaker 7: and from that god, Adam,
Speaker 7: man attempted to make a man who was like a god himself,
Speaker 7: and that was Ava.
Speaker 7: What? Avas are human?
Speaker 7: Yes.
Speaker 7: Yes. Inside the empty shell of each Eva is a human soul.
Speaker 7: But the only vessel which can hold a soul is Rey.
Speaker 7: These things are empty husks.
Speaker 7: They have no souls, no right to live.
Speaker 7: The room of Gav is empty.
Speaker 10: Stop this! Do you have any idea what you're doing?
Speaker 7: Yes, I know.
Speaker 7: I'm destroying them.
Speaker 13: These aren't human, just things with human forms
Speaker 13: But even so, I lost to these things
Speaker 13: To these soulless dolls
Speaker 13: I
couldn't win
Speaker 13: I could have suffered any humiliation
Speaker 13: Endured any torture
Speaker 13: But he had already chosen
Speaker 13: God, I'm a fool
Speaker 13: Like mother, like daughter
Speaker 13: Fools to the end
Speaker 13: If you want to kill me, go ahead and do it
Speaker 13: I'd welcome death
Speaker 7: If that's what you want,
Speaker 10: you are a fool.
Speaker 10: What is this curse
Speaker 12: that consumes all those who come into contact with Ava?
Speaker 12: *crying
*
Speaker 10: Fly me to the moon and let me play among the stars
Speaker 10: Let me see where spring is like on Jupiter and us
Speaker 10: In other worlds, hold my hand
Speaker 10: In other words, duly kiss me
Speaker 10: Fill my heart with song
Speaker 10: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 10: You are all I love for
Speaker 10: All I love, sip and adore
Speaker 10: In other words, please
Speaker 10: Let's be true in other worlds.
I love you.
Speaker 12: The city that he had been protecting has disappeared.
Speaker 12: The friends that he was close to have gone.
Speaker 12: The girls that he had been drawn to have been consumed by fear.
Speaker 12: All of Shinji's emotional supports are gone.
Speaker 12: But now a new friend smiles upon him in the twilight.
Speaker 12: Shinji gives himself over to that smile,
Speaker 12: and it's as if all the sins that he has ever committed are gone.
Speaker 12: But fate has yet another cruel trick in store.
Speaker 12: Next episode, The Final Messenger.
you