Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I can only see you, but I'm smiling.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to touch my heart.
Speaker 1: I'm still in awe of the pain.
Speaker 1: But I'll see you soon.
Speaker 1: There is a way to see the future.
Speaker 1: The world is a great place.
Speaker 1: If you're a hot dog,
Speaker 1: you'll be afraid of your thoughts.
Speaker 1: You'll be shining in the sky,
Speaker 1: a man, you'll be a fairy tale.
Speaker 2: Mama! Mama, they chose me! I'm an elite pilot now! I'm the best in the whole world now!
Speaker 2: I must keep this a secret, but I'll only tell you, Mama!
Speaker 2: Everybody's so nice to me now, I don't feel lonely anymore!
Speaker 2: I'm okay now, even without Papa!
Speaker 2: Look at me! Look at me, Mama!
Speaker 3: *Screams*
Speaker 3: No reason left to live.
Speaker 3: Nobody cares about me anymore.
Speaker 3: My father, my mother, nobody cares.
Speaker 3: I have no reason left to live.
Speaker 4: Are you Oscar Langley,
Speaker 5: so are you.
Speaker 5: Intelligence Division 2 just took the second child into protective custody.
Speaker 6: Right.
Speaker 6: It isn't like them to lose her in the first place.
Speaker 6: And then it takes seven days to find her.
Speaker 5: They must have done it on purpose.
Speaker 5: They're trying to make trouble for us, aren't they, Major?
Speaker 6: Could be.
Speaker 6: And the fifth child arrives to replace Asuka today.
Speaker 6: This whole thing is just too convenient.
Speaker 7: Rei Ayanami.
Speaker 7: There's a feeling about her, almost as if my mother--
Speaker 7: Ray and my mother...
Speaker 7: What are you doing with them, father?
Speaker 8: Hello, Commander.
Speaker 8: Did you know my cat died?
Speaker 8: The cat my grandmother was taking care of?
Speaker 8: I hadn't seen it for a long time, but now I know that I'll never see it again.
Speaker 4: Why did you destroy the dummy system?
Speaker 8: It wasn't the dummy system that I destroyed.
Speaker 8: It was Ray!
Speaker 4: I'll ask you once more, why did you do it?
Speaker 8: I'm not happy anymore.
Speaker 8: Not even when you make love to me.
Speaker 9: Do whatever you want with me!
Speaker 9: It's never stopped you before!
Speaker 4: You disappoint me.
Speaker 9: You had no hopes or expectations of me to start with!
Speaker 9: I was nothing!
Speaker 8: What can I do now?
Speaker 8: What, Mother?
Speaker 7: Where have you disappeared to, Asuka?
Speaker 7: But what can I even talk to her about?
Speaker 7: Could I talk about Ayanami with her?
Speaker 7: All of my friends, Toji, Kinsuke,
Speaker 7: all of their homes have been destroyed and now they've left.
Speaker 7: Friends.
Speaker 7: I don't have anybody left. I could call my friend.
Speaker 7: and...
Speaker 7: nobody.
Speaker 7: I can't go see Ayanami again.
Speaker 7: I don't have courage to face her.
Speaker 7: I don't even know how to talk or act around her now.
Speaker 7: Asuka.
Speaker 7: Misato.
Speaker 7: Mother.
Speaker 7: What can I do?
Speaker 7: Who?
Speaker 10: This song is good.
Speaker 10: Huh?
Speaker 10: Singing brings joy and revitalization to the human soul.
Speaker 10: I think that song is the highest achievement of the Lilam culture.
Speaker 10: Don't you agree, Shinji Ikari?
Speaker 10: How do you know my name?
Speaker 10: Everyone knows your name.
Speaker 10: I don't mean to sound rude, but you're rather ignorant of your own position.
Speaker 7: Oh, really?
Speaker 10: Who are you?
Speaker 10: I'm Kaoru. Kaoru Nagisa. I am like you. One of the selected children. The fifth child.
Speaker 7: You're the fifth child? Um, Mr. Nagisa...
Speaker 7: Call me Kaoru,
Speaker 10: Mr.
Speaker 5: Ikari.
Speaker 7: Mr. Ikari? Oh no, you can call me Shinji.
Speaker 5: The fifth child has just arrived.
Speaker 6: Kaoru Nagisa, Kaoru of the seashore.
Speaker 6: And all of his past records have been erased, just like Rei.
Speaker 5: But at least one record remains. He was born on the same day Second Impact occurred.
Speaker 6: The committee sent him directly to us. There must be something else.
Speaker 5: The Marduk report's file on the fifth child was classified.
Speaker 5: So I hacked into the intelligence department's computer system.
Speaker 6: I can't believe you did that.
Speaker 5: Oh, it was worth doing.
Speaker 5: I found out where Ritsuko is.
Speaker 5: So what do you want to do about the fifth child's sync tests?
Speaker 6: I don't have any tricks up my sleeve this time.
Speaker 6: Let's see what he can do.
Speaker 11: Take it down 0.3 more.
Speaker 6: Yes, sir.
Speaker 11: Are these data readouts correct?
Speaker 11: All of the test systems are operating correctly, sir.
Speaker 9: The Magi confirmed that there are no data errors.
Speaker 11: It's incredible that he can synchronize with Unit 2 even before we've reconfigured the core.
Speaker 11: He's amazing.
Speaker 6: But this isn't possible, sir.
Speaker 6: Nevertheless, it's happening.
Speaker 6: We must accept that fact and start an investigation into why it is so.
Speaker 10: You must be the first child, am I correct?
Speaker 10: You are Rei Ayanami.
Speaker 10: And you are the same as I am.
Speaker 10: How interesting that both of us have ended up in the same form as the Lilim for life on this planet.
Speaker 6: Identify yourself.
Speaker 11: The fifth child has made contact with Rey.
Speaker 11: I see.
Speaker 11: The Magi are currently analyzing the nature of the fifth and what his powers may be.
Speaker 6: And we still don't know who or what he is.
Speaker 6: Who in the hell is this boy?
Speaker 6: Shinji hasn't come back yet either.
Speaker 6: I guess I'm not deserving of his trust.
Speaker 10: Central Dogma is now open.
Speaker 10: Mays use route.
Speaker 10: We are the transfer.
Speaker 10: Hello.
Speaker 10: You weren't waiting here for me, were you?
Speaker 7: No.
Speaker 7: Well, not really waiting anyway.
Speaker 10: So what are you doing for the rest of the day?
Speaker 7: Well, usually when tests are over, I'll just take a shower and go home.
Speaker 7: But I don't really want to go home these days.
Speaker 10: The fact that you have a place where you can return, home will lead you to happiness.
Speaker 10: That is a good fact.
Speaker 10: You think so?
Speaker 10: I want to talk to you some more.
Speaker 10: May I come with you?
Speaker 10: To the shower, I mean.
Speaker 10: Aren't you going to the shower?
Speaker 7: Yeah.
Speaker 10: Or do you mean no?
Speaker 7: No, I don't mean no.
Speaker 10: You are extremely afraid of any kind of initial contact, aren't you?
Speaker 10: Are you that afraid of other people?
Speaker 10: I know that by keeping others at a distance, you avoid a betrayal of your trust.
Speaker 10: For while you may not be hurt that way, you mustn't forget that you must endure the loneliness.
Speaker 10: Men cannot erase this sadness, because all men are fundamentally alone.
Speaker 7: It's time.
Speaker 10: Time to go?
Speaker 7: Yeah. I have to go to bed.
Speaker 10: With me?
Speaker 7: No, I think you have your own room that they gave you, I mean.
Speaker 10: Okay.
Speaker 10: You know, pain is something that man must endure in his heart.
Speaker 10: And since the heart feels pain so easily, some believe life is pain.
Speaker 10: You are delicate like glass, especially your heart.
Speaker 10: I am?
Speaker 10: Yes, and worth
Speaker 7: earning my empathy.
Speaker 7: Empathy?
Speaker 10: I'm saying I love you.
Speaker 12: The Nerve organization was established to execute the wishes of Sele.
Speaker 12: It was intended to enact the scenario we had created.
Speaker 12: However, it appears to have become dominated by a single zealous individual.
Speaker 1: Yes,
Speaker 12: it has. We must take it back into our own dominion.
Speaker 12: It is time.
Speaker 12: We must restore Nerve and the Ava series to their proper role.
Speaker 12: Ikari, you will take responsibility for betraying Sele.
Speaker 4: I'm afraid there's not much time left for accomplishing our goal.
Speaker 4: However, the Lance of Longinus, which would have impeded the realization of our plan, is now gone forever.
Speaker 4: The last Angel shall soon appear, and with its destruction, our wishes may be born.
Speaker 4: Soon, Yui, please have patience.
Speaker 1: Why am I here?
Speaker 1: Why am I still alive?
Speaker 3: For what purpose?
Speaker 3: For whose purpose?
Speaker 3: The fifth child.
Why?
Speaker 3: In what way
Speaker 6: are he and I alike?
Speaker 6: Thank God this apartment block is on the outskirts of town.
Speaker 6: It's a miracle that it and you survived.
Speaker 6: But I can't guarantee your safety any longer.
Speaker 6: So the Haraki family will be taking care of you.
Speaker 6: From now
Speaker 13: on...
Speaker 6: I may not see you for a while, Pen-Pen.
Speaker 10: I think I should sleep on the floor.
Speaker 10: No,
Speaker 7: I'm staying at your place. I'm fine. I'll be okay on the floor.
Speaker 10: What did you want to say to me?
Speaker 10: What?
Speaker 10: You wanted to tell me something, didn't you?
Speaker 10: So much has
Speaker 7: happened since I came.
Speaker 7: Before this, I lived with my teacher.
Speaker 7: It was calm and boring in those days.
Speaker 7: I wasn't really doing anything.
Speaker 7: But I was fine with that.
Speaker 7: There was really nothing that I had to do.
Speaker 10: Did you hate dealing with people?
Speaker 7: More or less.
Speaker 7: But I didn't really care as much.
Speaker 7: However, I really hated my father.
Speaker 7: Why am I telling all of this to Kaoru?
Speaker 10: I think I may have been born just to meet you, Shinji Ikari.
Speaker 10: Humans cannot create from nothingness.
Speaker 10: Humans cannot accomplish anything without holding on to something.
Speaker 10: Humans are not gods.
Speaker 12: But there is one man who is trying to obtain the power of god.
Speaker 12: There is a man
Speaker 1: who
Speaker 12: is not one of us, who seeks to reopen Pandora's box.
Speaker 12: There is a man attempting to close the
Speaker 10: box before the hope at the bottom appears.
Speaker 10: The hope. You're saying this is the Lilim's hope?
Speaker 12: Hope exists in as many forms as there are people.
Speaker 12: For the human heart is the only place where hope exists.
Speaker 12: However, our hope is becoming substantiated.
Speaker 12: That is Lilith, the progenitor of mankind, the false successors from the Black Moon.
Speaker 12: And also Adam, progenitor of the Angels, who are the true successors from the Lost White Moon.
Speaker 12: His salvaged soul exists only within you.
Speaker 12: Yet his resurrected body exists within Ikari.
Speaker 12: Shinji's
Speaker 10: father.
Speaker 12: So he also is the same as me.
Speaker 12: That is so. And that is why we entrust you with our wish.
Speaker 10: All of this I know. Is that not why I am here after all?
Speaker 10: It's no good.
Speaker 6: I can't read his lips from all the way up here.
Speaker 6: But going out at the crack of dawn just to talk to himself is pretty suspicious.
Speaker 6: He noticed me? That's impossible.
Speaker 10: All will be as the
Speaker 5: Lilum directed.
Speaker 6: Well, did you get the data on him?
Speaker 5: Yeah, this is it.
Speaker 5: I sort of borrowed it from Lieutenant Ibuki without asking.
Speaker 5: I'm
Speaker 6: sorry that I made you do something like that.
Speaker 6: What is this?
Speaker 6: Yeah,
Speaker 5: it's no wonder that Maya can't talk about this.
Speaker 5: It's not even theoretically possible.
Speaker 6: Yeah, it's getting more and more mysterious.
Speaker 6: How can he set his sync ratio at any level he chooses?
Speaker 6: I guess it's time to go Maverick again.
Speaker 6: It's you again.
Speaker 8: How surprising.
Speaker 6: I have a question for you.
Speaker 8: Our conversation is being monitored, you know.
Speaker 8: I don't care. The fifth child, what is he?
Speaker 8: He is probably the last angel.
Speaker 10: It is time. Let us go, Adam Stark's shadow, servant of the Lilum.
Speaker 14: Ava Unit 2 just activated!
Speaker 14: That's impossible!
Speaker 14: Where's Asuka?
Speaker 14: She's in room 303!
Speaker 14: I've confirmed it!
Speaker 14: Who the hell is piloting it?
Speaker 14: It's unmanned!
Speaker 14: The entry plug hasn't even been
Speaker 9: inserted into Unit 2!
Speaker 6: Unmanned?
Speaker 14: Then the fifth child isn't there?
Speaker 14: AT field detected in Central Dogma!
Speaker 14: Ava 2?
Speaker 14: No, the blood pattern is blue!
Speaker 14: It's definitely an angel!
Speaker 14: It's an angel?
Speaker 14: No! That means that Ritz goes.
Speaker 14: The target has passed through the fourth defensive layer and is still descending.
Speaker 14: It's no good! We can't cut the power to the linear carriage!
Speaker 11: Evacuate the area! Seal all shatters and bulkheads surrounding Central Dogma.
Speaker 11: We've got to buy ourselves some more time.
Speaker 15: Closing all bulkheads
Speaker 4: immediately! All personnel
Speaker 5: and athletes! All personnel and athletes!
Speaker 5: God have mercy. Saleh has sent an angel to us.
Speaker 5: The
Speaker 4: old man wants to advance his schedule using us as his tools.
Speaker 12: Humans forget their foolishness and repeat their mistakes.
Speaker 12: If humans do not redeem themselves willingly, they will not change.
Speaker 12: We must not rely on Adam or the angels.
Speaker 13: We have no
Speaker 12: choice but to make changes with our own hands.
Speaker 12: I pray that Unit 1 will accomplish its task.
Speaker 14: Unit 2 has penetrated the armored shutters!
Speaker 14: Target has penetrated the second barrier, sir!
Speaker 4: Send unit one in to pursue it.
Speaker 14: Yes, sir.
Speaker 4: Under all circumstances, the last angel must be kept from entering Terminal Dogma.
Speaker 6: But why did the angel take unit two?
Speaker 4: You don't think it's going to attempt to fuse with unit two, do you?
Speaker 4: Or will it try to bring about our total destruction?
Speaker 6: No! No! No!
Speaker 9: It's not possible!
Speaker 9: I won't believe that
Speaker 10: Kauru's an angel! It's a lie!
Speaker 6: It's a fact, Shinji. You must accept it.
Speaker 6: Prepare for combat, do you understand?
Speaker 10: Shinji, you are late.
Speaker 14: Any Unit 1 descending via access route 2.
Speaker 14: It's about to make contact with the target.
Speaker 14: You betrayed me! You betrayed the trust I placed in you!
Speaker 15: You betrayed me just like my father did!
Speaker 15: Unit 1 has reached the fourth layer. It's about to confront the target.
Speaker 15: There he is!
Speaker 10: I've been waiting for you, Shinji.
Speaker 15: GAURU!
Speaker 10: Asuka,
Speaker 7: I'm sorry.
Speaker 10: The Ava series was born from Adam, born from man's antithesis.
Speaker 10: And yet the Lilum will utilize that which they hate most in order to survive.
Speaker 10: I do not understand.
Speaker 15: Skaru, stop! Why is this happening?
Speaker 10: Your Avas and I are composed of the same matter, born from Adam.
Speaker 10: I can synchronize with it easily as long as there is no dominant soul.
Speaker 10: Unit 2's soul is now hiding itself. Thus, Ava 2 is mine.
Speaker 10: No!
Speaker 7: You've got your own AT field?
Speaker 10: Yes. At least that is what Yulilam called this thing.
Speaker 10: This is the light of my soul. A sacred territory in which no one may intrude.
Speaker 10: Aren't Yulilam even aware that your AT field is merely that wall that encloses every mind that exists?
Speaker 15: I don't understand what you're talking about!
Speaker 15: Both
Speaker 10: Avas have penetrated all
Speaker 6: the way down
Speaker 14: to the final layer!
Speaker 14: 20 seconds until
Speaker 6: the target reaches track.
Speaker 6: If Unit 1's signals cut off or disappears, or if any other change should occur for the worse.
Speaker 5: I know. I'll initiate the self-destruct for this entire facility.
Speaker 5: It's better than letting third impact take place.
Speaker 6: I'm sorry.
Speaker 5: It's all right. Dying beside you wouldn't be a bad way to go out.
Speaker 6: Thank you.
Speaker 10: This is mankind's fate.
Speaker 10: The thread of human hope is spun with the flecks of sorrow.
Speaker 14: What the hell is that?
Speaker 14: It's
Speaker 13: another AT
Speaker 14: field, the strongest we've ever detected!
Speaker 14: It's shutting
Speaker 13: out everything!
Speaker 14: Light, magnetism, subatomic particles!
Speaker 9: It's blocking everything out? I can't sense anything!
Speaker 9: The targets, Unit 2, Unit 1, they're all gone!
Speaker 9: We've lost communication with the pilot!
*Bang*
Speaker 5: They've reached it. Heaven's door is opening.
Speaker 6: Then the angel has finally reached its goal.
Speaker 6: Get ready.
Enough!
Speaker 15: What's that?
Speaker 15: What's going on?
Speaker 15: It's another AT field.
Speaker 15: A field as strong as the first one has appeared around Terminal Dogma.
Speaker 15: He's right! It's breaking through the other AT field!
Speaker 15: What is it? Another angel?
Speaker 15: I don't know. I can't confirm it.
Speaker 15: God! It just disappeared!
Speaker 15: Disappeared? The angel?
Speaker 10: Adam, that from which we came.
Speaker 10: Must one who was born from Adam return to Adam, even though it would destroy man?
Speaker 10: But wait, this isn't... Lilith?
Speaker 10: I see. I understand now. The Lilum! Lilith!
Speaker 10: I thank you, friend Shinji. I wanted you to stop Unit 2 and take her from me. Otherwise,
Speaker 10: with her, I might have survived much longer.
Speaker 7: Karu, but why?
Speaker 10: It is my destiny to live forever, though my survival will bring destruction to the human
Speaker 10: race. However, it is possible for me to be killed, and whether I live or die makes no
Speaker 10: great difference. In truth, death may be the only absolute freedom there is.
Speaker 7: What are you? Garu? I don't understand what you are talking about, Garu!
Speaker 10: This is my wish. Please, destroy me. Otherwise, you will be destroyed. Only one life form
Speaker 10: Everyone can be chosen to evade the destruction and seize the future.
Speaker 10: And you are not the existence which should die.
Speaker 10: You need the future. It's what you live for.
Speaker 10: Thank you, Shinji. My life was meaningful because of you.
Amen, amen.
Speaker 7: The End
Speaker 7: I've never felt such kindness before.
Speaker 7: He was like me.
Speaker 7: And he was like Ayanami.
Speaker 7: I liked him too.
Speaker 7: Kauru should have survived.
Speaker 7: He was much better than I am.
Speaker 7: Kauru should have survived, not me.
Speaker 7: He deserved to live.
Speaker 6: No!
Speaker 6: The one who deserves to survive is the one who has the will to make it happen.
Speaker 6: He wished for death.
Speaker 6: He ignored his will to survive and chose to die for a false hope.
Speaker 6: Your survival is not a mistake, Shinji.
Speaker 7: Misato, how can you be so cruel?
Speaker 7: Oh.
Speaker 16: The Last Angel is gone, but Shinji's heart is filled with torment.
Speaker 16: Misato and Asuka find their souls laid bare seeking the help of others as they search for salvation.
Speaker 16: Acceptance becomes a means to an end in the next episode, the Ending World.
Speaker 16: world.