Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
EPISODE 16: SICKNESS UNTO, DEATH, AND...
Please press this button
if you would like to get off
ALERT
State of Emergency Declared:
Closed to General Traffic
Power Source
EXPEDITION
TEAM
RETURNS
SECOND IMPACT'S...
"CRYSTALLIZED DNA" THEORY
PRIDE OF OUR NATION'S DNA FIELD
DARK SIDE OF THE U.N.
UNDISCLOSED ORGANIZATION'S CORRUPT...
U.N. UNDISCLOSED...
THE LIGHT AND SHADOW OF THE
TOKYO UNIVERSITY ACADEMIC CLIQUE
ENTERPRISE AND ADHESION
YEAR 2004
DNA
MANIPULATION
AT THE ARTIFICIAL
EVOLUTION LABORATORY CRITICAL ACCIDENT?
FEAR OF BIOHAZARD
ENGINEERS EATING AWAY
AT GOD'S DOMAIN
FEAR
ONE
DEAD
...TO CONDUCT RESEARCH FOR...
...RESEARCHING IN THE SAME LAB...
...MS. YUI IKARI (27)...
...FELL VICTIM TO IT.
...MISTAKE IN CONTROL.
...MISTAKE!
QUESTIONS OF HUMAN EXPERIMENTATION
MAN-MADE CALAMITY
BIOINFORMATION...
OUT OF CONTROL
ESTABLISHED RISK
FORMER RESEARCH COLLEAGUES CRITICIZED
BRIBERY
DIRECTOR GENDO IKARI
GENOME BIOLOGY
SUPREME COURT RULES NOT GUILTY
THE DEFICIENCY OF BIOETHICS
GOD'S
ART
TO BE CONTINUED
Do you love me?
Hey, you wanna kiss?
Why don't you become one with me?
Who are you?
Loneliness?
Pleasure... Sky of reality... Cruel strangers...
PREVIEW
THE FOURTH QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL