EPISODE 22
AT LEAST, BE HUMAN
INSPECTION
DIVISION
WARNING
What are you, stupid?
DENIAL
FATHER
MOTHER
PRIVATION
INSECURITY
SEPARATION
EVASION
CONTACT
OBSESSIVE-COMPULSIVE
ATTACHMENT BEHAVIOR
DEPENDENCE
EMPTINESS
PSYCHOLOGICAL BREAKDOWN
SYMPATHY
PITY
I AM NOT A DOLL
MENTAL CONTAMINATION
DON'T VIOLATE ME!
STOP IT!
DIE WITH ME
NO!!
IT HURTS!
I HATE YOU SO MUCH!
PRESUMPTION
DORMANT
MASCULINE PROTEST
CLEARLY PRESENT
REACTIVE FORMATION
SHADOW
OPPOSITION
REPARATIONS
MOMENTARY ASSIMILATION
RATIONALIZATION
OBLIVION
DECEPTION
REASON FOR EXISTING
CONFIDENCE
CHILDHOOD EXPERIENCES
SENSE OF LOSS
REPARATIONS
COEXISTENCE
HOSTILITY
OPPRESSION
DEATH
DO NOT ENTER
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
TEARS