Speaker 1: The young man like a bad guy
Speaker 1: You're a young man, you're a fairy tale
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now on the door
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at you, I'm
Speaker 1: The way to the future is to be a place for the future
Speaker 1: A sad thing that is being made by the end of the world
Speaker 1: From the window to the end of the world
Speaker 1: A hot-past-taste of the day and the day of the world
Speaker 1: I will be afraid of the world
Speaker 1: This world will shine
Speaker 1: You are a man, you are a fairy tale
*Sigh*
Speaker 2: Is that you dead?
Speaker 3: *Sounds of
Speaker 3: - Yeah, she's got a tough job.
Speaker 3: Well then, I guess we've gotta be quiet
Speaker 3: so that we don't wake Masato up, right?
Speaker 3: - Well... - Shh!
Speaker 4: - Hey!
Speaker 5: -
Speaker 5: - What
Speaker 4: the heck are these creeps doing in
Speaker 5: here?
Speaker 5: - Shh! - Drying themselves?
Speaker 4: - Oh, sure. Talk about lame excuses!
Speaker 4: Well, I'm changing in here, and if you peep, you're dead!
Speaker 3: - You stuck-up, beacotistical little dude wanna watch a snake
Speaker 3: changing its skin anyway!
Speaker 3: - She's sure full of herself.
Speaker 3: - Miss Sato, did we wake you up?
Speaker 2: - Actually, I was already awake.
Speaker 2: Thanks for asking though.
Speaker 2: Shinji, don't forget that we're having a harmonics test
Speaker 2: at the lab this evening.
Speaker 2: - Right. - Hey Asuka, did you hear that?
Speaker 2: - Yes ma'am.
Speaker 3: - Huh?
Speaker 3: Wow! I mean, congratulations on your promotion, Miss Sato.
Speaker 3: - Yeah, congratulations.
Speaker 2: - You're too kind.
Speaker 3: - No ma'am, you deserved it.
Speaker 2: - Well, I'll see you guys later.
Speaker 2: - I'll see you later. - I'll see you later.
Speaker 5: - Have fun! See ya!
Speaker 5: - So what's up? Did something happen to Misato?
Speaker 3: - Haven't you seen her new badge?
Speaker 3: It's got two stripes on it now.
Speaker 3: Two stripes means that she's been promoted to major.
Speaker 4: - Promoted? I didn't notice.
Speaker 3: - Yeah, me neither.
Speaker 3: - Neither of you noticed? What a bunch of lame-os.
Speaker 6: - Man,
Speaker 3: don't you guys ever pay attention
Speaker 3: to that poor, hard-working woman.
Speaker 3: Do you have any idea of how hard it must be
Speaker 3: to take care of the two of you at her age?
Speaker 3: - I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
Speaker 3: I guess it's a good thing that some of us still have a little human compassion.
Speaker 7: Units 0 and 2 are both on the edge of the contamination zone. They've reached their limit.
Speaker 7: Unit 1 can still tolerate a little more though, can't he? Lower the graph depth another 0.3.
Speaker 7: He's almost reached the contamination zone.
Speaker 7: And he's still getting these readings?
Speaker 7: He's just wonderful.
Speaker 7: His harmonics and sync ratio are rapidly catching up with Asuka's.
Speaker 7: He does have talent, doesn't he?
Speaker 7: It's as if he was born to become a Nava pilot, isn't it?
Speaker 2: But that's not what Shinji wants.
Speaker 2: I know he's not really happy here.
Speaker 7: The test has been completed.
Speaker 7: That was excellent work, Shinji.
Speaker 7: What do you mean?
Speaker 7: Your harmonics value has increased by
Speaker 4: 8 points since the last test.
Speaker 4: That's very good.
Speaker 4: But it's still 50 points below mine.
Speaker 4: That's true, but 8 points in 10 days is amazing.
Speaker 4: I don't think it's so great!
Speaker 4: Okay, third child, enjoy your victory while you can.
Speaker 4: I'll see you when you get home, jerkface.
Speaker 4: And here's
the missing from Mr. Wild!
Oh, by the way, it's nice that you got promoted.
Speaker 5: Thanks, Shinji.
Speaker 5: But to tell you the truth, I'm not really all that thrilled with it.
Speaker 5: Oh, I understand.
Speaker 5: I'm not crazy about getting praised in public either,
Speaker 5: especially when it's like earlier today.
Speaker 5: All it did was make Asuka angry.
Speaker 5: Why does she get so pissed off?
Speaker 5: It's so stupid.
Speaker 2: It bothers you, doesn't it?
Speaker 2: It does.
Speaker 2: Well, that's because you think too much about what others think of you.
Speaker 5: Congratulations!
Speaker 3: Way
Speaker 2: to go, Misato!
Speaker 2: Thanks, you guys.
Speaker 2: And thank you, Toji.
Speaker 3: No, no, this was Kensuke's idea.
Speaker 3: That's right! I, Kensuke Ida, am the mastermind behind this dinner.
Speaker 3: Oh, well then thank you, Mr. Ida.
Speaker 3: Oh, it was no problem. It wasn't such a big deal, really.
Speaker 3: Hey, by the way, just what is Hikari doing here?
Speaker 4: I invited her, Doomkopf!
Speaker 4: YAAA!
Speaker 4: Did you invite Rei too?
Speaker 4: Well, I invited her, but she's not exactly the party type, you know?
Speaker 4: Darn, why is Kaji so late?
Speaker 4: Kaji? You mean that really cool looking guy who never shaves?
Speaker 4: Yeah, after hanging around these dorks all day, it's nice to know what a real man is like.
Speaker 4: So kiddo, is it still difficult for you to
Speaker 5: be in this kind of situation?
Speaker 5: I'm okay. I'm just not used to being around so many people.
Speaker 3: Oh, you get out of here. What do you think you're doing?
Speaker 5: Why do they have to be so nosy?
Why don't you just go home?
Just go back where you came. Where'd you come from, Mars?
Speaker 5: Your promotion.
Speaker 5: That means that someone must appreciate the kind of work you've been doing, right?
Speaker 5: Yeah, I suppose so.
Speaker 5: That's why they're all so happy for you.
Speaker 2: But you don't look very happy at all.
Speaker 2: Oh, I'm happy. But that's not the reason I do what I do.
Speaker 5: So why did you join Nerve?
Speaker 2: Oh, I don't know. It's been a long time since I signed up,
Speaker 8: you know.
Speaker 4: Why don't you just get the hell out of here before I do it?
Speaker 4: And I'll shove you with a second
Speaker 8: line.
Speaker 4: That's gotta be Kaji!
Speaker 8: I came directly from headquarters. We just happened to meet on the way.
Speaker 7: A likely story.
Speaker 7: You're not jealous, are you?
Speaker 7: Hm, absolutely not.
Speaker 8: I'd like to give you my sincerest regards, Major Katsuragi.
Speaker 8: I suppose I'll have to be polite to you from now on.
Speaker 2: Hm, and just what does that mean?
Speaker 2: Well,
Speaker 8: you know that Commanders Ikari and Fiyutsuki have never left Japan at the same time before.
Speaker 8: I guess they must really feel old Katsuragi here's dependable.
Speaker 7: My father's left Japan again?
Speaker 7: That's right, Shinji. He's at the South Pole.
Speaker 9: Once this was a living continent of Antarctica.
Speaker 9: Now it's an ocean of death.
Speaker 9: The Pole, not just another name for Hell.
Speaker 10: Nevertheless, mankind has returned to this wasteland.
Speaker 10: In the midst of death, we still
Speaker 1: live.
Speaker 10: That's because we're under
Speaker 9: the protection of science.
Speaker 9: Science is what makes man powerful.
Speaker 9: That kind of self-righteous arrogance
Speaker 9: is what caused the tragedy of 15 years ago, the second impact.
Speaker 9: And here, before us, is the end result.
Speaker 9: This is a far greater punishment than mankind deserved.
Speaker 9: This is the real Dead Sea.
Speaker 11: Yet this is a world that has been purified and purged of the original sin.
Speaker 11: I'd rather live in a world with people, no matter how stained this is.
Speaker 3: This is the bridge. We've just received a telex from Nerve Headquarters.
Speaker 3: An angel has been
Speaker 12: detected in orbit
Speaker 8: above the
Speaker 12: Indian Ocean.
Speaker 8: The angel appeared about two minutes ago.
Speaker 12: Send recon satellite number six to that orbit.
Speaker 8: T-minus two minutes to contact.
Speaker 8: The target has been sighted.
Speaker 2: It's enormous!
Speaker 2: It's impressive, all right.
Speaker 3: Recon 6 is now in range.
Speaker 12: Commencing data search.
Speaker 12: Commencing data transmission.
Speaker 12: Data transmission complete.
Speaker 2: Was that
Speaker 7: an AT field?
Speaker 7: Yes, a new way of using one.
Speaker 2: Look at the size of that tidal wave.
Speaker 2: That's an AT field impact.
Speaker 2: It uses
Speaker 7: kinetic energy, too.
Speaker 7: This angel is like a huge living bomb.
Speaker 7: At least the first blast missed and hit the ocean.
Speaker 7: However, the second shot hit closer to land,
Speaker 7: and for the last two hours it's been steadily correcting its error ratio.
Speaker 7: So it's learning to aim itself.
Speaker 2: We detonated
Speaker 8: an N2 aerial mine on it.
Speaker 8: No effect.
Speaker 8: The angel has been hiding since then.
Speaker 7: It's coming here, isn't it?
Speaker 7: It's a safe bet.
Speaker 7: And if it falls on us...
Speaker 7: Then there'll be a third Ashinoka Lake, right?
Speaker 7: Actually, this whole area will become an extension of the Pacific Ocean.
Speaker 7: Can we contact Commander Ikari?
Speaker 11: It's impossible. We can't get through the Angels' jamming.
Speaker 2: What about the Magi?
Speaker 2: The Magi are unanimous in recommending evacuation.
Speaker 2: What will you do?
Speaker 7: You're the one who's in charge of all this now.
Speaker 2: Notify all the ministries concerned that I am issuing a special D-17 declaration.
Speaker 2: All residents within a radius of 50 kilometers are to evacuate immediately.
Speaker 2: Also, tell Matsushiro to back up the Magi.
Speaker 8: Are we going to evacuate as well?
Speaker 2: No, but it's not necessary to place everyone here at risk.
Speaker 2: Your attention, please. The government has announced a D-17 special declaration of emergency for this area.
Speaker 2: All residents must evacuate to their designated locations.
Speaker 12: Beginning with the blocks 6 and 7, evacuate according to the directions of your district chief immediately.
Speaker 8: The evacuation of the city is now complete.
Speaker 12: The evacuation of all non-combatant and D-class personnel by Alarm C has been completed.
Speaker 7: You're not really serious, are you?
Speaker 7: Yes, I am.
Speaker 7: You're willing to sacrifice all three Avas to satisfy your own ambitions?
Speaker 7: The chance of success is 0.001%.
Speaker 7: Just one in 10,000.
Speaker 2: Well, it's not zero. I just trust the Avas.
Speaker 2: Major Katsuragi, don't forget that I'm the one in charge now.
Speaker 2: I have to do what I have
Speaker 7: to do.
Speaker 7: Destroying the Angels is my duty.
Speaker 7: Your duty? You must be kidding.
Speaker 7: This is to satisfy yourself, isn't it?
Speaker 7: This is just your revenge against the Angels.
Speaker 4: What? You want us to catch it with our hands?
Speaker 2: That's right.
Speaker 2: We'll locate the Avas in the estimated drop zone.
Speaker 2: Then, while maintaining your AT fields, you'll catch it before it hits the ground.
Speaker 2: But what if it doesn't fall where you think it will?
Speaker 2: Then there'll be a little boom.
Speaker 2: But what if the Avas can't handle the impact?
Speaker 2: We'll all be blown to the moon.
Speaker 2: What are our chances?
Speaker 2: I've got no idea.
Speaker 2: Not so good, in my opinion.
Speaker 2: If we pull this off, it'll be a miracle.
Speaker 2: Miracles aren't something that just happen.
Speaker 2: They're something that people make happen.
Speaker 2: We've got to be willing to sacrifice ourselves.
Speaker 2: I'm sorry, Aska. We've got no other choice. This is the best plan.
Speaker 2: How can you call something this crazy a plan?
Speaker 2: I suppose I can't, really. You can refuse to do it if you wish.
Speaker 2: I see. So you are okay with this?
Speaker 2: The regulations state here that you're all supposed to write out a will. Have you done that yet?
Speaker 2: I don't need to write one. I'm not going to die just yet.
Speaker 2: Neither do I. There's no point to it.
Speaker 2: Yeah, me neither.
Speaker 2: Okay, but when all of this is over, I'll treat all of you to a steak dinner, okay?
Speaker 2: A steak dinner?
Speaker 2: Yep.
Speaker 2: Wow.
Speaker 2: You won't forget, right?
Speaker 2: I swear I won't.
Speaker 5: A steak dinner is supposed to impress us?
Speaker 4: Does she really think we'd go crazy just for a dumb steak dinner?
Speaker 4: Man, the second impact generation has really got some cheap standards.
Speaker 5: I suppose she just
Speaker 4: can't help it.
Speaker 4: Well, that "wow" you made sounded pretty enthusiastic to me, Shinji.
Speaker 5: Well, it may not mean much to us, but it still means something to her, you know?
Speaker 4: I suppose so. Well, let's figure out where she's going to take us.
Speaker 4: Tokyo 3 5-star restaurant directory.
Speaker 4: You're gonna be coming with us, right, First Child?
Speaker 4: I don't think so.
Speaker 4: Why not?
Speaker 4: I dislike eating
Speaker 2: meat.
Speaker 4: Angel's ECM jamming has caused us to
Speaker 2: lose track of it again.
Speaker 2: Since it's impossible to calculate the exact location,
Speaker 2: the Magi have estimated a probable drop zone radius from what little data we could collect.
Speaker 2: This is it.
Speaker 2: That's a huge area to cover!
Speaker 7: It could drop on any of these locations?
Speaker 7: Given the size of the target's AT field,
Speaker 7: it could completely annihilate Nerve Headquarters simply by coming close with a near miss.
Speaker 7: So, we'll disperse the Avis so there's one at each of these three points.
Speaker 7: What is this
Speaker 2: dispersal based on?
Speaker 7: A guess.
Speaker 6: A guess?
Speaker 4: It's women's intuition!
Speaker 4: Her woman's intuition looks like our miracle is getting further and further away.
Speaker 5: She plays the lottery a lot, and she never wins either.
Speaker 5: Ew.
Speaker 4: Hey, Asuka.
Speaker 4: What?
Speaker 4: Why did you become an Eva pilot?
Speaker 4: To show the world how great I am, of course.
Speaker 4: So it's a way of proving that you exist?
Speaker 4: Yeah, I guess you could say that.
Speaker 4: Why don't you ask Wonder Girl?
Speaker 4: I've already talked
Speaker 5: with her about it.
Speaker 4: Hmm. So you've been having secret meetings.
Speaker 5: No, it's not like that.
Speaker 4: So why do you do this?
Speaker 5: I don't know.
Speaker 4: Just what do you mean? Are you
Speaker 5: stupid?
Speaker 4: Maybe I am.
Speaker 12: Huh.
Speaker 12: I suppose you really are.
Speaker 12: 20 minutes to estimated time of impact.
Speaker 2: The rest of you can leave now. I can take care of this situation.
Speaker 5: Sorry,
Speaker 8: this is our job as well.
Speaker 8: Yeah, we can't let those kids risk their lives all by themselves.
Speaker 2: Don't worry about the children.
Speaker 2: No matter how badly the Avas might get damaged,
Speaker 2: their AT fields will protect them.
Speaker 2: Actually, the safest place to be right now is inside the Ava.
Speaker 6: The
Speaker 2: other day you wanted to know why I really joined Nerve.
Speaker 2: It began with my father. He lived for his work, to the exclusion of everything else.
Speaker 2: I was never able to forgive him for that. In fact, at times, I even hated him.
Speaker 5: It sounds like my father.
Speaker 2: He never really took care of me or my mother.
Speaker 2: His friends always said that he was too sensitive and fragile, but the truth was, he was just a weak person.
Speaker 2: He didn't want to face reality, so avoiding his family was easier than dealing with it.
Speaker 2: When my mother decided to divorce him, I was actually happy.
Speaker 2: I was so sick of hearing her cry herself to sleep.
Speaker 2: And when my dad got upset about it, I actually laughed at him because I thought he got what he deserved.
Speaker 2: But then he sacrificed himself to save my life during the second impact.
Speaker 2: Then I didn't know whether I hated him or loved him.
Speaker 2: The only thing that was clear to me was that I wanted to destroy the angels who had caused the second impact.
Speaker 2: And that's why I joined Nerve.
Speaker 2: It might be that I still hate him and just want to avenge my father so that I can finally free myself from him.
Speaker 2: It's the only way I can escape.
Speaker 13: I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away.
Speaker 2: I won't.
Speaker 3: I won't run away.
Speaker 3: The target has been sighted. Maximum magnification. Distance, approximately 25,000.
Speaker 3: The
Speaker 2: Falling Angel's
Speaker 3: been sighted. All Avas, get on your marks.
Speaker 14: We can only give you a rough estimated trajectory based upon optical observations.
Speaker 14: The Magi will guide you until the estimated distance is 10,000 meters.
Speaker 14: After that, you'll have to use your own judgment.
Speaker 14: Remember, I'm placing my trust in you.
Speaker 3: The angel is approaching distance 20,000 right
Speaker 2: begin the operation here we go
Speaker 2: Let's move out
Speaker 3: Distance 12,000
Speaker 2: Spreading AT Field!
Speaker 4: Unit two, expand your field!
Speaker 4: I'm already doing it!
Speaker 4: Do it now!
Speaker 6: Exist!
Speaker 6: *Screams*
Speaker 3: Our wireless communications have been restored.
Speaker 3: We're receiving a transmission from Commander Ikari in Antarctica.
Speaker 2: Connect him, please.
Speaker 3: Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 2: I apologize, sir.
Speaker 2: Because of my irresponsible judgment, Unit One has incurred some damage.
Speaker 2: I take full responsibility for this, sir.
Speaker 9: No. Destroying Angels isn't Eva's purpose.
Speaker 9: It was fortunate that the amount of damage done was minimal.
Speaker 10: Excellent work, Major Katsuraki.
Speaker 2: Thank you, Commander.
Speaker 2: And on that subject,
Speaker 10: is the pilot of Unit 1 there?
Speaker 10: Yes.
Speaker 10: I've just read the report.
Speaker 10: Good work, Shinji.
Speaker 2: Yes,
Speaker 10: sir.
Speaker 10: Now, Major Kasaragi, I'll leave the handling of the rest of this in your hands.
Speaker 2: Yes, sir.
The next station is new Mianoshita.
New Mianushita. The door will open on the left side of the next question.
Speaker 2: So, now you're going to have to fulfill your promise.
Speaker 2: Well, of course I will.
Speaker 2: I went and pulled some large bills for my account so that I could cover everything.
Speaker 2: Of course, now I'm broke.
Speaker 4: A ramen place?
Speaker 4: Well, we know how poor you are, Misato.
Speaker 4: This'll be fine.
Speaker 4: And since there's no meat, Wonder Girl will be joining us.
Speaker 2: One garlic ramen with no roast pork.
Speaker 2: I'll
Speaker 4: have shark spin ramen with roast pork.
Speaker 4: Supersize
Speaker 1: it!
Speaker 4: There you go!
Speaker 5: Say, Misato.
Speaker 5: Yeah?
Speaker 5: I think I finally understood the good part about being praised by someone when I heard my father's words today.
Speaker 5: And I also realized that the reason I pilot my Eva is to hear those words from him.
Speaker 4: Now, wait a second. That's why you're a pilot?
Speaker 4: Jeez, you really are an idiot.
Speaker 4: Hmm.
Speaker 15: In other words, darling kiss me
Speaker 15: Fill my heart with song and let me sing forevermore
Speaker 15: You are all I know for all I worship and adore
Speaker 15: In other words, please be true.
Speaker 15: In other words,
I love you.
Speaker 2: The Magi, the trio of supercomputers that command all of Nerve headquarters, are under attack.
Speaker 2: As problems mount and central dogma is invaded, Nerve is forced to accept a course of self-destruction.
Speaker 2: It all happens in the next episode.
Speaker 2: Angel invasion.