Speaker 1: Like a cruel, cruel,
Speaker 1: You are a young man,
Speaker 1: You are a fairy tale,
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now
Speaker 1: If you're in the
Speaker 1: The back of the back of
Speaker 1: So,
Speaker 2: I owe you once again.
Speaker 2: You're not going to pay me back anyway, are you?
Speaker 2: Speaking of which, regarding the materials that they demanded under the Freedom of Information Act,
Speaker 2: I handled it by giving them some falsified data.
Speaker 2: The government is proceeding with legal action, but that will be blocked any day now.
Speaker 2: So should I do something about that project as well?
Speaker 3: No. Judging by the material you sent me, it appears there will be no need.
Speaker 2: Then I'll proceed with the plan.
Speaker 4: Uh, good morning.
Speaker 5: Good morning.
Speaker 5: *crunch*
Speaker 5: *crying*
Speaker 5: That's the way to start your morning.
Speaker 4: Uh, what's wrong with coffee?
Speaker 5: You got a problem with tradition?
Speaker 5: Don't you know that a traditional Japanese breakfast is steamed rice, miso soup and a little sake?
Speaker 4: Your tradition, maybe.
Speaker 5: 'Scuse me?
Speaker 4: And incidentally, just whose turn was it supposed to be to cook today?
Speaker 4: Well, now I know why a woman your age is still single.
Speaker 4: You're going to be an old maid, Misato.
Speaker 5: Are you saying that I'm lazy?
Speaker 5: And sloppy, too.
Speaker 5: Oh, just leave me alone.
Speaker 5: Oh, I'm finished.
Speaker 4: So, are you really coming to my school today?
Speaker 4: Of course
Speaker 5: I am.
Speaker 5: It's your parent-teacher meeting.
Speaker 4: But you're just so busy at work.
Speaker 5: Oh, it's no problem. You're part of my job anyway.
Speaker 4: So it's just part of your job, huh?
Speaker 5: Hi! Oh, thanks for coming. Yes, he's getting ready. I'll come let you in.
Speaker 4: Misato, you shouldn't go outside dressed like that. It's embarrassing.
Speaker 5: I know.
Speaker 6: Good morning,
Speaker 4: Ikari. Hey, Misato. We're taking off
Speaker 5: now.
Speaker 5: Be careful.
Speaker 4: Oh, come on.
Speaker 5: Hmm.
Speaker 5: Ironic.
Speaker 5: The way he's getting more casual and expressing his feelings is a good trend.
Speaker 5: Yes, he's just left.
Speaker 5: Make sure you keep your eyes on him.
Speaker 7: - Yeah! - Oh, it's really key!
Speaker 7: Ah!
Ah!
Speaker 7: Is she Ikari's guardian?
Speaker 7: What? He's got a babe like that for a bodyguard?
Speaker 7: Those idiots.
Speaker 7: Oh,
Speaker 8: Misato
Speaker 3: is so gorgeous.
Speaker 8: Yeah, right.
Speaker 3: It's amazing someone so beautiful
Speaker 8: could be
Speaker 3: Nerve's operations director.
Speaker 8: I don't think
Speaker 3: so.
Speaker 6: Huh?
Speaker 7: Hey,
Speaker 8: Kensuke,
Speaker 6: it's a good thing that Shinji is such a baby.
Speaker 6: Yeah, he's no rival for us.
Speaker 4: You guys don't know what a slob she is.
Speaker 4: Man, I wish Misato were my girlfriend.
Speaker 4: Oh, no, you don't.
Speaker 1: You just don't get it,
Speaker 4: do you?
Speaker 1: Okay, you can handle keeping
Speaker 8: the Earth safe, and the two of us will take care of Misato!
Speaker 5: Unit 1 has achieved the required cooling level, shifting operations to Stage 2.
Speaker 5: Keeping the Earth
Speaker 4: safe... That's what Eva's for.
Speaker 4: Come to think of it, just what is Eva?
Speaker 4: This entry plug smells a lot like blood.
Speaker 4: But I feel so comfortable and relaxed here.
Speaker 4: Now that I think of it, I don't know anything about it.
Speaker 9: What's the status of Unit Zero's bio-chest components?
Speaker 9: It was seriously damaged, so we'll have to make an entirely new one,
Speaker 9: even though it's pretty close to our ancillary budget's limits.
Speaker 9: Will our job get any simpler once we get Unit Two from Germany?
Speaker 10: It could go just the other way. Disposing of those dead angels costs a bundle.
Speaker 5: Yeah, this place is ridiculously underfinanced,
Speaker 5: especially since mankind's future rests on us.
Speaker 9: It can't be helped. Man cannot live by Ava alone.
Speaker 9: All those survivors need money to live, too.
Speaker 9: Money, money, money.
Speaker 9: So is the commander off to another conference again?
Speaker 9: Yes. He's on board and en route now.
Speaker 7: Thank God for a little peace and quiet.
Speaker 2: Excuse me. Do you mind if I sit here?
Speaker 2: Go ahead.
Speaker 2: The revised budget for the sample collection passed quite easily, didn't it?
Speaker 2: The Committee's main concern is for their own survival.
Speaker 2: They won't be so budget conscious when their own lives are at stake.
Speaker 2: Yes, they used to think there were no more angels.
Speaker 2: And I have more good news.
Speaker 2: All the permanent members of the Security Council, except the United States,
Speaker 2: have approved the budget for AVA Unit 6.
Speaker 2: It's just a matter of time before the U.S. approves it as well.
Speaker 2: The Americans seem to be allergic to unemployment, but they'll learn.
Speaker 2: And your country?
Speaker 2: We will participate in the construction beginning with Unit 8.
Speaker 2: The plans for the second installation project are still viable.
Speaker 2: However, a pilot has not yet been found.
Speaker 2: The Angels have returned.
Speaker 2: We will have no other choice but to defeat them.
Speaker 2: My people do not want a repeat of the second impact either.
Speaker 2: You understand that.
Speaker 4: You mean that everything I've learned about second impact is
Speaker 9: wrong?
Speaker 9: Yes.
Speaker 9: The history books say that it was a disaster caused by a massive meteorite.
Speaker 9: But most of the true facts have been concealed through international government cover-ups.
Speaker 9: Fifteen years ago, in Antarctica, mankind discovered the being known as the first angel.
Speaker 9: In the middle of the investigation, however, for unknown reasons, the angel exploded.
Speaker 9: That is the real truth about the second impact.
Speaker 4: Then the things we're doing here are...
Speaker 9: Are to prevent a probable third impact before it happens.
Speaker 9: That is the sole purpose of Nerve and the Evangelions.
Speaker 9: By the way, Masato, the event will occur tomorrow as scheduled.
Speaker 9: I understand.
Speaker 5: Good morning.
Speaker 5: Good morning, Misato.
Speaker 5: I'm going to old Tokyo on business.
Speaker 5: I'll probably be getting back late tonight,
Speaker 5: so have something delivered for dinner.
Speaker 5: Bye.
Speaker 4: Okay, um, sure.
Speaker 4: The
End
Speaker 5: It's hard to believe that this place used to be the flourishing capital known as Tokyo.
Speaker 5: We're here.
Speaker 9: Hm?
Speaker 9: Why are they having this in a place like this?
Speaker 9: Is the SSDF getting involved?
Speaker 9: The Strategic Self-Defense Force? No. They're not allowed to interfere.
Speaker 9: I see. That's why they can do whatever they like.
Speaker 1: Thank you.
Speaker 7: Thank you.
Speaker 3: I'd like to thank you all for coming to this special demonstration of Japan Heavy Chemical Industrial Cooperative's latest product.
Speaker 3: In a few minutes, we'll be taking you up to the control room to observe the actual demonstration.
Speaker 3: But first, we'll be answering some of your questions here.
Speaker 7: Yes.
Speaker 7: Ah, the
Speaker 3: famous Dr. Ritsuko Akagi. It's our pleasure to have you here for this demonstration.
Speaker 9: Thank you. May I ask you a question?
Speaker 3: Of course, certainly.
Speaker 9: The unit is equipped with an internal nuclear reactor. Is this correct?
Speaker 9: Correct.
Speaker 3: This is our product's most distinguished feature,
Speaker 9: guaranteeing 150
Speaker 3: days of continuous operating power.
Speaker 9: I see. But from a safety perspective,
Speaker 9: isn't it rather risky to incorporate a nuclear reactor
Speaker 9: in a land-based weapon designed for hand-to-hand combat?
Speaker 3: We think it's more practical than a weapon that won't work for more than five minutes.
Speaker 9: But in an emergency, there would be problems with remote control.
Speaker 9: But it's more
Speaker 3: humane than a system that induces tremendous mental stress and causes mental instability in the pilot.
Speaker 9: Cut it out. You're acting like children.
Speaker 9: And there's still the issue of manual control.
Speaker 3: I would think that it is much safer than an extremely dangerous weapon that's been known to run out of control and go berserk in the middle of a city.
Speaker 3: A weapon that cannot be controlled is insane. It's like an hysterical woman. Completely out of control.
Speaker 9: Our technology will be able to control it.
Speaker 9: So
Speaker 3: you're saying that science and human courage will tame the savage Ava Beast?
Speaker 3: Are you serious?
Speaker 9: Yes, of course I'm serious.
Speaker 9: And
Speaker 3: because it depends on something as fragile as a human heart,
Speaker 3: NERV has allowed the situation to get completely out of control.
Speaker 3: The UN has already had to approve an enormous supplement to your existing budget.
Speaker 3: And as a result, 20,000 people in a dozen countries are starving to death.
Speaker 3: Of course, the actual cause of all this is still under investigation.
Speaker 3: Why don't you at least take responsibility for your handiwork?
Speaker 3: How fortunate that your organization is above the law.
Speaker 9: It doesn't matter what you say.
Speaker 9: The fact is that Nerve has the only weapon capable of defeating the enemy.
Speaker 3: You mean the AT field.
Speaker 3: That is simply a matter of time and research.
Speaker 3: Nerve's day in the sun will not last forever.
Speaker 5: Damn him!
Speaker 5: Those judges are just pissed off about being cut out of their share of the loot!
Speaker 5: I want to rip off that smug face of his and shove it into this locker.
Speaker 5: Then I'll kick it and kick it and kick it!
Speaker 8: Cut that
Speaker 9: out. Behave yourself.
Speaker 9: He's just a show-off, begging for praise and adulation.
Speaker 9: He's petty, not worthy of attention.
Speaker 9: Yeah, but how did that smug SOB know about the AT field?
Speaker 9: How could something so classified leak out?
Speaker 9: Intelligence must be dragging its ass.
Speaker 3: We are ready to begin the jet alone activation test.
Speaker 3: Don't worry, folks. There's no risk at all.
Speaker 3: Please, make yourselves comfortable and watch through the observation window.
Speaker 3: We are ready to begin. Start the test.
Speaker 7: Discharging the power core.
Speaker 7: Pressure levels normal.
Speaker 7: Cooling system circulation, normal.
Speaker 7: Release the control rods.
Speaker 7: The reactor has reached nominal power status.
Speaker 7: Output is normal.
Speaker 7: Begin walk cycle.
Speaker 7: Walking forward ahead, slow.
Speaker 7: Forward right leg.
Speaker 7: Roger.
Speaker 7: Walk forward ahead, slow.
Speaker 7: Forward right leg.
Speaker 11: Balance is nominal.
Speaker 11: Power core status, nominal.
Speaker 11: Roger.
Speaker 11: Now, forward left leg.
Speaker 11: Keep her steady.
Speaker 11: Roger.
Speaker 11: Forward left leg.
Speaker 11: Maintaining balance.
Speaker 5: Oh boy, it's walking.
Speaker 5: That's certainly something to be proud of.
Speaker 7: What's wrong?
Speaker 7: This is odd.
Speaker 7: The pressure inside the reactor is increasing.
Speaker 7: The temperature of the primary cooling system is also rising.
Speaker 7: Valve open.
Speaker 7: Insert the neutron deceleration fluid.
Speaker 7: No effect.
Speaker 7: The pump output isn't increasing.
Speaker 7: Initiating valve system check.
Speaker 7: All right, emergency stop.
Speaker 7: Cut off the power.
Speaker 7: Aboard signal transmission confirmed.
Speaker 7: It's not accepting it.
Speaker 7: The radio circuit is being blocked! It's out of control!
Speaker 7: This can't be happening.
Speaker 7: It's coming right at us!
Speaker 7: Oh my god, no!
Speaker 5: This robot's as badly behaved as the idiot who built it!
Speaker 7: The compression valve is operating irregularly! The control rods aren't working!
Speaker 7: possibility of meltdown imminent.
Speaker 3: Impossible.
Speaker 3: The jet alone's onboard computer system
Speaker 3: has been programmed to handle all possible contingencies
Speaker 3: and scenarios.
Speaker 3: This kind of thing simply cannot happen.
Speaker 5: Well, then you're about to have an impossible nuclear meltdown
Speaker 5: out there.
Speaker 3: Under the present circumstances, our only viable option
Speaker 3: is to wait for it to stop itself.
Speaker 5: And how likely is that?
Speaker 5: 0
Speaker 7: .0002%.
Speaker 7: It would be an act of God.
Speaker 5: Acts of men are better than acts of God.
Speaker 5: Tell me how to stop that thing.
Speaker 3: We've already tried every possible option.
Speaker 3: Not yet.
Speaker 5: There's got to be a last resort.
Speaker 5: A way to wipe out everything. Tell me the password.
Speaker 5: The
Speaker 3: password to delete all programming is top secret.
Speaker 3: I don't have the authority to release it.
Speaker 3: I'm sorry, but I'm not allowed to tell you.
Speaker 5: Then you better get the clearance, Vato.
Speaker 5: Do it!
Speaker 3: Tokita here. Let me speak to Mr. Manda in Tokyo 2.
Speaker 3: That's right, the Director of Internal Affairs.
Speaker 3: Well, I'll have to delegate that to Mr. Yasugi.
Speaker 3: Ask him.
Speaker 3: Well, I can't give you authorization for such an important matter verbally.
Speaker 3: Could you submit a written request?
Speaker 3: So now I need to get Mr. Yoshizawa's permission?
Speaker 3: What? Yes, I've already gotten approval from Mr. Witts. Yes, yes, okay.
Speaker 5: Bureaucracies.
Speaker 3: A written order of clearance will be sent. I'll give you the password then.
Speaker 5: We can't wait that long! Once Jett alone's reactor red lines, it'll be too late!
Speaker 5: Jet alone is heading
for Atsugi City.
Speaker 5: Time's running out.
Speaker 5: I'm taking the responsibility for this operation myself.
Speaker 5: You can wait here.
Speaker 5: Yuga, I want you to roll out the transport and bring Shinji and Unit 1 with the F equipment up here right now.
Speaker 5: Yes, this is an emergency.
Speaker 9: This is pointless.
Speaker 9: Call this off, Captain Katsuragi.
Speaker 9: Do you have any idea as to how to stop it?
Speaker 5: I'll override the computer manually.
Speaker 3: - Are you serious?
Speaker 5: - Yes.
Speaker 3: But, but Jet Alone's interior must be flooded with radiation.
Speaker 3: You're insane!
Speaker 5: But if I succeed, Atsugi will be saved!
Speaker 7: The access hatch can be opened manually as soon as our command signal is cut off.
Speaker 7: You should be able to enter the hatch through the backpack unit.
Speaker 7: Mm
Speaker 5: -hmm.
Speaker 7: That's the password
Speaker 3: to delete the programming.
Speaker 5: Thank you, sir.
Speaker 5: Our target is jet alone.
Speaker 5: There's a danger that it may begin to melt down in five minutes.
Speaker 5: Therefore, we cannot allow it to get any closer to a populated area.
Speaker 5: Hugo!
Speaker 10: Yes, ma'am?
Speaker 10: As soon
Speaker 5: as you drop Unit 1, take the transport up to a safe altitude and stand by.
Speaker 10: Roger.
Speaker 5: And Shinji?
Speaker 5: Yes?
Speaker 5: Run alongside the target and place me onto its back.
Speaker 5: Once I've gotten on, I want you to try to hold jet alone back as much as you can.
Speaker 5: You're climbing on that
Speaker 8: thing?
Speaker 5: To break into it?
Speaker 5: That's right.
Speaker 5: But that's just crazy!
Speaker 5: I know, but I'm afraid there just isn't any better way to stop it.
Speaker 5: But it's too dangerous!
Speaker 5: Don't worry. Unit 1's armor can handle both the explosion and the radiation.
Speaker 8: Not for Ava! I
Speaker 5: meant for you!
Speaker 5: Well, I've got to give it my best shot, you know.
Speaker 5: My conscience won't let me do otherwise.
Speaker 10: Ma'am, I've sighted a target.
Speaker 5: Right! Here we go!
Speaker 10: Ava approaching drop position.
Speaker 5: Docking release!
Speaker 5: Roger.
Speaker 4: We've caught up with it.
Speaker 4: We've got less than four minutes.
Speaker 5: Put me on now!
Speaker 5: Don't think about it, do it!
Speaker 1: Be careful.
Speaker 7: Talk about
Speaker 5: hot! I got a bad feeling about this.
Speaker 7: Stop running, you bastard!
Misato, hurry up!
Speaker 5: I found it.
Speaker 1: Error? What
Speaker 5: the hell?
Speaker 5: The program must have been altered. It must have.
Speaker 7: The power reactor is just 0.2 point short of critical.
Speaker 7: The control rod still won't function.
Speaker 5: I guess I'll try the long shot.
Speaker 1: Misato! Get out of there!
Speaker 1: Move, you move! Damn it! You can do it!
Speaker 1: Misato!
Speaker 7: 0.1 to critical!
Speaker 7: My god, it's going to go!
Speaker 7: Meltdown imminent!
Speaker 7: - All safety is failing! - Dear god!
Speaker 8: Misano!
Speaker 8: Help!
Speaker 7: She did
Speaker 9: it!
Speaker 9: Internal pressure lowering.
Speaker 7: All readings are nominal.
- Yes! - Yes!
Speaker 9: Yes, she did it!
Speaker 9: Crazy fool.
Speaker 5: Misato,
Speaker 4: are you all right?
Speaker 5: Misato!
Speaker 5: Yeah, I'm okay.
Speaker 5: Not in the greatest of shape, however.
Speaker 4: You're alive! Oh, God!
Speaker 4: Are you all right?
Speaker 4: Oh, thank God! I can't believe you did it!
Speaker 4: It's a miracle!
Speaker 5: Yeah.
Speaker 9: But the miracle was set up by someone.
Speaker 9: Recovery of Unit 1 is completed.
Speaker 9: No danger of radioactive contamination.
Speaker 9: Except for Captain Katsuragi's operation,
Speaker 9: everything went according to the plan.
Speaker 3: Good work.
Speaker 5: Good morning, Shinji.
Speaker 5: Yee-haw!
Speaker 5: *Gasp*
Speaker 5: That's the way to start your morning.
Speaker 5: Now, let me out that shower.
Speaker 5: Hey, Shinji, have you seen any clean bras or panties lying around?
Speaker 4: Good
Speaker 5: morning, Ikari!
Speaker 4: Morning.
Speaker 5: I'm taking off!
Speaker 5: Have a nice day!
Speaker 3: Misato is just so cool.
Speaker 4: Yeah, I used to think so too.
Speaker 4: But she's such a slob.
Speaker 4: She's always embarrassing me.
Speaker 4: She never does anything but lie around the house.
Speaker 4: She's not embarrassed about it, but I am.
Speaker 6: You're a lucky guy.
Speaker 6: What do you mean?
Speaker 6: Ikari really is just a kid, isn't he?
Speaker 6: He sure is.
Speaker 6: Meaning what?
Speaker 6: She let's you see a side of her that she wouldn't show to anyone else, right?
Speaker 6: That means she's your family.
Speaker 4: Yeah.
Speaker 1: In other words, darling, kiss
Speaker 8: me
Speaker 1: Fill my heart with song
Speaker 1: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 1: You are all I long for
Speaker 1: All I worship and adore
Speaker 1: In other words, please be true. In other words,
Speaker 5: I love
Speaker 1: you.
Speaker 5: Don't miss Oscar strikes!