Speaker 1: The young man like a man like a man
Speaker 1: You are a young man, you are a fairy tale
Speaker 1: If the wind is now on the door,
Speaker 1: I can only see myself,
Speaker 1: You are smiling
Speaker 1: You are so happy
Speaker 1: I don't know what you can do
Speaker 1: But I will know that you will find the back of your back
Speaker 1: The future will be the way to the future
Speaker 1: The holy of the天使 of the day
Speaker 1: The window from the day to the day
Speaker 1: The hot-to-day light of the day
Speaker 1: The dream of the day to the day
Speaker 1: The sky will be the shining
Speaker 2: Ashton.
Speaker 3: The fact
Speaker 2: that the instrumentality project is behind schedule?
Speaker 2: The
Speaker 3: projects are all linked together. There are no problems.
Speaker 2: Including Rey?
Speaker 2: Well, I won't press you.
Speaker 2: So how will we deal with you-know-who?
Speaker 2: Let him do as he wishes. The same with the Marduk Institute.
Speaker 2: I agree. We can make use of him. For a while.
Speaker 2: What
Speaker 4: started here?
Speaker 4: Sixteen years ago.
Speaker 5: It's me.
Speaker 4: Ah, so it is.
Speaker 4: This
Speaker 5: is Shannon Bio Inc., a foreign chemical firm.
Speaker 5: It's been like this for nine years, nine years without a single change.
Speaker 5: So far, 106 corporations out of the 108 affiliated with the Marduk Institute have turned out to be dummy companies.
Speaker 4: And this one is the 107th.
Speaker 5: This is the company's registration record.
Speaker 4: And you want me to take a look at the board of directors, don't you?
Speaker 5: You already know about this?
Speaker 5: I
Speaker 4: know most of the names, yes.
Speaker 4: The Marduk Institute is supposed to be an advisory body established under the control of the Human Instrumentality Committee for the purpose of selecting EVA pilots.
Speaker 4: Something's not adding up right here.
Speaker 5: Your task is to investigate Nerve. Getting involved with the Marduk may be an ill-advised step.
Speaker 4: Well, I can't help it. My nose for trouble has a penchant for getting my eyes in the
Speaker 5: wrong places.
Speaker 4: Hi, this is Kaji. I'm out right now, but you can leave your name and a message at the beep.
Speaker 6: Help me, Kaji!
Speaker 6: Don't touch me, you pervert!
Speaker 7: That ought to do it.
Speaker 7: What's going
Speaker 1: on?
Speaker 7: I was just calling Kaji.
Speaker 7: I wanted him to take me out tomorrow.
Speaker 7: I've been calling him and calling him, but he's always out these days.
Speaker 7: He's always out doing something.
Speaker 7: You mean you'll be available tomorrow?
Speaker 7: Unfortunately, it seems so.
Speaker 7: Great! Then I've got a favor to ask you.
Speaker 7: Well, you see...
Speaker 8: What? A date?
Speaker 8: The guy's a friend of Kadama, my big sister,
Speaker 8: and he keeps asking and asking me to set you and him up.
Speaker 7: Pretty please?
Speaker 9: Huh?
Speaker 9: Get back to your work!
Speaker 9: Sorry.
Speaker 10: Why don't you get back to work, Toji?
Speaker 7: Microsis operation completed.
Speaker 7: Inversible
Speaker 10: graph measurement
Speaker 9: byline.
Speaker 9: So,
Speaker 11: which dress are you wearing?
Speaker 11: Oh, for the wedding tomorrow?
Speaker 6: Well, I
Speaker 8: wore the pink suit for Kiyomi's wedding,
Speaker 8: and I wore the dark blue dress for Kotoko's shower, and...
Speaker 8: There's that orange one.
Speaker 8: You haven't worn that one lately.
Speaker 8: The orange one?
Speaker 8: Well, there's a reason I haven't worn it.
Speaker 8: It's too tight.
Speaker 8: Thank you!
Speaker 8: Maybe I should just buy a new one.
Speaker 8: Man, all these stupid weddings are killing my bank account.
Speaker 8: Tell me about it.
Speaker 8: We've been to so many showers, I'm almost broke.
Speaker 8: Yeah, it's like everyone's in a rush to get married before they turn
Speaker 11: 30.
Speaker 11: And you don't want to be the last one still single, do you?
Speaker 7: Excuse me?
Speaker 7: Okay, you
Speaker 11: guys can take off now.
Speaker 7: Good work.
Speaker 7: It's about time!
Speaker 7: These stupid experiments are really getting on my nerves!
Speaker 7: Speaking of
Speaker 11: which, Shinji seems more subdued than usual.
Speaker 11: Tomorrow's the day.
Speaker 11: Oh, yeah. Tomorrow.
Speaker 9: Tomorrow.
Speaker 9: I have to see my father tomorrow.
Speaker 9: What should I talk to him about, Rei?
Speaker 9: I don't understand. Why are you asking me?
Speaker 9: Because I've seen you talking with my father and actually enjoying it.
Speaker 9: Say, my father.
Speaker 9: What's he like?
I don't know.
Speaker 12: Oh.
Speaker 12: Have you been watching me because you wanted to ask that question?
Speaker 12: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 12: Hey, when we were cleaning, that cloth,
Speaker 9: the way you ringed it,
Speaker 9: it reminded me of a mother when you squeezed it.
Speaker 9: A mother?
Speaker 9: Yeah.
Speaker 9: It just reminded me of a mom.
Speaker 9: I bet you'll make a great mother, Ray.
Speaker 9: I mean...
Speaker 1: You...
Speaker 1: Embarrass me.
Speaker 7: I'm home!
Speaker 7: What's
Speaker 12: happening?
Speaker 7: You better go to bed, Oscar.
Speaker 7: Don't you have a date tomorrow?
Speaker 7: With some med student.
Speaker 7: Oh, Misato!
Speaker 7: - Yo, can I use your lavender perfume?
Speaker 7: - Uh, no.
Speaker 7: - No, Nini.
Speaker 7: - That stuff's not for kids.
Speaker 7: Is Shinji in his room?
Speaker 7: - Yeah, ever since he got home.
Speaker 7: I don't think he wants to meet his father.
Speaker 7: If he hates him so much, why doesn't he just say?
Speaker 7: You Japanese are weird.
Speaker 7: - Well, he doesn't actually hate him.
Speaker 7: That's the
Speaker 8: problem.
Speaker 3: - Leave.
Speaker 3: Good work, Shinji.
Speaker 8: Shinji!
Speaker 8: I'm coming in, okay?
Speaker 8: You're worried about seeing your father tomorrow, right?
Speaker 8: You mustn't run away, Shinji.
Speaker 8: Nothing will ever change unless you have the courage to step forward.
Speaker 8: I know that, Misato.
Speaker 8: You're going to find out the truth.
Speaker 8: You've got to keep moving forward.
Speaker 8: After each step, you've got to keep taking another afterwards.
Speaker 8: Anyway, when you see him tomorrow,
Speaker 8: you've got to keep your chin held high,
Speaker 8: because you'll be seeing her too.
Speaker 8: Good night, Shinji.
Speaker 10: You bought a new dress, didn't you?
Speaker 10: Let me see.
Speaker 10: Oh, you want to see it, do you?
Speaker 10: It's an expensive one.
Speaker 10: Price doesn't
Speaker 7: always be pleasant.
Speaker 7: You're on.
Speaker 7: Tell me about it.
Speaker 7: Well, what do you think? Did you pick that one with Paji in mind?
Speaker 7: Grow up.
Speaker 7: Long time
ago.
Speaker 7: Well, see ya.
Speaker 7: Later.
Speaker 8: You must keep three bags in your heart.
Speaker 8: And now, let us proceed to the reception.
Speaker 11: Little boy
Speaker 8: Blue is late.
Speaker 8: That over-sexed idiot's never been on time in his whole lazy life.
Speaker 8: For your dates, you mean? He gets to work early.
Speaker 4: Hello, girls. You're looking particularly lovely today.
Speaker 4: I had a little trouble getting out of work on time.
Speaker 4: I find
Speaker 8: that hard to believe since you don't do anything.
Speaker 8: You could at least
Speaker 4: have
Speaker 8: taken the time and trouble to shave that awful stubble.
Speaker 8: Your tie is crooked.
Speaker 4: Well, thank you.
Speaker 4: You act like you're married.
Speaker 4: You're very astute, Ritsipoo.
Speaker 8: Who'd marry
Speaker 6: this bum?
Speaker 3: It's been three years since we were last here.
Speaker 9: That's when I ran away.
Speaker 9: I haven't come back here since then.
Speaker 9: I just don't believe that my mom is really resting here.
Speaker 9: I don't even remember her face.
Speaker 3: Burying memories is man's way of surviving
Speaker 3: But there are some things a man should never forget
Speaker 3: Yui taught me that one irreplaceable thing, Shinji
Speaker 3: That is the reason I come here, to confirm that commitment
Speaker 9: You don't have a picture of her?
Speaker 3: No photographs
Speaker 3: Even this grave is an artifice
Speaker 3: Nothing remains
Speaker 9: That's like my teacher said
Speaker 9: You cast everything away
Speaker 3: Everything is kept in my heart
Speaker 3: I'm satisfied with that
Speaker 3: Our time is up.
Speaker 3: I'm leaving now.
Speaker 9: Father!
Speaker 9: I'm glad that we could talk together today.
Speaker 3: Indeed.
-
Speaker 7: I'm not sure what
Speaker 9: you
Speaker 9: But I could have quit any time.
Speaker 9: So
Speaker 7: why didn't you?
Speaker 7: Huh?
Speaker 9: Nobody told me to stop, I guess.
Speaker 9: Oh, I should have known.
Speaker 9: Hey, you're back early.
Speaker 9: I thought you were going out to dinner, too.
Speaker 7: Oh, my date was even more boring than you.
Speaker 7: Saw Wiley was standing in line for the roller coaster,
Speaker 7: I took a train back here.
Speaker 9: That seems kind of cold.
Speaker 7: Oh, gosh, he's the only real man in my life.
Speaker 7: I know it's getting a little late,
Speaker 7: but I've
Speaker 8: got to go powder my nose.
Speaker 4: Making a quick exit?
Speaker 4: High heels.
Speaker 4: It's been a while since we went out together.
Speaker 11: She's drinking too much.
Speaker 11: She's losing her control.
Speaker 4: Sometimes you just have to drink to keep yourself under control.
Speaker 4: All of us do.
Speaker 11: Well, you did used to live with her, so I guess you'd know the truth.
Speaker 4: Well, that was a lifetime ago.
Speaker 4: She didn't even own a set of heels back then.
Speaker 11: That's not how we saw it back when we were in school.
Speaker 4: We were kids, Ritsu.
Speaker 4: That wasn't real.
Speaker 4: We were just children playing house.
Speaker 4: It was nice.
Speaker 4: But life's not that simple.
Speaker 4: Oh, I almost forgot.
Speaker 11: The cat dragged this in.
Speaker 11: Thank you, Kaji, for being
Speaker 4: honest.
Speaker 4: To the ladies, yes.
Speaker 4: Otherwise,
Speaker 11: eh...
Speaker 11: I doubt that.
Speaker 11: And Misato?
Speaker 4: I've lost that war before.
Speaker 4: Doom battles aren't my style.
Speaker 11: I think you still have a chance.
Speaker 4: Well, what about you?
Speaker 11: Oh, I don't like to talk about myself.
Speaker 11: There's nothing much to say.
Speaker 4: Why is she taking so long?
Speaker 4: How much makeup can she wear?
Speaker 11: Hmm.
Speaker 4: What
Speaker 11: were you doing in Kyoto?
Speaker 4: I wasn't in Kyoto.
Speaker 11: Don't try to fool me.
Speaker 11: You'll get your fingers burned if you get too involved in this.
Speaker 11: That's the advice of a friend.
Speaker 4: I'd rather be burned by the heat of my passion for you.
Speaker 8: Well, should I buy you some fireworks?
Speaker 4: Hello.
Speaker 8: Oh, you never change, do you?
Speaker 4: Of course I change.
Speaker 4: The act of living is an embracement of change.
Speaker 11: Homeostasis and transestasis.
Speaker 11: Homeo-what?
Speaker 11: One is a force to maintain the present status,
Speaker 11: and the other is a force for constant change.
Speaker 11: Anything that lives is composed of these two conflicting forces.
Speaker 4: Like men and women.
Speaker 11: I'll just be taking off now. I've got some work to do.
Speaker 11: Now?
Speaker 4: That's too bad.
Speaker 4: Mm-hmm. Have fun.
Speaker 8: But...
Speaker 8: -
Speaker 8: - Hey, Shinji, it's me.
Speaker 8: I'm gonna be out drinking with Kaji.
Speaker 8: Don't wait up for me, okay?
Speaker 9: - Right.
Speaker 9: Yeah, sure.
Speaker 9: - Misato?
Speaker 9: - Yeah, she'll be late, so don't wait up for her.
Speaker 7: - What?
Speaker 7: You mean she won't be back until tomorrow morning?
Speaker 9: - I doubt it.
Speaker 9: She's going out with Kaji.
Speaker 9: - Are you dense?
Speaker 9: That guarantees it.
Speaker 8: Drinking
Speaker 4: till you throw up.
Speaker 4: How old are you?
Speaker 8: Old enough to regret it.
Speaker 4: I'm old enough as well.
Speaker 8: You're damn right.
Speaker 8: I can't
Speaker 4: believe that you wear high heels these days.
Speaker 4: Time really does fly.
Speaker 8: You need to shave your sloppy face.
Speaker 6: Okay, let
Speaker 8: me walk.
Speaker 8: Thank you.
Speaker 8: Kaji, do you think I've changed?
Speaker 4: You're even prettier.
Speaker 8: Not what I mean.
Speaker 8: When I told you there was someone else, it wasn't true.
Speaker 8: But you knew that, didn't you?
Speaker 4: No.
Speaker 8: One morning, I just realized how much like my father you were.
Speaker 8: I panicked.
Speaker 8: I couldn't believe that I wanted a man just like my father.
Speaker 8: I was terrified, so I ran.
Speaker 8: I was so scared.
Speaker 8: I was afraid of becoming a woman, afraid of being with you,
Speaker 8: and thought I hated my father.
Speaker 8: But then I fell in love with a man who was just like my father.
Speaker 8: I thought joining Nerve would be a way to sever those ties.
Speaker 8: And then it turned out that my father was with Nerve.
Speaker 8: So I tried to bury all of my feelings by swearing to avenge myself against the angels.
Speaker 4: Choosing that path was your decision.
Speaker 4: You don't have to apologize to anyone.
Speaker 8: Don't bullshit me, Kaji.
Speaker 8: I just turned tail and ran.
Speaker 8: It was just an escape from the real world and my father.
Speaker 8: I'm no better than Shinji is.
Speaker 8: I'm a Kawagashi.
Speaker 8: Well, it's just like right now.
Speaker 8: I had to get up the nerve to get drunk enough to even tell
Speaker 12: you the truth.
Speaker 8: I'm a child.
Speaker 8: I have no right to be Shinji's
Speaker 12: guardian.
Speaker 8: Look at me, afraid to accept a helping hand up from a man
Speaker 8: except when I'm so falling down drunk that I don't even know what I'm doing.
Speaker 8: I'm a horrible woman and I'd use you, use
Speaker 6: you because I'm
Speaker 8: a coward.
Speaker 8: I'm pathetic.
Speaker 7: Hey, Shinji.
Speaker 7: You wanna kiss me?
Speaker 7: Huh?
Speaker 6: What?
Speaker 7: Kissing, you know. Have you ever done it?
Speaker 7: Uh-uh.
Speaker 7: So let's do it.
Speaker 7: But why?
Speaker 7: I've got nothing else to do.
Speaker 7: That's your reason?
Speaker 9: You're weird.
Speaker 7: Afraid to kiss a girl on the anniversary of your mom's death?
Speaker 7: Is she watching you from up in heaven?
Speaker 7: That's not
Speaker 9: it.
Speaker 9: Or
Speaker 7: are you scared?
Speaker 7: I'm not
Speaker 9: afraid!
Speaker 7: Pucker up!
Speaker 7: Right. Did you brush her teeth?
Speaker 7: Yeah.
Speaker 7: Then here I come.
Speaker 7: Stop breathing. It's tickling me.
Speaker 6: *Gasp*
Speaker 4: - Hang on, we're here.
Speaker 4: - Hey, Kaji.
Speaker 7: - What?
Speaker 7: Hey, hello, Kaji.
Speaker 4: - There, I'll be leaving now.
Speaker 7: - You can spend the night here.
Speaker 4: - I'd never live it down if I went to work like this.
Speaker 7: - Oh, you could do it.
Speaker 7: Hey, come on, Kaji, it'd...
Speaker 4: Later, Asuka.
Speaker 9: Lavender review.
Speaker 4: Take care of Misato, okay?
Speaker 9: Sure.
Speaker 9: Good night, Kaji.
Speaker 4: Yeah.
Speaker 9: What's wrong? You look upset.
Speaker 7: That's because you kissed me, you jerk!
Speaker 9: Let me call a roll.
Speaker 9: Ladies first.
Speaker 9: Ayanami? Rei Ayanami? Is she absent again?
Speaker 4: *Bell rings
Speaker 8: And the other would appear to be a spy for the Japanese government.
Speaker 4: Hm. So you knew.
Speaker 8: Don't underestimate nerve.
Speaker 4: Was this ordered by Ikari?
Speaker 8: No. My initiative. But if you stay with this other job, you'll die.
Speaker 4: Perhaps not. Commander Ikari is using me for his own ends.
Speaker 4: But I am sorry that I've kept this secret from you.
Speaker 8: I'll let it pass. Repayment for your help yesterday.
Speaker 4: I appreciate that. But you should know that the Commander and Ritsuko are hiding something from you too.
Speaker 4: And this is it!
Speaker 8: Oh my god.
Speaker 8: Is it an Eva?
Speaker 8: No, it can't be.
Speaker 4: Yes.
Speaker 4: The key to the second impact and everything that's happened since.
Speaker 4: The starting point of everything.
Speaker 4: This is Adam.
Speaker 8: Adam?
Speaker 8: But why is the first angel here?
Speaker 8: You're right, Kashi.
Speaker 8: I don't know, Nerv.
Speaker 8: I don't know NERV at all!
Speaker 12: Darling, kiss me
Speaker 12: Fill my heart with song
Speaker 12: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 12: You are all I long
Speaker 12: For all I worship and I do
Speaker 12: In other words
Speaker 12: Please be true
Speaker 12: Before the world
I love you
Speaker 10: After finally getting ahead of Asuka and the sync tests,
Speaker 10: Shinji is full of pride, but everything comes crashing down
Speaker 10: when he's swallowed by the Sea of Darak.
Speaker 10: As his Ava's energy supply runs out, fear and loneliness surround him,
Speaker 10: enveloping him in a new level of anguish and despair.
Speaker 10: His very survival is at stake in the next thrilling episode.