Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
FORM OF THE MIND
FORM OF THE MAN
EPISODE 20
Rei Ayanami
Gendo Ikari
Yui Ikari
Father
Mother
Child
Stranger
Self
The Ego
Hypocrisy
Needs
Repression
The Weak
Identification
Self
Internalization
Breasts
Inferiority Complex
Will
Symbiosis
Solitude
Compensation
Reality
Ideal
Inculcation
Mind and Body
Fear
Insecurity
Value
Dependence
Escape
Estrangement
Loss
Oral Stage
Obsession
Come.
Gendo lkari
Welcome to
Nerv
OPERATION PLAN
TYPE EP2 SALVAGE WORK PROCEDURAL OUTLINE
(AND TYPE LP3 COMPLEMENTATION PROCEDURE)
Asuka
Ritsuko
Toji
Kensuke
Misato
Asuka
Ritsuko
Toji
Kensuke
Ayanami
Misato
Asuka
Ritsuko
Toji
Kensuke
Ayanami
Misato
Asuka
Ritsuko
Toji
Kensuke
Ayanami
Misato
Asuka
Ritsuko
Toji
Kensuke
Ayanami
Misato
Asuka
Ritsuko
Toji
Kensuke
Ayanami
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
YEAR 2015
Kyoto, Year 1999
ANTARCTICA, YEAR 2000
YEAR 2001
YEAR 2002
HAKONE, YEAR 2003
YEAR 2005
NEW TOKYO-2, NAGANO PREFECTURE
YEAR 2004
YEAR 2008
YEAR 2010
COMPLETE
YEAR 2015 ONCE AGAIN
THE BIRTH OF NERV