Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 2: I'm
Speaker 1: just looking at you and smiling.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to touch the one I want.
Speaker 1: I'm still in awe of my dreams.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure you'll notice that the back of my eyes.
Speaker 1: The future will be the way to the future
Speaker 1: The world is a terrible, the天使's the day
Speaker 1: The window from the end of the day
Speaker 1: The hot air is a hot air to the day
Speaker 1: The memories of the night
Speaker 1: The sky is shining
Speaker 3: Hey, cool! I just want a free ice cream bar!
Speaker 4: The cost of having my laundry done is killing me.
Speaker 5: Yeah, I know. I just wish I had the spare time to do my laundry for myself.
Speaker 6: Could
Speaker 7: be worse.
Speaker 6: At least we sleep at home.
Speaker 4: Oh, Commander Friutski. Good morning, sir.
Speaker 4: Good morning, sir.
Speaker 6: Good morning.
Speaker 4: Well, you're up early today, sir.
Speaker 6: I've got to represent Commander Ikari uptown.
Speaker 4: Ah, today's the city council meeting, isn't it?
Speaker 6: An exercise in ennui.
Speaker 6: Ikari always sticks me with the most boring and tedious assignments.
Speaker 6: I couldn't handle it without the Magi's help.
Speaker 4: Speaking of which, election day is coming up, isn't it?
Speaker 6: Yes, but the council really has no authority anyway.
Speaker 6: Actually, the Magi run just about everything.
Speaker 5: Really? You mean the same three supercomputers we use?
Speaker 5: Yes.
Speaker 6: Our government is run by the majority decision of three different computers.
Speaker 6: I suppose it's a sort of a form of democracy.
Speaker 5: And the council members just go along with their decisions?
Speaker 5: Well,
Speaker 6: it's been an effective form of government thus far.
Speaker 5: This city really is built on science. We're so lucky to be living in such a wonderful
Speaker 4: time.
Speaker 6: Eh, technophiles.
Speaker 6: You're running an experiment with Unit Zero this morning, aren't you?
Speaker 4: Yes. We're going to be performing the second prolonged EVA activation test at 10.30.
Speaker 6: Ah, I'll expect good news.
Speaker 4: Abort the test! Break the circuits!
Speaker 4: Cutting circuits.
Speaker 3: Power supply
Speaker 8: restored.
Speaker 4: It seems that one's the problem again.
Speaker 5: Yes. It looks like the conversion efficiency is 0.8% lower than our calculation.
Speaker 8: The conversion is barely within tolerance, though. What'll we do?
Speaker 8: Let's
Speaker 4: try it again using the same configuration, but lower the reciprocal conversion rate by 0.01.
Speaker 4: All right, let's start the experiment over again.
Speaker 7: Hey!
Hold the elevator!
Speaker 9: Got it.
Speaker 9: Man, it's been a while since I ran that hard.
Speaker 9: So, what's with the black expression, Sunshine?
Speaker 10: It's nausea from having to see you.
Speaker 10: Yes,
Speaker 4: hold one minute, please.
Speaker 11: What?
Speaker 11: Uh,
Speaker 12: well, Father, uh, well...
Speaker 11: What is it? Hurry up.
Speaker 12: I'm supposed to tell my parents that an interview for advanced vocational education is going to be held at school.
Speaker 11: I've delegated all of that to Katsuragi. Don't bother me with such nonsense
Speaker 9: anymore.
Speaker 9: Don't forward any more of these calls to me.
Speaker 10: Huh?
Speaker 9: The power's out?
Speaker 10: No, it can't be. It's not possible.
Speaker 2: Something's wrong. An accident?
Speaker 9: Perhaps Dr. Akagi made a mistake, huh?
Speaker 5: The main power supply is shut down.
Speaker 5: Voltage level is zero.
Speaker 5: Uh, it's not our fault.
Speaker 9: Well, what do you think?
Speaker 5: The backup
Speaker 10: supply should switch back on any second now.
Speaker 6: No, sir. The backup circuits aren't working either.
Speaker 6: That can't be.
Speaker 6: Which circuits are still functioning?
Speaker 2: Only 1.2% of them!
Speaker 2: Only 9 circuits from number 2567!
Speaker 6: Connect all the remaining power circuits to maintain the Magi in Central Dogma.
Speaker 6: But that could interfere with our life support systems.
Speaker 6: Do it! We need the Magi!
Nozomu Takahashi wants to help you form a more cheerful government...
Speaker 6: Man, that Captain Katsuragi sure is lazy.
Speaker 9: I mean, can't she at least make the time to go and pick up her own laundry?
Speaker 9: Huh?
Speaker 3: Maybe Commander Akari was just really busy.
Speaker 3: I don't think so. And it wasn't like he hung up.
Speaker 3: It sounded more like the line had failed.
Speaker 3: Hey, are you a man or what? Why do you let each and every little incident get under your skin?
Speaker 3: What are you doing?
Speaker 3: Here, let me...
Speaker 3: Hmm? Huh? Huh? Huh?
Speaker 3: Stupid thing! It must be broken, damn it!
Speaker 3: One, two,
three!
Speaker 4: We'd better head for the command center.
Speaker 4: If the backup power hasn't kicked in yet...
Speaker 4: Then something's very wrong.
Speaker 9: What's the backup system?
Speaker 4: There are three backup circuits.
Speaker 10: It's impossible for all of these to fail at once.
Speaker 11: Then that means these circuit breakers didn't go on their own.
Speaker 11: Someone did this intentionally.
Speaker 6: Well, it would be a disaster if an Angel were to attack right now.
Speaker 8: Radar's detected an unidentified object.
Speaker 8: Projected landing point is in the form of atomic region.
Speaker 8: It must be Angel number eight.
Speaker 8: Yeah, an Angel.
Speaker 8: What'll we do?
Speaker 8: I guess the standard procedure is to go full alert status.
Speaker 8: It looks like this one's heading straight for Tokyo 3 and Nerve.
Speaker 8: Looks like it.
Speaker 8: Well, there's nothing we can do.
Speaker 4: It's still advancing.
Speaker 8: Any word yet from Tokyo 3?
Speaker 8: They're
Speaker 4: still not responding to our transmissions.
Speaker 8: What in the hell are those Nerve guys doing?
Speaker 4: I never thought I'd actually have to use one of these escape tubes.
Speaker 4: I figured they were just holdovers that we held onto just for
Speaker 2: our peace of mind.
Speaker 2: Well, being prepared is half the battle.
Speaker 3: This one doesn't work either.
Speaker 2: None of the facilities work.
Speaker 3: This is odd.
Speaker 3: Has something happened in the geo front?
Speaker 2: A natural assumption.
Speaker 3: Well, let's try to
Speaker 10: contact Nerve headquarters.
Speaker 10: The emergency phone isn't working either.
Speaker 11: There's no answer on line 77. None of them work.
Speaker 10: No,
Speaker 2: it's disconnected.
Speaker 10: This one, too. The
Speaker 3: main and emergency cables are all down.
Speaker 13: So what now?
Speaker 3: Oh.
Speaker 12: What are you looking for?
Speaker 3: What do you think, Doomkopf? I'm looking for my emergency manual.
Speaker 3: We should go to NERF headquarters ourselves.
Speaker 3: That's right, but before that, we're going to have to decide which of us will be this group's leader.
Speaker 3: Naturally, I have the best qualifications.
Speaker 3: Any objections?
Speaker 3: Well, let's go.
Speaker 2: Nervous over this way.
Speaker 2: We can use the access port for Route 7.
Speaker 12: But the doors don't work.
Speaker 12: Oh, we can open it manually.
Speaker 3: Well, there you go, Shinji.
Speaker 3: This is your department.
Speaker 3: You're the one who wants to be in charge,
Speaker 13: but whenever going gets tough,
Speaker 13: you always defer to me.
Speaker 8: That damn council always defers to us when the going gets tough.
Speaker 8: Well, what did they say?
Speaker 8: Those Tokyo-2 buttheads, they're getting ready to flee, of course.
Speaker 5: The angel is still advancing.
Speaker 8: In any case, we've got to try and make contact with Nerve.
Speaker 8: But how are we going to do that?
Speaker 8: We fly there ourselves.
This is the 3rd District JAS-DF.
An unidentified object is moving toward this area.
Speaker 6: Oh boy, I gotta report this to headquarters, but how? Oh man!
Speaker 6: Hey,
Speaker 10: Booster Takahashi, he's the candidate who remains calm, even in situations like this.
Speaker 9: Ah, alright.
Speaker 10: I'm dying, it's too hot in here.
Speaker 9: The air conditioners are down too. If you're so hot, Katsuragi, why don't you take off your shirt?
Speaker 9: There's no reason for you to be shy, you know.
Speaker 10: Don't even think about trying to take advantage of this situation.
Speaker 9: Yeah, right.
Speaker 10: It's getting even warmer now that
Speaker 4: the air is getting stagnant.
Speaker 4: It's hard to believe that this base has the world's most advanced technology.
Speaker 4: Yeah, but look at the commanders.
Speaker 5: Even in this heat, they're both still cool and in command.
Speaker 6: It's hot.
Speaker 6: Yes.
Speaker 6: This geofront was designed to be a self-sufficient colony.
Speaker 6: It's supposed to be able to operate even when completely isolated from the outside.
Speaker 6: It's impossible for all the power sources to have broken down.
Speaker 4: Someone caused this?
Speaker 6: It would be a logical way to
Speaker 11: indirectly dissect this facility.
Speaker 11: You
Speaker 4: mean that they could figure out Nerve's layout by the restoration process?
Speaker 6: They are clever bastards.
Speaker 6: I
Speaker 4: could run a dummy program through the Magi.
Speaker 4: That would make it more difficult to get a complete grasp of our structure.
Speaker 6: Make it so.
Speaker 4: Yes, sir.
Speaker 6: I can't believe that the first havoc wrecked upon our headquarters was caused by another member of our own species.
Speaker 11: Mankind's greatest enemy is man himself.
Speaker 13: This usually only takes two minutes. Are you sure this is the right way?
Speaker 13: Of course I'm
Speaker 3: sure. We'll be at the Geo Front any minute now.
Speaker 3: Uh, haven't I heard that four times already?
Speaker 3: Jeez, why do you have to nitpick everything? You're always so negative.
Speaker 3: Me? What?
Speaker 2: Silence, please.
Speaker 2: Oh,
Speaker 3: what now, Wonder Girl?
Speaker 2: Listen.
Speaker 2: Attention
all nerve personnel. There's an angel approaching.
Attention all nerve personnel.
Speaker 14: That's Yuga! Hey!
Speaker 14: Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
Speaker 14: There's an angel approaching.
An angel is approaching.
Speaker 3: A new angel?
Speaker 2: We can't waste any more time. There's a shortcut.
Speaker 3: Hey, don't forget that I'm the leader here.
Speaker 3: So where is this shortcut?
Speaker 3: This way may be quick, but we
Speaker 13: look really stupid.
Speaker 13: Hey, just what are the angels?
Speaker 13: Why are you asking now?
Speaker 13: I don't know. It just doesn't make sense. Angels are messengers from God, right?
Speaker 13: Why are we fighting angels?
Speaker 13: What are you,
Speaker 3: stupid? They attacked us. When someone's attacking you, you can't just sit there and do nothing, right?
Speaker 3: Let's see. To the right.
Speaker 3: I think the correct path is to the left.
Speaker 3: Stop contradicting me!
Speaker 3: Shinji, what do you think?
Speaker 3: Uh, uh...
Speaker 3: I'm not certain.
Speaker 3: Look, I'm the leader, so you can both just shut up and follow me.
Speaker 12: We're going up again.
Speaker 12: I thought something was odd here.
Speaker 3: So why didn't you say something earlier?
Speaker 3: You're always nitpicking, huh?
Speaker 3: This has got to be the Geo Front this time.
Speaker 3: -
Speaker 7: -
-
- -
Speaker 3: - Well,
Speaker 3: we'd
Speaker 3: better hurry. Now that I've visually
Speaker 3: confirmed
Speaker 6: the angel's presence...
- - - There's
Speaker 6: an
Speaker 6: angel
Speaker 6: approaching! We have to dispatch an Ava immediately!
Speaker 6: But how?
Speaker 11: Fyutski, take charge here.
Speaker 11: What?
Speaker 11: I'm going down to the cage to prepare the Evas for manual launch.
Speaker 11: Manually?
Speaker 11: Can that be done?
Speaker 11: We have a diesel generator for emergencies.
Speaker 11: Well, yes, but who is going to pilot them?
Speaker 3: This
way.
Speaker 3: You're Commander Ikari's favorite, aren't you?
Speaker 3: I guess that that means you get treated a little different, right?
Speaker 3: Asuka, this isn't the time for this.
Speaker 3: You always look so smug, too.
Speaker 3: Hey, just because they like you best doesn't mean you can act so superior.
Speaker 3: I
Speaker 2: don't act superior.
Speaker 2: And I'm not treated any better either.
Speaker 2: I know that quite well.
Speaker 8: Understood. The termination plug has been ejected, sir.
Speaker 8: Excellent.
Speaker 11: Prepare for manual insertion of the entry plug.
Speaker 11: But the pilots aren't here yet.
Speaker 4: Don't worry. They'll be along soon enough.
Speaker 4: There's no way I can
Speaker 12: clear this away with my
Speaker 2: hands.
Speaker 2: Then we will have to break into another ventilation duct in order to get there.
Speaker 3: First child's feeling aggressive, and I'll bet she'd do anything to stay number one.
Speaker 3: Some people just think they're better than others.
Speaker 5: Entry plug is fixed and ready.
Speaker 4: Now all we need are the children.
Speaker 3: If you dare look up my dress, I'll kill you.
Speaker 3: Do you hear me, Shinji?
Speaker 3: You look!
Speaker 3: I'm there!
Speaker 3: I told
you not to look!
What I'm done to the board is you!
Huh?
Speaker 4: Oh, that's where you've been.
Speaker 4: We've been waiting for you.
Speaker 11: Prepare for manual entry.
Speaker 11: Roger!
Speaker 11: Never open
the hatches!
Speaker 4: The Evas?
Speaker 4: They're already on standby.
Speaker 4: Huh?
Speaker 4: But there's no power.
Speaker 4: It was all done by hand.
Speaker 4: The Commander did it.
Speaker 4: My father...
Speaker 4: Commander Akari believed in you and prepared everything.
*Gunshot
Speaker 11: Understood. Remove all of the remaining restraints and supports. Commence launch!
Speaker 3: The Angel has stopped directly above us!
Speaker 3: Hurry up! Get a move on!
Speaker 4: The emergency batteries have been engaged!
Speaker 4: Well, we're ready. Let's move out!
Speaker 7: Oh!
Speaker 3: This is pathetic!
Speaker 2: Vertical shaft in sight.
Speaker 2: Get out of the way!
Speaker 3: I can't believe we're doing this, it's so embarrassing.
Speaker 3: Huh?
Speaker 2: It's acid, watch out!
Speaker 2: Huh?
Speaker 2: Oh!
I'm not sure
Speaker 2: It would appear that the Angel plans to attack headquarters directly using that acid.
Speaker 3: What do we do?
Speaker 3: We're gonna
Speaker 13: beat it, of course!
Speaker 13: Okay, but how?
Speaker 13: We dropped our rifles and the battery packs on our backs are running out of power!
Speaker 13: They will last more than another three minutes!
Speaker 3: I've got an idea.
Speaker 3: There will be three positions: defense, offense, and backup.
Speaker 3: Defense's job will be to neutralize that Angel's AT field and to protect the offense from the acid bath.
Speaker 3: Backup will go down the shaft, retrieve the rifles, and hand one to the offense, who will then fire a volley, destroying the target.
Speaker 2: How does that sound?
Speaker 2: I will take the defensive position.
Speaker 3: Sorry, Wonder Girl!
Speaker 3: That'll be my job.
Speaker 3: But it's too dangerous.
Speaker 3: That's why I'm doing it. And don't forget I still owe you one from the last time we fought an Angel.
Speaker 3: Shinji will be offense. Rei will be the backup.
Speaker 3: Got it?
Speaker 3: Understood.
Speaker 3: Right, here we go.
Speaker 3: Ava, let's go!
Speaker 3: Oscar!
Speaker 3: Hey, Nami!
Speaker 3: Oscar, get out of the way!
Oscar!
Speaker 3: Now we're even, Shinji.
Speaker 3: Oh, no, please open,
Speaker 10: please.
Speaker 10: Why won't it open?
Speaker 10: Please, I've got to go to the bathroom now.
Speaker 10: Hey, you're not looking at my dress, are you?
Speaker 10: No,
Speaker 9: ma'am.
Speaker 7: Huh?
Speaker 7: Ah!
Speaker 5: Ah!
Speaker 5: Watch out!
Ah!
Speaker 5: Sex fiends.
Speaker 12: It's ironic.
Speaker 12: Without electricity and artificial light, the sky can look so beautiful at
Speaker 3: night.
Speaker 3: Yeah, but without the lights, it seems like there are no humans here.
Speaker 3: There. I feel much more comfortable this way.
Speaker 2: Man fears the darkness, and so he scrapes away at the edges of it with fire.
Speaker 2: Hmph.
Speaker 12: Philosophy, huh?
Speaker 12: So is that what makes mankind a special species? Is that why the angels attack us?
Speaker 3: What are you, stupid? Who knows what they think?
Speaker 14: In other words, darling, kiss me
Speaker 14: Fill my heart with soul
Speaker 14: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 14: You are all I want
Speaker 14: For all I want to adore
Speaker 14: In other words
Speaker 14: With this feature
Speaker 14: In other worlds
I love you
Speaker 10: When Misada was promoted to Major, Shinji begins to learn about her personal vendetta against the Angels.
Speaker 10: Then it's up to the Eva team to stop the largest and most dangerous Angel yet!
Speaker 10: The size of this creature alone makes many abandon all hope, and that's before it unveils its
Speaker 7: terrifying new weapon!