YEAR 2000, ANTARCTICA
Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
EPISODE 21
NERV IS BORN
YEAR 1999, KYOTO
Metaphysical Biology Research Room 1 Fuyutsuki
BACK IN THE YEAR 2015
BACK IN THE YEAR 1999
Kyoto Prefecture Police Department
YEAR 2000, ANTARCTICA
YEAR 2001
YEAR 2002
RUINS OF TOYOHASHI CITY, AICHI PREFECTURE
SAME YEAR, ANTARCTICA
We're Married
Gendo & Yui
Ikari
It has been
a long time.
Are you doing well?
Gendo & Yui
Ikari
It has been
a long time.
Are you doing well?
SAFETY FIRST
YEAR 2015
NERV HEADQUARTERS - ISOLATION FACILITY 4
YEAR 2002
SOUTH POLE INVESTIGATION SHIP - ISOLATION FACILITY 2
United Nations Moves Headquarters to Japan
In Five Years, Candidate is New Tokyo-2
Second Impact Caused by a Massive Meteor
Impossible to Predict or Avoid
Probability of Once in Every Several
Hundred Million Years
Official United Nations Statement
At 20-30% of the Speed of Light
YEAR 2003, HAKONE
UNITED NATIONS ARTIFICIAL EVOLUTION LABORATORY
DIRECTOR'S OFFICE
YEAR 2015
YEAR 2005
NEW TOKYO-2, NAGANO PREFECTURE
2ND TOKYO UNIVERSITY, SCHOOL GROUNDS
YEAR 2003
ASHINOKO LAKEFRONT, HAKONE
YEAR 2004
HAKONE - UNDERGROUND LABORATORY 2
YEAR 2008
YEAR 2010
GEOFRONT ARTIFICIAL CANOPY
LOWER LEVEL 2 DIRECT SUPPORT AREA (FUTURE LOCATION)
COMPLETED
YEAR 2015
Play
Messages
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
AT LEAST, BE HUMAN