Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
THE YEAR IS 2015 A.D.
THIRD ANGEL
SACHIEL ATTACKS
ORDINARY WEAPONS PROVE
INEFFECTIVE AGAINST THE ANGEL
THE OPERATION IS ABANDONED
BY THE MILITARY
TRANSFERS ALL COMMAND TO
SPECIAL DUTY ORGANIZATION "NERV"
LATE THAT NIGHT,
THE ANGEL ARRIVES DIRECTLY
ABOVE NERV HEADQUARTERS
SEIZED THAT DAY WAS
THIRD CHILD
THE THIRD QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL
SHINJI IKARI
ACCEPTS PILOTING DUTY
EVANGELION UNIT 01
FIRST LAUNCH
NERV EXPERIENCES ITS FIRST ACTUAL BATTLE
FIRST DIRECTLY-OVERHEAD ENCOUNTER
EVA UNIT 01, CRANIAL AREA DAMAGED,
RENDERED INOPERABLE
COMPLETE SILENCE
THEN,
LOSS OF CONTROL
"New Tokyo-3 Urban Combat"
Interim Report
Person in Charge
Chief of Operations Captain Misato Katsuragi
AND WITH THE THIRD ANGEL AND UNIT 01
THE CONFIRMATION OF AN AT FIELD
UNIT 01 ERODES TARGET'S AT FIELD
ANGEL DESTROYED
COUNTERATTACK FACILITIES PARTIALLY DAMAGED
EVA UNIT-01 MODERATELY DAMAGED
EXISTENCE OF VICTIMS OF THIS INCIDENT
NEVER PUBLICIZED
Excerpt from Toji Suzuhara's essay
FOURTH ANGEL
SHAMSHEL ATTACKS
AT THE TIME, GROUND-TO-AIR INTERCEPT SYSTEM
OPERATING AT 48.2%
NEW TOKYO-3
96.8% SWITCHED TO BATTLE CONFIGURATION
Hikari Horiki's note (partial)
ANGEL ARRIVES IN NEW TOKYO-3 AIRSPACE
SECOND DIRECTLY-OVERHEAD ENCOUNTER
SUFFERS ACCIDENT, DISCONNECTED FROM
EXTERNAL POWER SOURCE, HOWEVER...
ANGEL DESTROYED
NERV OBTAINS ANGEL SAMPLE
STILL IN ORIGINAL SHAPE
HOWEVER, A FINAL REPORT ON THE
ANALYSIS RESULTS HAS YET TO BE FILED
FIFTH ANGEL
RAMIEL ATTACKS
AGAINST THIS IMPREGNABLE TARGET,
CAPTAIN KATSURAGI PROPOSES
OPERATION YASHIMA, WHICH IS APPROVED
FIRST CHILD
FIRST QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL
DESIGNATED PILOT OF EVA UNIT 00
REI AYANAMI
LAUNCHES FOR THE FIRST TIME IN EVA
UNIT 00 RELEASED FROM CRYOGENIC FREEZE
LATE THAT NIGHT, A PART OF THE ANGEL
INVADES THE GEO-FRONT
NERV DECISIVELY EXECUTES
OPERATION YASHIMA
Excerpt from Kensuke Aida's personal materials
OPERATION YASHIMA EXECUTED
SUCCESSFULLY
EVA UNIT 00 HEAVILY DAMAGED
HOWEVER, PILOT RETURNS SAFELY
SIXTH ANGEL
ENCOUNTER WITH GAGHIEL
SECOND CHILD
SECOND QUALIFIED INDIVIDUAL
DESIGNATED PILOT OF EVA UNIT 02
ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
FIRST LAUNCH ABOARD EVA UNIT 02
CLOSE QUARTERS COMBAT AT SEA
AND
FIRST UNDERWATER BATTLE
IN AN ENGAGEMENT OFF THE SHORE OF OLD LTOH
ANGEL DESTROYED
SEVENTH ANGEL
ISRAFEL ATTACKS
FIRST ANGEL TO USE DIVIDING
AND MERGING ABILITIES
HOWEVER, WITH THE HEAVY SIMULTANEOUS
2-POINT ATTACK BY EVA UNIT 01 AND UNIT 02
ANGEL DESTROYED
EIGHTH ANGEL
SANDALPHON DISCOVERED
WITHIN MT. ASAMA CRATER
NERV ISSUES ORDER A-17
PRIORITIZED ABOVE ALL ELSE, THE FIRST
CAPTURE OPERATION IS DEPLOYED
CONFINED BRIEFLY IN THE ELECTROMAGNETIC
OPTICAL WAVE ENCLOSURE,
BUT...
THE ELECTROMAGNETIC MEMBRANE IS TORN TO
SHREDS AND THE OPERATION IS INTERRUPTED
OPERATION OBJECTIVE IS IMMEDIATELY
CHANGED TO DESTROYING THE ANGEL
EVA UNIT 02 EXECUTES OPERATION
ANGEL DESTROYED
EVA UNIT-00 RESTORED FROM DAMAGE
AND MODIFICATION WORK COMPLETE
BACK ON DUTY
NINTH ANGEL
MATARAEL ATTACKS
THE FIRST OPERATION WITH ALL THREE EVAS
DEPLOYED AT THE SAME TIME
ANGEL DESTROYED
TENTH ANGEL
SAHAQUIEL ATTACKS
AGAINST THE TARGET FLYING IN
FROM THE STRATOSPHERE
THROUGH DIRECT INTERCEPTION BY THE 3 EVAS
ANGEL DESTROYED
ELEVENTH ANGEL
FACTS CONCERNING THE ATTACK
ARE CURRENTLY UNCONFIRMED
WILD RUMOR OF A DIRECT INVASION
OF NERV HEADQUARTERS
HUMAN INSTRUMENTALITY COMMITTEE
SPECIAL MEETING CONVENED
CHAPTER FOURTEEN
SEELE, THRONE OF SOULS
FIRST UNIT INTERCHANGEABILITY TEST
SUBJECT REI AYANAMI
87TH UNIT LINK-UP TEST
SUBJECT ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
FIRST UNIT INTERCHANGEABILITY TEST
SUBJECT SHINJI IKARI
Knight
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
LIES AND SILENCE