Speaker 1: As a poor man, like a young man,
Speaker 1: you will be a man.
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now
Speaker 1: Even though I'm just looking at
Speaker 1: The back of the back of the world is
Speaker 1: "You are a
Speaker 2: me anyway, do you? Using that as an excuse is no different than running away.
Speaker 3: What you truly fear
Speaker 3: is failure, isn't it? You fear that you may be hated by others. You fear acknowledging that
Speaker 3: weakness even to yourself.
Speaker 2: How can you criticize
Speaker 3: me when you do the same thing? You're right. At
Speaker 3: the core, we are all the same. Our minds lack something basic. And we fear that lack. And that
Speaker 3: is why we are attempting to become one. We will meld with and fill each other. This is the
Speaker 3: Instrumentality.
Speaker 4: Mankind cannot live without being surrounded by others.
Speaker 4: Mankind cannot live alone.
Speaker 3: Although you yourself are always unique.
Speaker 4: That is why life is hard.
Speaker 3: That is why life is sad and empty.
Speaker 3: Thus you want the close physical and mental presence of others.
Speaker 3: That is why we wish to become one.
Speaker 4: The human soul is made of weak and fragile
Speaker 5: elements.
Speaker 5: The body
Speaker 3: and mind are made of brittle components as well.
Speaker 5: And so, via the instrumentality, mankind must fill and complement each other.
Speaker 5: Must you ask? Because there's no other way to exist.
Why do you exist?
Speaker 3: Maybe I exist to find out why I exist.
Speaker 3: For whom do you exist?
Speaker 3: For myself, of course.
Speaker 3: Maybe for myself.
Speaker 3: Are you happy being alive?
Speaker 2: I don't know.
Speaker 3: Of course I'm happy!
Speaker 3: Are you happy being alive?
Speaker 3: I don't want to do anything except be happy.
Speaker 4: Do you hate being sad?
Speaker 6: I don't like it.
Speaker 4: Do you hate enduring pain?
Speaker 3: I don't like it.
Speaker 5: Is that why you run away?
Speaker 3: Yes. Do you blame me?
Speaker 3: What's wrong with running away from something that hurts?
Speaker 3: I mustn't run away.
Speaker 3: Tell me why you mustn't run away.
Speaker 3: Because escaping from reality can be painful.
Speaker 3: Even though you're running from something more painful.
Speaker 3: I couldn't bear it.
Speaker 3: As long as you know what the pain is, it can be endured.
Speaker 3: That's correct.
Speaker 3: If the pain is too harsh, you can escape it.
Speaker 3: If you really hate it, Shinji, you can still run.
Speaker 2: No, I won't. I'm
Speaker 3: tired of escaping.
Speaker 3: Yes, I mustn't run
Speaker 1: away.
Speaker 3: That is true. That is because you are now aware that running only brings you more pain.
Speaker 3: This is because running away can be far worse.
Speaker 3: That's why you do not wish to escape.
Speaker 2: Because if you run away, nobody will respect you.
Speaker 2: Don't leave me alone.
Speaker 2: Don't deserve me. I'm begging you.
Speaker 2: There he goes again, depending upon others who do everything for him.
Speaker 2: That's a sad survival mechanism, isn't it?
Speaker 2: So what? It's better than being left all alone.
Speaker 2: Because you fear being hurt.
Speaker 2: You try to make
Speaker 3: yourself believe that,
Speaker 7: don't you?
Speaker 8: You're not the only one who gets hurt, Shinji.
Speaker 8: Everybody feels pain. You aren't the only one.
Speaker 7: It's just easier for you to think that it's true, isn't it?
Speaker 7: Shut up! I don't care!
Speaker 7: Why should
Speaker 3: I? Nobody cares about me!
Speaker 3: Once again, you've abandoned all sense of self-value, of self-worth.
Speaker 3: I have nothing.
Speaker 3: There you
Speaker 1: go again, saying
Speaker 3: that you have no worth at all.
Speaker 3: Do you believe that by not expecting anything, you won't get hurt either?
Speaker 3: Is that how you sustain your pathetic ego, by asking others to praise you?
Speaker 2: Nobody accepts me.
Speaker 3: That's not true. You just believe that is so.
Speaker 3: And so that's why I must pilot the Ava.
Speaker 3: Again, that is merely your point of view.
Speaker 3: You've been trying to convince yourself that you're worthless since the very beginning.
Speaker 3: But I have to! I've got to do it!
Speaker 8: No, that's not true.
Speaker 8: You don't have to.
Speaker 8: No, you just think you do.
Speaker 8: No, you're wrong.
Speaker 2: My life is pointless otherwise.
Speaker 2: And that's why you pilot the Ava?
Speaker 2: Piloting Ava gives me an identity. A purpose.
Speaker 2: I had no value before I became a pilot.
Speaker 2: The fact that I now pilot an Ava justifies my presence here.
Speaker 2: I have no other
Speaker 3: value.
Speaker 3: I have no other value.
Speaker 2: I have no other value, no other value at all.
Speaker 2: I perceive no value in myself.
Speaker 2: I hate myself!
YOU LILTLE WORM! I HATE YOU!
Speaker 8: I HATE YOU!
Speaker 8: Me, too.
Speaker 8: I hate you, too.
Speaker 8: I hate everything about you!
Speaker 3: I'm sorry but...
Speaker 3: I HATE YOU!
Speaker 3: I
Speaker 4: hate you, I hate you.
Speaker 9: I hate everything about you,
Speaker 4: I hate you.
Speaker 9: Oh Shinji, I hate you.
Speaker 2: See? Everyone hates me!
Speaker 2: Every person in existence must hate me!
Speaker 2: No, that's just what you imagine.
Speaker 2: Yes! But that must be it, because I hate myself!
Speaker 3: Because you hate yourself, no one respects you.
Speaker 3: I hate
you! I hate you! I hate everything!
Speaker 2: But they praise me. They're nice to me.
Speaker 2: When I pilot the Eva, they treat me better.
Speaker 2: Other people are being nice to me for the first time.
Speaker 2: Which is your true feeling?
Speaker 2: I don't know. Or is it perhaps that both are my true feelings?
Speaker 2: So that's why you pilot the Ava?
Speaker 2: Because I have no choice. I only have the Ava.
Speaker 2: Otherwise,
Speaker 3: you could not retain your own identity.
Speaker 3: In fact, Ava Unit 1 is part of your sense of being.
Speaker 3: But if you depend only on the Ava, then the Ava will become your only identifier.
Speaker 8: Ava will become your only value.
Speaker 3: Without that value, you, the real you, will be erased from this existence.
Speaker 2: I don't care! I had no other value to start with anyway!
Speaker 2: I was learning to play the cello, but that didn't help me either!
Speaker 3: You just didn't discipline yourself! I didn't have to do that!
Speaker 2: But now that I can pilot the Ava...
Speaker 2: No. Soon you may lose your identity,
Speaker 3: as I have. Soon you may lose Ava and your self-worth.
Speaker 2: I pilot it
Speaker 3: because that's all I can
Speaker 2: do.
Speaker 6: Rain.
Speaker 6: Dark shadows of gloom hang above me.
Speaker 6: That's how I feel.
Speaker 6: This isn't how I want it to be.
Speaker 3: This is not the ending of love.
Speaker 3: This is not how I wish it to be.
Speaker 6: Morning.
Speaker 3: The beginning of a day.
Speaker 3: Another terrible day.
Speaker 3: I wish this wasn't the way it is.
Speaker 2: The sky. Something warm. Something unfamiliar. Something that fills me with horror.
Speaker 2: I don't want this. I don't want it to be this way.
Speaker 2: I hate everything!
Speaker 2: What do you want, Shinji?
Speaker 3: What do you want, Shinji?
Speaker 3: Don't
hate me, please!
Speaker 3: What I fear is...
Speaker 3: What I want
Speaker 2: is...
Speaker 2: Can I stay next to you?
Speaker 2: May I stay here?
Speaker 3: Do you like me?
Speaker 3: Do you want to go where your mother is?
Speaker 3: No.
Speaker 3: Don't you want to go be with your father?
Speaker 2: No, I don't.
Speaker 3: Why?
Speaker 3: Because I'm afraid of being hated.
Speaker 3: Because my identity might start to disappear.
Speaker 3: What is it that you wish for?
Speaker 3: What is it that you want?
Speaker 2: You're very insecure, aren't you?
Speaker 2: To become secure, I have to have...
Speaker 2: Value!
Speaker 2: I want to be worth something!
Speaker 2: I want to be worth enough to attract the attention of others!
Speaker 10: But your value is something you have to find for yourself.
Speaker 10: You have to find it, Genji.
Speaker 2: I have no value without it.
Speaker 2: My life is worthless without it.
Speaker 3: Then what am I?
Speaker 2: Then what am I?
Speaker 3: What am
Speaker 11: I?
Speaker 2: Wait, what is this? This is me. This is the shape that lets others recognize me as myself.
Speaker 2: It is my symbol for myself. This is, this is, and this is as well. Representations. Everything is
Speaker 2: merely a description, not the real myself. Everything is simply a shape, a form, an identifier to let
Speaker 2: others recognize me as me. But then, what am I? Is this me? My true self? My fake self? What is it
Speaker 2: that I am?
Speaker 3: You are you. There is little difference between how
Speaker 2: you interpret yourself and how the
Speaker 2: others interpret you. Right. My clothes, my shoes, my room. These are all parts of what makes up
Speaker 2: myself. These things are connected through your consciousness. So what I think is me is me. What
Speaker 2: I recognize as self is myself. I'm no more and no less than the sum of my self-awareness,
Speaker 2: but I don't understand myself. Where am I? What am I?
Speaker 2: Nobody understands
Speaker 11: me!
Speaker 3: What are you, stupid? Of course nobody understands you!
Speaker 3: Nobody can ever understand you!
Speaker 3: The only one who can take care of you and understand you is... you, yourself.
Speaker 3: So you must take care of yourself.
Speaker 2: But I still don't understand myself! I don't even know what it is that makes me myself!
Speaker 2: How could I love myself?!
Speaker 3: You are still unstable.
Speaker 3: That is, the present you.
Speaker 3: And the people around the present you.
Speaker 3: And the environment that surrounds the present you.
Speaker 3: None of these elements of reality last forever.
Speaker 3: Time continues to flow, and time brings change.
Speaker 3: Your world is in a state of constant change.
Speaker 3: You're capable of change any time your mind perceives these changes.
Speaker 2: What is this?
Speaker 2: A world of nothing?
Speaker 2: A world with nobody in it?
Speaker 2: This is the world of perfect freedom.
Speaker 2: Freedom?
Speaker 2: Perfect
freedom. A world in which you have no restriction.
Speaker 3: Is this really freedom?
Speaker 3: Yes. This is what it is.
Speaker 3: However, this world has nothing in it.
Speaker 2: Unless I do something?
Speaker 3: Right. Unless you do or think of something.
Speaker 3: But I don't know what to do or think of.
Speaker 3: He is uncertain.
Speaker 3: He has no self-image to orient himself.
Speaker 3: There's nothing solid here.
Speaker 3: It is a world in which there are no obstacles, no anything.
Speaker 3: And yet, you are still afraid, aren't you?
Speaker 3: What should I do?
Speaker 5: Let me give you a restriction.
Speaker 3: There. Now you have a top and bottom.
Speaker 3: But you have lost a degree of your freedom.
Speaker 3: You may no longer fly. You must stand upon the earth.
Speaker 5: But now you feel easier, don't you?
Speaker 5: Because you have less to trouble your mind.
Speaker 5: And now you can walk.
Speaker 9: This is happening because you will it to be.
Speaker 9: Is this my will?
Speaker 9: This world with the floor is the only thing around yourself.
Speaker 8: But now you can move around anywhere you wish to within it.
Speaker 8: You could even turn the world upside down if you wanted to do that.
Speaker 3: And your perspective within your world is constantly changing.
Speaker 8: It changes with the
Speaker 5: passage of time.
Speaker 5: Because the thing that forms your shape is your mind
Speaker 5: and its interaction with the world that surrounds you.
Speaker 2: You can do anything here, because this is your world.
Speaker 2: This
is the shape of reality.
Reality.
Speaker 2: What is this?
Speaker 2: An empty space?
Speaker 2: An empty world?
Speaker 2: A world where nothing exists but myself?
Speaker 2: But with only myself, I have nothing to interact with.
Speaker 2: It's as if I'm here, but not here at all.
Speaker 2: It's as if I'm slowly fading out of existence.
Speaker 2: Because only you are here.
Speaker 2: Only myself?
Speaker 2: Without others to interact with, you cannot truly recognize your own image.
Speaker 2: My own image?
Speaker 3: That's right. In the act of observing others, you may find and recognize yourself.
Speaker 3: Your self-image is restrained by having to observe the barriers between yourself and others.
Speaker 3: And yet, you cannot see yourself without the presence of others.
Speaker 2: Because there are others, I can perceive myself as an individual.
Speaker 2: If I am alone, then I will be the same without others.
Speaker 2: For
Speaker 3: if this world is only of me, then there will be no difference between me and nothing!
Speaker 3: By recognizing the differences between yourself and others, you establish your identity as yourself.
Speaker 3: Your mother
Speaker 2: is
Speaker 3: a different individual.
Speaker 2: Right. I am me and she is she.
Speaker 2: But are you really sure that the perceptions of others form my true self?
Speaker 3: Has it taken you this long to realize that?
Speaker 3: What an idiot!
Speaker 3: Huh?
Speaker 3: It's about time you got up, you idiot.
Speaker 6: Oh, it's you, Asuka.
Speaker 3: What the hell does that mean?
Speaker 3: Can't you appreciate that I went to the trouble of coming
Speaker 3: to wake you up personally?
Speaker 3: I don't hear any words of appreciation
Speaker 3: for your oldest childhood friend.
Speaker 2: Oh, thanks.
Speaker 2: Let me sleep a little more.
Speaker 2: Hey,
Speaker 3: get up, you!
Speaker 3: It's time to get up, you dark!
Speaker 12: You stupid bird!
Speaker 12: I didn't mean to get that up!
Speaker 12: I can't help it.
Speaker 12: It's morning.
Speaker 12: I gotta take a whiz or something.
Speaker 10: Oh, my.
Speaker 10: Oscar's so sweet to come pick him up every morning,
Speaker 10: and he doesn't appreciate it.
Speaker 5: Hmm.
Speaker 5: Is that so, dear?
Speaker 10: Yes, dear.
Speaker 10: And you have to get ready, too.
Speaker 5: I'm always ready, dear.
Speaker 10: Gosh, you are just like Shinji.
Speaker 5: Mm-hmm. You ready?
Speaker 10: Anytime.
Speaker 10: I am the one who gets complaints from Professor Fuyutsuki if you're late for the meeting.
Speaker 5: That's true. He's your biggest fan.
Speaker 5: Oh,
Speaker 10: you? Cut that out and
Speaker 12: get ready.
Speaker 5: Yes, dear. She who must be obeyed.
Speaker 12: Hurry up!
Speaker 12: Jeez, you're such a pain in the ass sometimes.
Speaker 12: Is this what happens when you start your period?
Speaker 12: What?
Speaker 3: What did you say?
Speaker 3: Ow!
Speaker 3: Mrs. Zucari, we're leaving now.
Speaker 3: Uh, see you later, Mom.
Speaker 3: See you, sweetie.
Speaker 3: Come
Speaker 10: on, dear. Put the newspaper down.
Speaker 10: Uh,
Speaker 8: all
Speaker 3: right.
Speaker 3: Hey, isn't a new student starting today?
Speaker 3: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 3: Since this city's going to become the new capital,
Speaker 3: There are a lot of people moving in.
Speaker 3: It's no wonder we're getting so many new kids.
Speaker 3: - That makes sense.
Speaker 3: I wonder what she's like.
Speaker 3: Oh, I hope she's got a great butt.
Speaker 3: - Oh crap, I'm late.
Speaker 3: I can't be late for the first day.
Speaker 11: I'm sorry! I'm really in a hurry, kid!
Speaker 11: I'm really sorry!
Speaker 11: Bye, dear!
Speaker 3: Wow! So did you
Speaker 2: see her panties then?
Speaker 2: Well, it wasn't a good look really.
Speaker 2: Just a little flash.
Speaker 8: Oh! I can't believe it that you're the one who has all the luck!
Speaker 8: What'd you do that for?
Speaker 7: Exactly what were you just talking about, Mr. Suzuhara?
Speaker 7: It's time to put that idle butt of yours to work!
Speaker 7: Change the water in the flower vases!
Speaker 7: Oh, she's
Speaker 3: mean!
Speaker 7: Did you just say something?
Speaker 2: Poor Toji's so carpet-bagged.
Speaker 2: It's sad, isn't it?
Speaker 2: Look who's talking.
Speaker 2: Hey, are you saying that I'm...
Speaker 2: I'm merely reporting the fact.
Speaker 1: How so?
Speaker 1: It
Speaker 2: just
Speaker 3: is! Accept it!
Speaker 3: Hey, why do you treat me like this?
Speaker 3: Hey, that hurts, you idiot!
Speaker 3: Ow,
Speaker 8: Stan!
Speaker 8: The calm, the peace and tranquility.
Speaker 8: *Bang*
*Bang*
Speaker 3: Oh yeah!
Speaker 13: Miss Residdle our teacher!
Speaker 3: Oh, she's gorgeous!
Speaker 3: Wow!
Speaker 3: Oh yeah! Oh yeah! Look at that!
Speaker 13: Oh! She just... the best!
Speaker 13: Oh yeah!
Speaker 3: Just look at those three stooges!
Speaker 3: Have they no shame!
Speaker 3: *Bang*
Speaker 3: Listen up dudes, we've got a new blue haired babe here to introduce herself.
Speaker 3: My name's Rei Ayanami. How's it hanging?
Speaker 3: No!
Speaker 3: You're the jerk who was staring at my panties!
Speaker 3: Hey! What do you mean by that? You're the one who was flashing them, you know.
Speaker 3: Who are you and why are you defending him? Are you riding his baloney pony?
Speaker 13: No!
Speaker 3: We're just really good childhood friends! You shut up!
Speaker 3: Be quiet you two, we're in a class, not a bar.
Speaker 3: Hey, this is more entertaining than class.
Speaker 3: Go on, I want to see how this turns out.
Speaker 3: Hey, Shinji, you didn't
Speaker 8: tell me you were
Speaker 3: getting it with Asuka.
Speaker 2: I see.
Speaker 2: So this is another possibility.
Speaker 2: Another possible reality.
Speaker 2: This current myself is the same way.
Speaker 2: It's not the true myself.
Speaker 2: I can be any way I wish to be.
Speaker 2: I see.
Speaker 2: And myself, who is not an Ava pilot, can exist as well.
Speaker 2: If you take that into consideration,
Speaker 2: then perhaps this world isn't that bad.
Speaker 2: Still, the reality itself might not be bad,
Speaker 2: but I could still hate myself.
Speaker 8: But it's your mind which takes reality and separates it
Speaker 8: into what's bad and hateful.
Speaker 8: It is only the mind which separates reality from truth.
Speaker 9: Any new position from which you view your reality
Speaker 9: will change your perception of its nature.
Speaker 9: It's all literally a matter of perspective.
Speaker 3: There are as many
Speaker 4: truths as
Speaker 8: there are people.
Speaker 8: But there's only one truth that is your truth.
Speaker 8: That's the one that's formed from whatever point of view
Speaker 8: to view it from. It's a revised perception that protects you.
Speaker 8: That's true, and one can have a perspective that's far too small.
Speaker 3: However, a person can only see things from the perspective that they choose to see them from.
Speaker 3: One must learn to judge things via the perceived truths that one receives from others.
Speaker 3: For example, sunny days make you feel good.
Speaker 3: Rainy days make you feel gloomy.
Speaker 3: If you are told this is so, then that is what you believe is so.
Speaker 3: But you can have fun on a rainy day as well.
Speaker 4: Your truth can be changed simply by the way you accept it.
Speaker 4: That's how fragile the truth for a human is.
Speaker 5: A person's truth is so simple that most ignore it to concentrate on what they think are deeper truths.
Speaker 5: You, for example, are simply unused to what it is to be liked by others.
Speaker 3: You've never learned how to deal with fearing what others feel about you, and so you avoid it.
Speaker 3: But... don't the others hate me?
Speaker 3: What are you, stupid? Haven't you realized it's all in your imagination, you mega-dork?
Speaker 2: But I hate myself.
Speaker 3: One who truly hates himself cannot love. He cannot place his trust in another.
Speaker 2: I'm a coward. I'm cowardly, sneaky, and weak.
Speaker 2: No. Only if you think you are, but if you know yourself, you can take care of yourself.
Speaker 2: I hate myself.
Speaker 2: But maybe I could love myself.
Speaker 2: Maybe my life could have a greater value.
Speaker 2: That's right.
Speaker 2: I am no more or less than myself.
Speaker 2: I am me.
Speaker 2: I want to be myself.
Speaker 2: I want to continue existing in this world.
Speaker 2: My life is worth living here.
Speaker 11: Yay!
Speaker 11: You're the best!
Speaker 3: Congratulations!
Speaker 2: Thank you all!
Speaker 11: I'm
not alone.
Speaker 11: In other words, truly kiss me
Speaker 11: Feel my heart with song
Speaker 11: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 11: You are all I long for
Speaker 11: All I want, sit and adore
Speaker 11: In other words
Speaker 11: Please be true
I love you