Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I just saw you
Speaker 1: I'm smiling
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to see you
Speaker 1: I'm still not sure
Speaker 1: I'm not sure
Speaker 1: But I'll see you soon
Speaker 1: I'm so excited to see you next time.
Speaker 2: Fuck me! I'm so glad I'm going shopping with you, Kaji!
Speaker 3: Hey, wait a second. Isn't this the swimsuit section?
Speaker 2: That's right! What do you think of this one?
Speaker 3: Um, aren't you just a little young to be wearing something like that, Asuka?
Speaker 2: Oh, come on, Kaji. This is what all the girls are wearing.
Speaker 3: Oh, really?
Speaker 2: Uh-huh. Oh, I'm so anxious about this school trip. I just know we'll have a great time.
Speaker 3: So, where is your class going?
Speaker 2: Okinawa! It's gonna be awesome! We're even gonna go scuba diving!
Speaker 3: Scuba diving, huh? Boy, it's been years since the last time I went diving.
Speaker 2: Hey, where'd you go for your school trip, Kaji?
Speaker 3: Well, actually, we didn't have one.
Speaker 2: Why is that?
Speaker 3: Just a little thing called the second impact.
Speaker 2: What? Did you just think I can't go on the trip?
Speaker 4: Yep.
Speaker 4: Well, why not?
Speaker 4: It's part of your job.
Speaker 4: You mean I'm on permanent standby?
Speaker 4: You got it.
Speaker 4: What idiot decided that?
Speaker 4: This one. The operations planning manager.
Speaker 2: Shinji, why don't you stop hiding behind that cup of tea
Speaker 2: and talk some sense into this woman.
Speaker 2: Act like a man.
Speaker 5: Well, you know, actually, I had kind of expected
Speaker 5: that we wouldn't be allowed to go.
Speaker 5: So you've already given
Speaker 4: up.
Speaker 1: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 4: Huh, pathetic.
Speaker 4: There's nothing more useless than a housebroken male.
Speaker 1: Hey, don't talk about me like that.
Speaker 4: Look, I know how you must feel,
Speaker 4: but there's just no other way.
Speaker 4: There's always the possibility
Speaker 4: that an angel might attack while you're away.
Speaker 4: So I
Speaker 2: get stuck here on standby status
Speaker 2: while everyone else is having fun?
Speaker 2: Why is it that we're the ones
Speaker 2: who always have to be ready to defend against them.
Speaker 2: Any good officer knows that the best defense is a good offense.
Speaker 2: Why can't we find them and attack them first?
Speaker 2: - If we could
Speaker 4: do that, we would do it.
Speaker 4: Look, think of this as an opportunity
Speaker 4: to get ahead for a change.
Speaker 4: The two of you can catch up on your studies
Speaker 4: while the rest of your classmates are on the trip.
Speaker 4: Or did you think I hadn't seen these report cards?
Speaker 4: I guess you thought I wouldn't know
Speaker 4: about your test scores yet.
Speaker 4: Well, all of your grades are forwarded directly
Speaker 4: to my terminal and I have been very disappointed
Speaker 4: with the both of you.
Speaker 4: - Ah, this is so silly and this school's grades
Speaker 4: are just dumb.
Speaker 4: The old fashioned numeric grading scale you use
Speaker 4: on your exams is stupid.
Speaker 4: - In Rome, do as the Romans do.
Speaker 4: You could at least try to adjust to Japanese school life.
Speaker 6: - This sucks!
Speaker 6: - Hey Asuka, I'll bring you back something
Speaker 2: nice.
Speaker 2: - Sayonara suckers.
Speaker 2: - Hey, don't worry.
Speaker 2: enough fun for the both of you!
Speaker 7: Post the survey data on Mount Asimel from Balthazar
Speaker 7: to Melchior as soon as possible.
Speaker 8: A school trip, huh?
Speaker 8: That sounds pretty reckless in times like these.
Speaker 4: I guess the idea is to let all the kids
Speaker 4: have time to get out and act like kids while they can.
Speaker 4: *BOOM
*
Speaker 2: Hmm, what have you got there, Shinji?
Speaker 5: Basic physics primer.
Speaker 5: Oh,
Speaker 2: you're such an obedient student.
Speaker 1: Well, I'll have to study it anyway. I mean, I...
Speaker 2: Well, if I can't go diving in Okinawa, let's do it here.
Speaker 2: Do what?
Speaker 2: Diving, of course.
Speaker 2: So what are you working on?
Speaker 2: Let's see.
Speaker 2: You can't solve an easy problem like this?
Speaker 2: There, all done.
Speaker 2: It's easy when you know how.
Speaker 6: How can you solve a difficult problem like this and not make good grades on your tests?
Speaker 2: It's because I'm having too much trouble figuring out what the questions are.
Speaker 2: You mean you can't read the questions in Japanese?
Speaker 2: That's right. I still haven't learned all of the kanji yet.
Speaker 2: I didn't have to study it in college.
Speaker 2: You went to college?
Speaker 2: Yeah, I graduated last year.
Speaker 2: So, what does this one say?
Speaker 2: It's a question about
Speaker 7: thermal expansion.
Speaker 2: Thermal expansion? Oh man, that's kid stuff.
Speaker 2: To put it in terms you'll understand, most things expand when they get hot and contract when they get cold.
Speaker 2: Well, it sounds
Speaker 1: simple enough.
Speaker 1: Look,
Speaker 2: if I were to warm up my breasts with my hands, do you think they'd grow bigger or smaller?
Speaker 2: I don't know. I don't think about things like that.
Speaker 2: Such a boring little boy.
Speaker 2: Oh.
Speaker 2: Hurry!
Speaker 9: This just isn't clear enough.
Speaker 9: But the report from the Mount Asuma Earthquake Research Lab
Speaker 9: implies we should take a closer look at this shadow.
Speaker 9: We can't ignore it.
Speaker 9: What
Speaker 8: do the Magi say?
Speaker 5: It's 50/50 odds.
Speaker 9: Who's up there?
Speaker 9: Katsuragi has already arrived at the site.
Speaker 9: Ma'am, you're going too deep?
Speaker 4: Thin the probe down another 500.
Speaker 4: Depth, 1200.
Speaker 4: The pressure-resistant partition is cracking.
Speaker 4: That's Katsuragi.
Speaker 4: If it breaks, we'll pay for the damage.
Speaker 4: 200 more, please.
Speaker 5: We're monitoring a reaction.
Speaker 4: Start analysis.
Speaker 5: Right.
Speaker 4: The probe has imploded due to the extreme pressure.
Speaker 4: Did you get it?
Speaker 10: Just barely. The pattern is blue.
Speaker 4: Then there's no doubt. It's an angel.
Speaker 4: This laboratory is now under the jurisdiction of Nerve.
Speaker 4: There will be no unauthorized phone calls.
Speaker 4: Any access to the outside world is prohibited, and all records pertaining to these events will be classified top secret.
Speaker 4: Katsuragi here. I need an A-17 from Commander Ikari, top priority.
Speaker 9: Watch what you're saying, Captain. This isn't a secure line.
Speaker 4: I know that. Switch me to a scramble line immediately.
Speaker 4: An A-17? You want to make an offensive attack?
Speaker 4: That is correct.
Speaker 4: No, it's too dangerous. Have you forgotten
Speaker 11: what happened 15 years ago?
Speaker 11: No, but consider this. This is our chance to move from a state of perpetual defense to an offensive posture.
Speaker 11: The risk would be enormous.
Speaker 11: However, I'm sure that you must be aware of how important it is to obtain a living angel as a sample, am I correct?
Speaker 11: We will not tolerate failure.
Speaker 9: Failure. If we fail, it will result in the extinction of the entire human race.
Speaker 9: Are you really going to do it, Commander?
Speaker 8: Is that an angel?
Speaker 8: Yes, it's some sort of chrysalis form that precedes the adult stage we're familiar with.
Speaker 8: This operation's prime objective will be to capture this angel.
Speaker 8: We must capture it alive and in a form as close to its original state as possible.
Speaker 8: And if we fail?
Speaker 8: Then you must destroy it immediately.
Speaker 8: Understood?
Speaker 8: Roger!
Speaker 8: The designated pilot
Speaker 2: will be...
Speaker 2: Oh, take me, please! I love to go
Speaker 8: diving!
Speaker 8: It's going to be me,
Speaker 1: as always.
Speaker 2: Asuka.
Speaker 8: Huh?
Speaker 8: You will carry out the mission.
Speaker 2: Sure! It's gonna be
Speaker 8: easy!
Speaker 8: And me?
Speaker 8: The special equipment we'll be using hasn't been standardized for use in the prototype.
Speaker 8: Ray and Unit Zero will remain here on standby.
Speaker 8: I see.
Speaker 8: Oh, poor
Speaker 2: little Ray. She doesn't get to have any fun.
Speaker 8: Now that an A-17 has been ordered, we've got to roll out immediately. Get ready.
Speaker 8: Roger.
Speaker 2: Huh? You know, this heat-resistant entry-plug suit doesn't seem any different from our regular ones.
Speaker 2: Press the switch on your right wrist.
Speaker 2: Okay.
Speaker 2: Oh,
Speaker 8: what?!
I'm
Speaker 2: I'm
Speaker 3: so disappointed.
Speaker 3: I was looking forward to seeing you in action.
Speaker 3: He's there behind
Opa-loopa!
Speaker 2: Dr. Akagi, I just can't let Kashi see me in this awful looking thing!
Speaker 2: Are we having problems down there?
Speaker 8: Sort of, yes.
Speaker 8: Excuse me, but I could...
Speaker 8: I will go in Unit 2.
Speaker 2: Oh no, you don't!
Speaker 2: The only way you're using my Unit 2 is over my dead body!
Speaker 2: I'd rather do it than let her take my place!
Speaker 2: I'm sorry, Leapkin. They made me do it!
Speaker 4: AVA Units 1 and 2 have arrived.
Speaker 4: Have both units stand by. Reposition the laser board and stand ready on the crane.
Speaker 1: Roger.
Speaker 4: Hey,
Speaker 2: is Kaji here yet?
Speaker 4: God's gift won't be coming. He's got no business here.
Speaker 2: No, but I wanted him to see me in my greatest triumph to date.
Speaker 7: An A-17 has been ordered. This will include a freeze of all assets.
Speaker 3: So that means that some people will be in trouble.
Speaker 7: Why didn't you try to stop them?
Speaker 3: I had no way of stopping this. This order was an official one, you know.
Speaker 7: But you must know that if Nerve fails at this, the entire world will perish.
Speaker 3: Don't worry. Not even they are that arrogant.
Speaker 1: What are those jets?
Speaker 8: The UN and the Air Force will be standing by. Until this mission's over, anyway.
Speaker 8: Are they here to help us?
Speaker 8: No. They're here to clean up the mess. Just in case we fail.
Speaker 2: What do you mean?
Speaker 8: They'll use N2 depth charges to destroy the Angel. And us as well.
Speaker 8: This job sucks!
Speaker 8: What kind of
Speaker 10: a jerk would order something like that?
Speaker 8: Commander Ikari.
Huh?
Speaker 5: Laser operation complete.
Speaker 3: The board path has been secured.
Speaker 5: The Type-D equipment is functioning
normally.
Unit 2 is ready and in position.
Speaker 4: Understood. Asuka, are you ready?
Speaker 4: Ready when you are.
Speaker 4: Let's do it!
Speaker 2: Oh man, talk about hot.
Speaker 2: Unit
Speaker 5: two is entering the lava.
Speaker 2: Hey, look at this Shinji.
Speaker 2: Huh?
Speaker 2: A perfect inner dive.
Speaker 2: Depth 170. Rate of descent 20. No problems detected. Visibility is zero.
Speaker 2: I can't see a thing. Switching to CT monitor.
Speaker 2: Even with this I can barely see a thing.
Speaker 5: Depth is 400. 450. 500. 550. 600. 650.
Speaker 5: 900, 950, 1000, 1050.
Speaker 5: We're over the maximum safety depth.
Speaker 5: Depth is 1300.
Speaker 5: Unit has reached estimated target level.
Speaker 4: Asuka, what do you see?
Speaker 4: I'm not detecting anything.
Speaker 4: It's not here.
Speaker 8: The lava currents must be faster than we
Speaker 4: thought.
Speaker 8: The target's velocity certainly doesn't match our predictions.
Speaker 4: Hurry up and recalculate.
Speaker 4: Descend further. Continue the operation.
Speaker 4: Huh?
Speaker 4: Depth is 1350.
1400.
Speaker 4: A crack has occurred on the second coolant pipe.
Speaker 4: Depth is 1480.
Speaker 5: We have exceeded the maximum allowed depth.
Speaker 4: But we haven't made contact with the target yet.
Speaker 4: Keep going.
Speaker 4: How's it going, Asuka?
Speaker 4: Nice and toasty. I just want to finish this and take a shower.
Speaker 4: There's a nice hot spring near here. We'll go there once this is over. Just hang in there a little
Speaker 5: longer.
Speaker 5: Maximum allowed depth plus 120.
Speaker 5: Ava Unit 2 has lost its progressive knife. Maximum allowed depth plus 200.
Speaker 5: Captain Katsuragi, you've got to stop this. Have you
Speaker 4: forgotten that there's a human
Speaker 12: being
Speaker 4: in there?
Speaker 4: I will manage this operation as I see fit. Continue to descend.
Speaker 4: I agree with Misato. I'm okay. I can go on.
Speaker 5: Depth 1780. Unit has reached the corrected target depth.
Speaker 5: Wait. I see it.
Speaker 4: The target is
Speaker 3: in sight.
Speaker 13: Prepare for capture.
Speaker 8: All right, because of the convection current that's moving both you and the target, you'll have
Speaker 13: just one chance to make contact.
Speaker 13: I understand. Just leave it to me.
Speaker 9: 30 meters to contact.
Speaker 13: Relative velocity 2.2 on the axis.
Speaker 13: The electromagnetic cage has been spread. No problems detected. The target has been captured.
Speaker 4: Nice work, Asuka.
Speaker 2: The operation is completed. I'm beginning my ascent.
Speaker 2: Oscar, are you alright?
Speaker 2: Well, of course I am. The only thing we have to fear is fear itself. This was easy.
Speaker 2: Man, this isn't an entry plug suit. It's a sauna bath.
Speaker 2: Oh, I just want to go and take a cold shower.
Speaker 8: Sounds like the tension let loose all at once.
Speaker 8: Yeah.
Speaker 8: Were you scared about this operation?
Speaker 8: I sure was.
Speaker 4: Well, yeah.
Speaker 4: If something had gone wrong, it could have been another--
Speaker 8: I know.
Speaker 8: Second impact.
Speaker 8: All over again.
It's going crazy!
Speaker 10: Oh, no!
Speaker 10: It started to hatch!
Speaker 10: It's earlier than we predicted!
Speaker 10: Cage status!
Speaker 10: There's no way it can
Speaker 3: handle this!
Speaker 4: Abort the capture! Jettison the cage!
Speaker 4: Damn!
Speaker 4: We're changing the operation. We've got to destroy that angel.
Speaker 4: Unit 2, prepare for combat!
Speaker 4: Do it, Oscar!
Speaker 4: You got it!
Speaker 2: Damn it! I forgot that I dropped the frog knife!
Speaker 2: The angel!
Speaker 2: Releasing holster!
Speaker 2: It's fast!
Speaker 2: This is no
Speaker 1: good.
Speaker 12: I've
Speaker 2: lost it again.
Speaker 2: And if this lousy visibility wasn't bad enough,
Speaker 2: I'm also too hot in this disgusting suit stuck to my body with sweat.
Speaker 2: This really sucks.
Speaker 4: Asuka!
Speaker 4: We're going to drop you Unit 1's progressive knife.
Speaker 4: Stand ready.
Speaker 4: Understood.
Speaker 4: Huh?
Speaker 4: Oh, jeez!
Speaker 4: Drop it now, Shinji!
Speaker 4: Here it comes!
Speaker 4: 40 seconds to knife arrival.
Speaker 4: The angel is approaching rapidly!
Speaker 12: Fuck off! Go away!
Speaker 12: Hurry up with that thing!
Speaker 12: No! Fall faster!
Speaker 12: What
Speaker 10: the hell?!
Speaker 10: No! How could it open its mouth in molten lava?
Speaker 5: What do you think that thing's built out of?
Speaker 10: *Gasps*
Speaker 10: Of course! The coolant!
Speaker 10: Transfer all of the internal
Speaker 2: coolant pressure to camel number 3! Do it!
Speaker 2: *BANG*
Speaker 2: That's it. I'm done for.
Speaker 2: Shinji!
Speaker 2: Idiot. You show off.
Speaker 14: Hello? Are the people from Nerve here somewhere?
Speaker 5: Yeah, we're here!
Speaker 14: I need your signature here.
Speaker 14: Thank you. Have a nice day.
Speaker 10: It's from Kaji.
Speaker 10: What is this?
Speaker 1: The springs are over that way.
Speaker 1: Ah, this feels
Speaker 5: like heaven.
Speaker 2: Oh, boy, I never thought a bath could feel this good.
Shinji, can you hear me?
Speaker 4: Yes, ma'am!
Speaker 4: Would you be a dear and throw me the body shampoo?
Speaker 4: We ran out of hours!
Speaker 4: Sure.
Speaker 4: Here it comes.
Speaker 2: Roger!
Speaker 4: Ow! You
Speaker 2: idiot!
Speaker 2: What were you throwing, you dark?
Speaker 2: Oh, t-t
Speaker 12: -sorry.
Speaker 2: He hit me in my most
Speaker 4: private part.
Speaker 4: Oh, let me take a look.
Speaker 4: Oh,
Speaker 2: watch your fingers!
Speaker 4: Wow, your skin is so soft and
Speaker 2: smooth, Oscar.
Speaker 2: Don't! You're tickling me!
Speaker 2: How do you like this?
Speaker 4: Oh, don't touch me there!
Speaker 4: Oh, come on, what gives?
Ah!
Speaker 5: Thermal expansion. How embarrassing.
Speaker 4: Hm? Oh, the scar.
Speaker 4: It's something that happened during the second impact.
Speaker 4: You know my past. About everything, don't you?
Speaker 4: Well, it's part of my job.
Speaker 4: It's all ancient history now.
Speaker 4: We really ought to let it go.
Speaker 6: Oh, my God.
Speaker 6: Another one, darling kiss me
Speaker 6: Fill my heart with songs and let me sing forevermore
Speaker 6: You are all I know for all I want, sing another door
Speaker 6: In other words, please be true.
Speaker 6: In other words, I
love you.
Speaker 4: When Sabotage cuts off all the power to Tokyo 3, Nerve HQ is left open to attack by a new angel.
Speaker 4: Without power or any modern support facilities, the three pilots must find a way to launch the Avas and do battle in total darkness.
Speaker 4: Don't miss the next exciting episode!