Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I just saw you just look at
Speaker 1: The world's
*Ejects*
Speaker 2: It's not working! Unit 1's interlock circuit has been cut off!
Speaker 3: What about the eject signal?
Speaker 2: All codes are being blocked from inside the plug!
Speaker 2: It's not being accepted!
Speaker 3: Look! Shinji, if we hadn't taken over, you would have been killed!
Speaker 2: That's not the
Speaker 4: point.
Speaker 3: Maybe, but it's the truth!
Speaker 4: Stop pushing me, dammit! Don't push me anymore!
Speaker 4: Unit 1 has 185 seconds of power left.
Speaker 4: That's enough to destroy at least half of headquarters!
Speaker 5: He'll do it too, the way he is right now.
Speaker 2: Shinji, will you listen to us?
Speaker 2: If the commander hadn't made the decision to engage the dummy plug,
Speaker 2: everyone here could have been killed!
Speaker 2: I said
Speaker 4: that's beside the point, damn you!
Speaker 4: My father tried to kill Toji, and he did it using my hands!
Speaker 4: That bastard!
Father! I know you're there!
Say something! Answer me!
Speaker 5: Increase the entry plug's LCL pressure to its maximum level.
Speaker 6: What?
Speaker 5: I have no time to waste on a petulant child.
Speaker 4: I've still got a
Speaker 7: direct control circuit!
Damn it. Damn you.
Speaker 2: How
Speaker 8: are you?
Speaker 8: I'm not hurt enough to stop doing my job.
Speaker 8: I couldn't lie in bed during an emergency like this.
Speaker 8: So what did they end up doing with Shinji?
Speaker 8: It's my understanding that they had to
Speaker 6: cut the
Speaker 8: escape hatch open
Speaker 9: with a laser cutter and remove him forcibly.
Speaker 10: This sucks. I'm afraid that this time...
Speaker 10: He's really finished. He can't talk his way out of this. Idiot.
Speaker 10: Is he alright?
Speaker 10: He wasn't injured, if that's what you mean.
Speaker 10: He's probably imagining that it was all a dream.
Speaker 10: A dream?
Speaker 10: Yeah. Don't tell me you don't dream either.
Speaker 4: Shinji, why is he in the hospital there next to me?
Speaker 4: Is this the same hospital where my sister is?
Speaker 4: Shhh.
Speaker 4: Shinji and Ayanami?
Speaker 9: Ikari, why did you do that?
Speaker 4: Because I couldn't trust him.
Speaker 4: My father betrayed me, Rei.
Speaker 4: Even though I was finally able to talk to him, he still doesn't understand me... at all.
Speaker 9: Did you try to understand him? His feelings?
Speaker 4: I used to try.
Speaker 9: Why don't you try to understand him?
Speaker 4: I SAID I DID!
Speaker 9: You're running away from the truth because it's ugly?
Speaker 7: Why not?! What's wrong with running away from reality if it sucks?!
Speaker 4: This
Speaker 1: is weird.
Speaker 1: What are those two arguing about?
Speaker 8: This is by special permission. You've got exactly five minutes.
Speaker 8: Thank you.
Speaker 6: Hey,
Speaker 11: it's the class rep.
Speaker 9: Tizuhara, how are you feeling?
Speaker 11: Lousy, but at least I'm
Speaker 3: still alive.
Speaker 3: That's strange. I thought Shinji was here. Was that just a dream?
Speaker 9: They took him out of here yesterday.
Speaker 9: You slept for three days, Toji.
Speaker 1: I did? Three days?
Speaker 1: Did you?
Speaker 1: No,
Speaker 9: I've only been here a little while.
Speaker 9: They wouldn't let me.
Speaker 9: I mean, I came as the class representative, you know.
Speaker 3: Of course, I know that.
Speaker 9: Do you really?
Speaker 4: I'm sorry.
Speaker 4: I didn't get to eat the lunch you made.
Speaker 9: Don't worry about it.
Speaker 9: It's alright. Just wish I could bring you a lunch here, but it's not allowed.
Speaker 4: Uh, Srep, would you do me a favor?
Speaker 4: Uh-huh.
Speaker 4: Would you tell my sister that there's nothing wrong with me?
Speaker 4: Shinji Akari, Commander wants to see you.
Speaker 5: Disobeying orders. Using an Eva for personal vendettas.
Speaker 5: Childish intimidation.
Speaker 5: These are all criminal offenses.
Speaker 5: Do you have anything to say?
Speaker 4: Yes.
Speaker 4: I don't want to pilot an Ava anymore.
Speaker 4: And I don't want to stay here either.
Speaker 5: Well then, you may leave.
Speaker 4: Yes.
Speaker 4: I'll go back to my old teacher.
Speaker 5: So, you're running away again?
Speaker 5: You disappoint me.
Speaker 5: I assume that we will never meet again.
Speaker 4: Yes.
Speaker 4: That's my intent.
Speaker 5: This is me. Erase the third child's ren. Ray will become Unit 1's designated pilot, with the dummy plug as backup.
*phone rings*
Speaker 4: Hey! Shinji!
Speaker 4: Can you hear me?
Speaker 4: Is it true that you're leaving?
Speaker 4: It is true, isn't it?
Speaker 4: But why?
Speaker 4: Why are you running away again?
Speaker 4: I admired you!
Speaker 4: I envied you!
Speaker 4: You're different from us!
Speaker 4: Damn!
Speaker 4: Even Toji became a pilot!
Speaker 4: - I don't think Asuka will be coming.
Speaker 4: She must be pretty disgusted with me.
Speaker 8: - Yes, she didn't even ask me to say goodbye to you.
Speaker 4: - That sounds like her.
Speaker 4: That's good.
Speaker 8: - It's going to be hard if you keep hiding your anger like that.
Speaker 4: - That's your philosophy, Misato.
Speaker 4: I can't live the way you do.
Speaker 8: - As I'm sure you may.
Speaker 8: - I'm sure you may.
Speaker 8: You know there will be a lot of restrictions
Speaker 8: placed upon your activities from now on.
Speaker 4: Yes, I know that, but--
Speaker 8: Yes?
Speaker 6: Let
Speaker 8: me ask
Speaker 4: you one thing.
Speaker 4: Why was Toji chosen to be the fourth child?
Speaker 8: It would seem that all of the students that are in your class
Speaker 8: are fourth-level candidates, Shinji.
Speaker 8: I just found out myself that it was yet
Speaker 8: another elaborate fabrication.
Speaker 4: All of them?
Speaker 8: All of my classmates?
Speaker 8: Shinji, about Suzuhara.
Speaker 8: That was a mistake that can't be mended with words alone.
Speaker 8: But I have to be honest with you.
Speaker 8: I was projecting all of my dreams, hopes, and purpose
Speaker 8: onto you.
Speaker 8: I know that it's been a huge burden for you,
Speaker 8: but we-- and by that, I mean everyone at Nerve--
Speaker 8: have had no choice except to place our future in your hands.
Speaker 8: I want you to remember that.
Speaker 4: The end justifies the means?
Speaker 8: Yes, that's how it is.
Speaker 8: And another thing--
Speaker 8: I'll be leaving your passcode to headquarters
Speaker 8: and your room as they are.
Speaker 4: What's the point?
Speaker 4: Get rid of them.
Speaker 4: It's over now. I won't pilot that thing.
Speaker 8: This is the real Shinji talking.
Speaker 8: I've never heard him sound so certain about anything before.
Speaker 12: A special state of emergency has been declared for the Tokai region.
Speaker 12: All residents must evacuate to their designated shelters immediately.
Speaker 12: An angel?
Speaker 13: All personnel, go to first stage battle stations. Prepare for ground-to-air intercept.
Speaker 6: Target status!
Speaker 9: It's broken through
Speaker 6: our perimeter!
Speaker 6: The Kamagataki defense line has been shattered!
Speaker 8: The first 18 layers of armor have been breached!
Speaker 8: I don't believe it. 18 layers destroyed in one shot.
Speaker 8: The AVAs can't deploy fast enough to intercept up top.
Speaker 8: Position Unit 2 for combat inside the geo-front, directly in front of headquarters.
Speaker 8: ASCA will snipe the target as soon as it breaks into the geo-front.
Speaker 2: Zero status?
Speaker 2: Unit 0 is in the AT Field Neutralization Zone, Major.
Speaker 2: But the left arm still hasn't been regenerated.
Speaker 2: Then it's not ready for
Speaker 5: combat yet.
Speaker 5: Send Ray out in Unit 1.
Speaker 5: Prepare a dummy plug as the backup system.
Speaker 8: Right.
Speaker 8: Initiating entry. Charging LCL. Commencing A10 nerve connection.
Speaker 8: The pulse
Speaker 2: flow is reversing!
Speaker 2: Unit 1's refusing the neural connection!
Speaker 6: Is that possible?
Speaker 5: Ikari? Yes. Is it refusing me?
Speaker 5: Abort the activation. Send Ray out an AVA Unit 0. Reactivate Unit 1 with the dummy plug.
Speaker 8: But Unit Zero isn't ready!
Speaker 8: It's not a problem. I can go.
Speaker 8: Rey?
Speaker 8: If I die, I can be
Speaker 4: replaced.
Speaker 4: I made up my mind. I swore I'd never pilot that thing.
Speaker 1: Hey, you there! What are you doing? Get in the shelter, quickly!
Speaker 3: It's no use! One more hand in the armor will be completely destroyed!
Speaker 8: I'm counting on you, Asuka.
Speaker 10: Here it comes. I can beat this angel even without Shinji the hero here to help out.
Speaker 9: Damn you!
Speaker 6: Shite!
Speaker 13: Next!
Speaker 6: I'm
Speaker 13: neutralized against AT Field, aren't I?
Speaker 13: Why won't you collapse, damn you!
Speaker 13: This can't be happening, I can't lose again, not again!
Speaker 6: My god!
Speaker 11: - Adopt a train hunt!
Speaker 11: - Alaska, no!
Speaker 11: Disengage your nerve connections now!
Speaker 10: - Evacuation training?
Speaker 10: What are you, stupid?
Speaker 10: That stuff's not for pilots like us.
Speaker 11: - Direct hit on the eighth block.
Speaker 11: Abandon the sixth shelter.
Speaker 11: All
Speaker 6: survivors
Speaker 11: go to the third shelter.
Speaker 3: - Unit two is severely damaged.
Speaker 3: It can't continue combat.
Speaker 3: How's Asuka?
She's alive!
Speaker 8: Verdumpt!
Speaker 3: The Angel has started moving again!
Speaker 8: What's Unit 1's status?
Speaker 8: Dummy plug
Speaker 2: upload completed.
Speaker 2: Call insertion completed.
Speaker 8: Initiate contact.
Speaker 8: Roger!
Speaker 8: What?!
Speaker 8: The pulse has vanished!
Speaker 8: It's refusing the
Speaker 2: dummy plug!
Speaker 2: Unit 1 won't activate!
Speaker 2: The dummy and
Speaker 5: Ray...
Speaker 5: Were both refused.
Speaker 5: Fyutsuki, take the con.
Speaker 4: Evacuate the casualties to the 6th block!
Speaker 4: Uninjured! Go to the 3rd shelter!
Speaker 1: Hey!
Speaker 1: This way!
Speaker 1: Hey, what are you doing? Do you wanna die?
Speaker 3: Asuka...
Speaker 3: Hey, Shinji!
Speaker 4: Kaji? What are you doing here?
Speaker 3: That's my line. What are you doing here, Shinji?
Speaker 3: I...
Speaker 4: I decided that I'd never pilot an Ava again.
Speaker 4: And since I decided that...
Speaker 3: Oh, really?
Speaker 3: Well, to answer your question, since my other job became public knowledge,
Speaker 3: I'm off the combat roster.
Speaker 3: So, here I am, sprinkling.
Speaker 3: At
Speaker 4: a time like this?
Speaker 3: What better time?
Speaker 3: Although I'd rather be between Misato's melons,
Speaker 3: this is a place I'd like to be when I die.
Speaker 4: Die?
Speaker 3: That's right. It is said that if an angel comes into contact with Adam, who lies sleeping beneath this very ground, humanity will be eradicated in the third impact.
Speaker 3: The only thing that can stop this is the one thing that has power equal to an angel's. Evangelion.
Speaker 4: Ayanami, with no rifle!
Speaker 4: It's an N2
Speaker 8: mine!
Speaker 8: Ray!
Speaker 8: AT Field, full power.
Speaker 6: Unit zero.
Speaker 6: Rei!
Speaker 6: Oh dear god.
Speaker 3: Shinji, the only thing I can do is stand here in water.
Speaker 3: But you, you have something that you can do.
Speaker 3: That only you can do.
Speaker 3: Nobody is forcing you.
Speaker 3: Think for yourself and make that decision by yourself.
Speaker 3: Think about what you have to do now.
Speaker 3: Think about no longer having any regrets.
Speaker 3: *Sounds
of
Speaker 5: process from step 108.
Speaker 7: Let me pilot it!
Speaker 7: Please, let me pilot Unit 1!
Speaker 5: Father…
Speaker 5: Why are you here?
Speaker 4: I'm here because I'm the pilot of Evangelion Unit 1,
Speaker 7: Shinji Ikari!
Speaker 7: We've been breached! Target is inside the main shaft! It's advancing!
Speaker 7: Where is it heading?
Speaker 7: It's advancing directly towards Central Dogma!
Speaker 7: It's
Speaker 8: coming
Speaker 6: here!
Speaker 8: All personnel evacuate!
All personnel evacuate! Repeat, all personnel evacuate!
Speaker 6: Wait!
Speaker 8: Ava Unit 1?
Speaker 8: Shinji!
*Screams*
No!
Speaker 1: - Please, I know! - Launch the fifth catapult!
Speaker 1: Check!
Speaker 1: *Mario screams*
Speaker 6: *Mario
screams*
*Mario screams*
Speaker 2: Huh?
Speaker 2: Energy reserve depleted!
Speaker 2: One is completely drained its reserves!
Speaker 2: The backup power supply isn't working!
Speaker 2: Shinji!
Speaker 7: Shinji!
Speaker 7: Dammit, move! Move! Move!
Speaker 7: Come on, move, you goddamn piece of junk!
Speaker 7: Move now or there's no point to any of this, dammit!
Speaker 11: Huh?
Speaker 11: What's that?
Speaker 7: Move! Move! Move!
Speaker 7: Move! Come on! Move!
Speaker 7: Oh, God! You've got to move now!
Speaker 7: Everyone will be killed!
Speaker 7: God, I'm sick of it already!
Speaker 7: Come on move! God damn you, you filthy stinky buster!
Speaker 2: It's... it's reactivated.
Speaker 8: Oh my god!
Speaker 2: This is impossible.
Speaker 2: It must be wrong. How can Shinji's sync ratio with Unit 1 be over 400%?!
Speaker 2: It's finally happened.
Speaker 9: It's aware.
Speaker 9: Oh!
*Sigh*
Speaker 6: It's breaking
Speaker 13: free!
Speaker 13: Free of what?
Speaker 13: Those plates weren't just armor.
Speaker 13: They were also restraints.
Speaker 7: Those bindings allowed us to control it.
Speaker 7: But now the Ava is removing the web that binds it to our will.
Speaker 7: The beast inside the Ava is free at last!
Speaker 3: Unit 1's awakened and been set free.
Speaker 3: Zele sure won't stay quiet for this.
Speaker 3: Was this part of your scenario, Commander Ikari?
Speaker 3: It's begun at last.
Speaker 3: Indeed.
Speaker 3: This is the beginning.
Speaker 3: Oh!
Speaker 11: In other words, the rain is big
Speaker 11: Fill my home with song and let me sing forevermore
For all our love, for all our love
Speaker 11: In other worlds, please be true.
Speaker 11: In other worlds, I
love you.
Speaker 8: Fused with another existence, what will Shinji see?
Speaker 8: Meanwhile, everyone who was left behind tries desperately to rescue him, but the attempt fails.
Speaker 8: It's the next episode. Form of the mind, form of the man.
.