Speaker 1: As a poor man,
Speaker 1: This is the end of my mind.
Speaker 1: I hope you enjoyed the future.
Speaker 2: Major Katsuragi, do you still refuse to allow us to question the only person who was directly involved in this incident, the pilot of Unit 1?
Speaker 3: Yes, sir. It is my belief that he is still very unstable emotionally, and that bringing him here into this situation would be very unwise at the current time.
Speaker 4: Then, as his proxy, let us ask you, Major Katsuragi.
Speaker 5: Did the Angels attempt communication with a human being?
Speaker 5: After
Speaker 3: reading the subject's reports, I found no concrete evidence to validate that theory.
Speaker 3: In all likelihood, this irregularity is simply an odd coincidence.
Speaker 6: If the subject's memory is correct.
Speaker 3: There was no evidence that his memory had been tampered with.
Speaker 6: But the Ava's AC recorder was not functioning. There is no way to confirm it.
Speaker 6: Was the Angel interested in the human mind?
Speaker 3: I am unable to answer that question.
Speaker 3: Whether the Angels even have a concept of what the human mind is,
Speaker 3: or whether they can understand our thought patterns is completely unknown.
Speaker 6: A new factor has been revealed in this incident.
Speaker 6: in that the Angel tried to take Ava into itself.
Speaker 6: Is there any possibility that this
Speaker 5: aspect may be linked to the predicted 13th Angel and all Angels thereafter?
Speaker 3: Based on the previous patterns we have observed, there would appear to be no systematic organization among the Angels.
Speaker 3: Correct. They have worked independently thus far.
Speaker 3: What do you mean, sir?
Speaker 2: You may not ask questions.
Speaker 3: Understood.
Speaker 2: That will be all. Dismissed.
Speaker 3: Yes, sir.
Speaker 2: Well, what do you
Speaker 7: think, Ikari?
Speaker 7: The Angels appear to be getting more intelligent. There's not much time left.
Speaker 7: Left
Speaker 2: for us, you mean.
Speaker 8: Who's the patient in room 12?
Speaker 4: That's the emergency room patient from the first Ava incident. She's been here for a long time.
Speaker 4: Her injuries are really complicated.
Speaker 4: Poor girl. And she's still in elementary school.
Speaker 9: He's here again today?
Speaker 9: Yeah. He comes to see her at least twice a week.
Speaker 9: He's a good brother. Thinking about his sister like that...
Speaker 9: Yeah, boys like that are pretty rare.
Speaker 7: Ray, are things satisfactory?
Speaker 3: Yes. I will be with Dr. Akagi all day tomorrow.
Speaker 3: And the day after that, I will be in school.
Speaker 7: And how is school?
Speaker 3: No problem, sir.
Speaker 7: I see. That's good.
Speaker 9: Class attention!
Speaker 9: Okay, sit down.
Speaker 2: Well, Ayanami is absent as usual.
Speaker 2: and so's Mr. Ida.
Speaker 2: Hey,
Speaker 3: what's up with Kinsuke?
Speaker 2: He's in New Yokosuka
Speaker 2: to see some dumb battleship.
Speaker 2: Ship called Miyoko or something like that
Speaker 2: is in port.
Speaker 2: Mr. Suzuhara!
Speaker 2: Yes, yes, yes, sir!
Speaker 2: Will you deliver this document to Miss Ayanami
Speaker 2: after school?
Speaker 10: Yes, sir!
Speaker 11: The first branch is still okay?
Speaker 11: No, no, don't bother.
Speaker 11: The data from the recon set is still being confirmed
Speaker 11: by the Magi.
Speaker 11: Right.
Speaker 12: It disappeared.
Speaker 12: The entire second branch just vanished?
Speaker 12: Yes, sir.
Speaker 13: It's been confirmed.
Speaker 13: It's been wiped off the map.
Speaker 13: Oh my god.
Speaker 12: That second insect had gone crazy.
Speaker 12: General affairs is total chaos.
Speaker 8: What do you think happened over there?
Speaker 8: It's under investigation.
Speaker 8: Our only clues are these recon photos
Speaker 8: from the geosynchronous satellite.
Speaker 8: There's
Speaker 14: nothing else
Speaker 8: left.
Speaker 8: 10 seconds.
Speaker 8: Nine,
Speaker 15: eight, seven, six, five, four, three,
Speaker 15: 3, 2, 1, contact.
Speaker 15: This is horrible.
Speaker 15: Evangelion Unit 4, its support group, and all the other facilities within an 89 kilometer radius were completely destroyed.
Speaker 15: Along with thousands of people.
Speaker 13: Looking at the time schedule, it would appear that they were in the middle of installing the experimental S-2 unit from Germany.
Speaker 15: Potential causes range from an insufficient structural integrity to an error in calculation during the preliminary design stage.
Speaker 15: That's 32,768 possibilities.
Speaker 15: And that's not mentioning
Speaker 8: sabotage.
Speaker 5: But it wasn't really an explosion, was it?
Speaker 5: It just disappeared.
Speaker 8: In all probability, they were swallowed by a Dirac-C, just as Unit 1 was.
Speaker 8: Then the restored S-2 engine is...
Speaker 8: Gone.
Speaker 8: Along with our hopes.
Speaker 8: We're being forced to use things we don't understand.
Speaker 8: Yes.
Speaker 8: Things like the Avis.
Speaker 8: So what'll we do with Unit 3?
Speaker 8: It's being shipped here as we speak.
Speaker 8: The U.S. government doesn't want to risk losing their first branch as well.
Speaker 8: Didn't they insist on the right to build Units 3 and 4 in the first place?
Speaker 8: And now they're forcing it off on us?
Speaker 8: They're really pushing it.
Speaker 8: Well, you can't blame them, can you?
Speaker 8: After a disaster like that, anyone would get nervous.
Speaker 8: We'll handle it.
Speaker 8: And how are you going to handle the test activation?
Speaker 8: Will you use Ray's dummy plug?
Speaker 8: I'll decide soon.
Speaker 8: This is the dummy plug prototype. Ray's personal data has been transferred into it, but our current technology can't really digitize a human mind and soul.
Speaker 8: In the end, this is nothing but a pale duplication that emulates the real pilot's thinking processes. It's still only a machine.
Speaker 7: It transmits a signal pattern to the AVA. If the AVA believes that there is a pilot and synchronizes, then that's good enough.
Speaker 7: Load the data into units one and two.
Speaker 8: But we're still working out the bugs, sir.
Speaker 7: Just do it. It's sufficient.
Speaker 8: Yes, sir.
Speaker 7: I've delegated the transport of the unit to the UN.
Speaker 7: It will be here by the end of the weekend.
Speaker 7: At that time, you will take care of it.
Speaker 8: Yes, sir. We'll perform the modifications and activation test in Matsushiro.
Speaker 7: Hmm. And the test pilot?
Speaker 8: Use of the dummy plug is not recommended.
Speaker 8: One of our candidates...
Speaker 7: Will be chosen as the fourth.
Speaker 8: Yes, sir. There is one child available whose core can be prepared immediately.
Speaker 7: Then make it so.
Speaker 8: Yes, sir.
Speaker 7: Ray, we're finished now.
Speaker 8: Right.
Speaker 7: Let's eat.
Speaker 8: Yes,
Speaker 3: sir.
Speaker 9: Stand up.
Speaker 9: Dismissed.
Speaker 10: Yeah, it's lunchtime at last.
Speaker 10: My very favorite part of the entire school day.
Speaker 10: What?
Speaker 10: Huh?
Speaker 16: Hmm?
Speaker 16: What do you mean you didn't make our lunches?
Speaker 16: I didn't have time to cook last night.
Speaker 16: I had too much homework.
Speaker 16: Oh, you did, did you?
Speaker 16: And that's your excuse for me having to go without lunch?
Speaker 10: Uh-oh.
Speaker 10: The newlyweds are fighting.
Speaker 9: Oh, shut up!
Speaker 8: What's with the grim face?
Speaker 8: Uh, well, it's the Unit 3 activation test.
Speaker 8: We'll be using the fourth as the test pilot.
Speaker 8: The fourth?
Speaker 8: The fourth child's been found?
Speaker 8: Yesterday.
Speaker 8: I haven't received a report from the Marduk Institute.
Speaker 8: Don't worry, Major. You'll get your report.
Speaker 8: Dr. Okagi, are you hiding something from me again?
Speaker 8: No, of course not.
Speaker 8: Well, okay.
Speaker 8: So who's the kid?
Speaker 8: You're kidding! Him?
Speaker 8: Yes, well, the prospective candidates have to be kept together for their own protection.
Speaker 8: It can't be helped.
Speaker 8: I don't know how to tell them.
Speaker 8: It's hard.
Speaker 3: Asuka will be fine.
Speaker 3: She's committed to piloting in Ava.
Speaker 8: And Rei
Speaker 3: is exceptional.
Speaker 3: We've never had any problems with her.
Speaker 3: Shinji, on
Speaker 8: the other hand, has gone through some pretty bad phases.
Speaker 8: Even depression.
Speaker 8: I don't want to expose him to any more stress.
Speaker 8: I know, but gathering children of this kind is an imperative.
Speaker 8: It's for the sake of our own survival.
Speaker 8: You shouldn't...
Speaker 8: Shouldn't complicate things?
Speaker 8: Of course.
Speaker 9: Class dismissed!
Speaker 17: Bye!
Speaker 17: See you later!
Speaker 17: Hey,
Speaker 9: don't forget that you've got bulletin duty this week, Suzuhara.
Speaker 10: I've got what?
Speaker 10: The class bulletin,
Speaker 9: remember?
Speaker 9: You're supposed to deliver this to Miss Ayanami.
Speaker 9: Aw,
Speaker 10: come on. Who else has duty?
Speaker 10: It's you and Ayanami this week.
Speaker 10: It's Ayanami and me?
Speaker 10: Then I guess I got it.
Speaker 10: Huh! But I can't go to some girl's place by myself!
Speaker 10: Well, I can go with you!
Speaker 10: Hey! Shinji! Welcome home with me, will ya?
Speaker 10: You know where Iyanami lives, right?
Speaker 18: Uh, uh, mm-hmm.
Speaker 10: Hey, Ray, I'm coming in.
Speaker 10: Hey, you can't enter a girl's place without her permission.
Speaker 10: We've got no choice.
Speaker 10: She won't see it
Speaker 14: if we
Speaker 10: leave it here.
Speaker 17: Uh, is anybody home?
Speaker 10: My God.
Speaker 10: This is a girl's room?
Speaker 10: It's so decrepit.
Speaker 10: Please.
Speaker 11: You shouldn't touch
Speaker 10: anything.
Speaker 10: You should get pissed.
Speaker 17: I'm just cleaning
Speaker 11: up.
Speaker 10: Well, I won't help you do it.
Speaker 10: It's just not manly.
Speaker 11: Well, okay.
Speaker 11: But you know, Misato hates guys like that.
Speaker 11: I don't care. It's my policy,
Speaker 10: all right?
Speaker 10: You know, now that I think about it, you've changed.
Speaker 10: What?
Speaker 10: You, Shinji.
Speaker 10: The first time I saw you, I really thought you were the world's biggest jerk.
Speaker 10: I mean, you sure didn't seem like someone who'd do something for someone else back then.
Speaker 10: I guess you were so deep in your shell that I couldn't see the real you.
Speaker 10: Hi. Excuse us.
Speaker 3: What for?
Speaker 10: We brought you your school bulletins.
Speaker 11: I'm sorry. I kind of cleaned up. It was just trash, right?
Speaker 11: - I...
Speaker 8: Thank you.
Speaker 10: Man, you Ava pilots sure are a bunch of wackos, huh?
Speaker 10: Thank
Speaker 3: you.
Speaker 3: Words of gratitude.
Speaker 3: Words I've never used.
Speaker 3: Not even with him.
Speaker 12: The city. A paradise made by mankind.
Speaker 7: Driven from paradise, man escaped to this earthly existence on the edge of death.
Speaker 7: Created by the weakest of beings, created by the sapience born from that weakness,
Speaker 7: this paradise is our creation.
Speaker 12: To protect ourselves from the fear death instills,
Speaker 12: To satiate our beings with pleasure, we created a paradise by and of ourselves.
Speaker 12: This city surely is such a paradise. A city designed and built to
Speaker 7: protect us.
Speaker 7: A city for those who run in fear from the outside world. The world of our enemies.
Speaker 7: Of course, cowards do tend to live longer. That's
Speaker 12: one benefit.
Speaker 17: The
Speaker 12: third new Tokyo. Nerve's hidden intercept base.
Speaker 12: And now, the long-delayed seventh construction phase is about to be finished at last.
Speaker 12: It's almost complete.
Speaker 12: Now, about Unit 4's accident, how will you present that to the committee?
Speaker 12: With the facts. The cause is unknown.
Speaker 12: But this was a major catastrophe.
Speaker 7: It was of no consequence to us.
Speaker 7: The S-2 engine sample may have been lost, but the data is still in Germany.
Speaker 7: This installation and Unit 1 will be sufficient.
Speaker 7: But the committee is in a total panic!
Speaker 7: Of course they're panicked. It wasn't scheduled.
Speaker 12: Yes. Zele must be busy rewriting
Speaker 7: their schedules now.
Speaker 7: Incidents not depicted in the Dead Sea Scrolls may occur. This should teach the old men a lesson.
Speaker 7: The Intercept system is completed, and they're not going to have any
Speaker 5: party for it?
Speaker 5: NERVE has got to be the most inflexible and stifling organization on Earth!
Speaker 5: Well, it's because of Commander Ikari.
Speaker 5: And are you
Speaker 15: approved too?
Speaker 15: I don't think that's pertinent data, sir.
Speaker 15: And I'm going to have to tell Major Katsuragi and Dr. Akagi about this.
Speaker 5: Not if I cover your mouth with
Speaker 15: mine.
Speaker 15: Kashi! How's it going?
Speaker 5: Uh, well, it's going, I guess.
Speaker 3: Oh, I have work to do. Excuse me?
Speaker 3: Far be it for me to make judgments on your private life,
Speaker 3: But under the current situation, is it wise to be hitting on girls who are under certain chains of command?
Speaker 5: Who's under who's not your concern? Would you prefer to be hit on?
Speaker 3: That depends on how you answer this. You know the secrets behind the Marduk Institute and that Adam thing, right?
Speaker 3: What secrets?
Speaker 3: Don't play games!
Speaker 5: Asking for help isn't like you, Misato.
Speaker 3: Well, I'm asking, Kaji. Something stinks here. The way the fourth child was found was too convenient. Something funny's going on.
Speaker 5: I'll tell you one thing.
Speaker 5: The Marduk Institute doesn't exist. Nerve is pulling the strings all by itself.
Speaker 3: Nerve's pulling the strings? Commander Ikari?
Speaker 5: 707 is a good starting place.
Speaker 3: Code 707? But isn't that Shinji's school?
Speaker 3: Misato...
Speaker 3: Yes?
Speaker 3: Ritsuko says she's expecting you for a meeting about tomorrow's trip.
Speaker 3: All right, thank you. I'll see you later.
Speaker 5: Uh-huh.
Speaker 5: So, can I buy you a drink, cup of tea?
Speaker 11: Kaji, I'm a boy.
Speaker 11: I thought you'd be a more serious person, Kaji.
Speaker 5: You're saying that to someone as straight arrow and reliable as me, Mr. Ikari?
Speaker 5: I... I'm sorry.
Speaker 5: I'm sorry, too. I didn't mean to sound rude.
Speaker 5: Hey, I want to show you something.
Speaker 2: You grow
Speaker 18: melons?
Speaker 5: Yeah, aren't they cute?
Speaker 5: This is my hobby.
Speaker 5: But keep it a secret, okay?
Speaker 5: Making something grow is really great.
Speaker 5: One can see and learn so many things from the process.
Speaker 5: It also brings pleasure.
Speaker 5: But pain too, right?
Speaker 5: Do you hate pain?
Speaker 5: I don't like it.
Speaker 5: Ah, but have you found what gives you pleasure?
Speaker 5: That's not so bad.
Speaker 5: If you've known pain and hardship, it's easier to be kind to others.
Speaker 5: Being kind isn't a weakness.
Speaker 5: Hello? Yes?
Speaker 5: It's Katsuragi. The sync test will be starting soon.
Speaker 8: I was afraid of this. Shinji's sync ratio is dropping.
Speaker 8: And what's that mean?
Speaker 8: I can't say for sure, but I think that something may have happened to him during that last incident.
Speaker 8: Something's affected him.
Speaker 8: This makes it even harder to tell him about the pilot.
Speaker 8: Well, the new pilot will be informed officially tomorrow.
Speaker 9: Everyone stand up! Dismissed!
Speaker 11: All right! Lunchtime!
Speaker 9: Report to the principal's
Speaker 3: office.
Speaker 14: What?
Speaker 11: What'd you do now?
Speaker 11: I don't know.
Speaker 10: Excuse me,
Speaker 14: I'm
Speaker 10: Toji Suzuhara.
Speaker 11: You're Toji
Speaker 1: Suzuhara?
Speaker 1: How was your trip to New Yokosuka?
Speaker 11: Oh, it was way cool.
Speaker 11: Speaking of which, I did pick up some disturbing information.
Speaker 11: EVA Unit 3?
Speaker 11: Yeah, the one they built in the U.S.
Speaker 11: It's been completed, hasn't it?
Speaker 11: I don't know.
Speaker 11: I know it's classified, but come on.
Speaker 11: You gotta tell me something.
Speaker 11: But I really don't know.
Speaker 11: Haven't you heard the rumor that the activation test
Speaker 11: will be held at the second test facility in Matsushiro?
Speaker 11: No, I hadn't.
Speaker 11: Then the pilot hasn't been chosen yet?
Speaker 11: How would I know?
Speaker 11: Misato could choose me for the position.
Speaker 11: Shinji, would you ask her for me?
Speaker 11: I really want to be an EVA pilot.
Speaker 11: I don't know if she could or not.
Speaker 11: Hmm.
Speaker 11: Well, what about the story that Unit 4 was lost?
Speaker 11: Was lost?
Speaker 11: You really didn't know?
Speaker 11: It disappeared along with the entire second branch.
Speaker 11: My dad's whole section was in a panic.
Speaker 11: Are you sure?
Speaker 11: I've got my sources.
Speaker 17: Misato didn't tell me anything.
Speaker 11: Well, you know, I guess it doesn't directly concern the pilots.
Speaker 11: If she didn't tell you, it's probably because you don't need to know.
Speaker 11: I'm sorry about bothering you with all these weird questions.
Speaker 11: - Hasn't Toji come back yet?
Speaker 2: - Thus we, mankind, survived the hell called Second Impact
Speaker 2: and rose again.
Speaker 2: The number of children have been decreasing
Speaker 2: on a year-to-year basis.
Speaker 2: - Uh, sorry I'm late.
Speaker 2: - I know about it. Be seated.
Speaker 2: Anyway, it is you, the younger generation,
Speaker 2: who will lead the way to the future.
Speaker 19: - Let's get out of here!
Speaker 19: - And Toji?
Speaker 19: Oh, he's gonna be here late. He's got clean-up duty today.
Speaker 17: The school is now closing. All students
Speaker 9: must go to their homes immediately.
Speaker 9: Um, Suzahara?
Speaker 10: Huh?
Speaker 9: You're... on clean-up duty.
Speaker 9: You have to line up these desks and clean off the blackboards.
Speaker 10: I haven't had lunch yet. I'll do it as soon as I've eaten.
Speaker 9: Do you always buy your lunch from the school shop?
Speaker 10: Well, of course. There's no one at home who can cook.
Speaker 9: Suzuhara?
Speaker 9: I have two sisters. Their names are Kadami and Nozomi,
Speaker 9: and I always make lunches for them every day.
Speaker 10: That's a lot of work.
Speaker 9: I am actually a pretty good cook, though I guess you might not expect that.
Speaker 10: Hmm?
Speaker 9: And you see, I always end up cooking too much for our lunches.
Speaker 10: That's definitely a waste.
Speaker 10: If you need help getting rid of the leftovers, I'll help.
Speaker 9: Yes, please.
Speaker 16: Hi, Akaji!
Speaker 16: Oh, Asuka.
Speaker 5: Sorry, I'm busy right now. Can it wait?
Speaker 16: Do you have time for Misato?
Speaker 16: No.
Speaker 16: Gaji!
Speaker 5: Dammit! Not right now.
Speaker 16: Oh, these are our sync data reports.
Speaker 16: Huh? Four? Oh my god, the hammer! It can't be!
Speaker 16: Who in the hell made him the fourth child?
Speaker 16: I won't stand for it!
*Loud noise*
I'm not sure what you're doing
Speaker 18: Fill my heart with songs
Speaker 18: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 18: You are all I long for
Speaker 18: All I worship and adore
Speaker 18: In other words
Speaker 17: Please be true
Speaker 17: In other words
I love you
Another one, I love you.