Speaker 1: As a cruel, a man like a man,
Speaker 1: a man, you become a man.
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now,
Speaker 1: but I'm still holding my eyes.
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at the moment
Speaker 1: You are smiling
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to touch
Speaker 1: I'm just curious
Speaker 1: I'm still not sure
Speaker 1: But I'll see you soon
Speaker 1: The back of the back of
Speaker 1: "Signan you, you're a fairy tale"
Speaker 2: Shinji, wake up.
Speaker 2: How long are you going to avoid school?
Speaker 2: It's been five days now.
Speaker 2: Unit one's already completely repaired.
Speaker 2: You're the pilot.
Speaker 2: Are you going to leave it sitting there?
Speaker 2: Shinji!
Speaker 2: Huh?
Speaker 2: He's run away. I'm not surprised.
Speaker 2: Shenjing!
Speaker 3: - Well,
Speaker 4: um...
Speaker 4: - Pardon me, ma'am, but we're Shinji's classmates,
Speaker 4: Ida and Suzuhara.
Speaker 4: - Ida and Suzuhara?
Speaker 3: - Yeah. - Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 4: I'm Suzuhara.
Speaker 4: - Oh, aren't you the ones who got in Unit 1's entry
Speaker 5: plug?
Speaker 5: - Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 5: We're
Speaker 6: really sorry for causing so much trouble.
Speaker 2: The reason
Speaker 6: we came here today is that Shinji's been absent
Speaker 6: ever since then, so we came to see if he was okay.
Speaker 2: Well, Shinji's... he's at the nerve training facility right now.
Speaker 4: Oh, I see.
Speaker 4: These are the printouts that were building up on Shinji's desk.
Speaker 2: Oh, sorry for your trouble.
Speaker 4: Thank you.
Speaker 4: Well, we'll just
Speaker 6: be leaving now.
Speaker 4: Please say hi to Shinji for us.
Speaker 4: Yeah, I will. Bye.
Speaker 4: This is an unexpected development.
Speaker 4: She was a real babe, wasn't she?
Speaker 4: Hmm.
Speaker 2: Hmm.
*Sigh*
*Splash*
Speaker 7: Thank you for using the Tokyo-3 loop line.
This train will be going out of service at this station.
Speaker 7: Please, make sure you take all of your belongings with you as you exit the train.
Speaker 7: Thank you for using Tokyo Loop Line.
Speaker 8: I ought to go back.
Speaker 7: *Squeak
Speaker 7: No, there's
Speaker 1: still a tidal wave of
Speaker 9: pushing at 230 meters a second.
Speaker 9: Doctor, we must evacuate.
Speaker 9: No, it's my duty to remain here.
Speaker 9: Doctor, you think death is easy, but you
Speaker 3: have an obligation to watch this
Speaker 2: living hell.
Speaker 2: Hmm.
Speaker 3: *Gasp
*
-
Speaker 2: But he's only 14 years old.
Speaker 2: Making him bear the burden of the future of mankind seems so cruel.
Speaker 2: But we have to use 14-year-old children to pilot the Avas.
Speaker 2: I know.
Speaker 2: But...
Speaker 2: So has he called or made contact?
Speaker 2: Nothing?
Speaker 2: Mm-mm.
Speaker 2: Nothing.
Speaker 2: I don't think he's going to come back this time.
Speaker 2: What will you do?
Speaker 2: Nothing.
Speaker 2: It's better for him if he doesn't come back.
Speaker 2: But why?
Speaker 2: Because of what happened after the last battle.
Speaker 2: Why did you ignore my orders?
Speaker 8: I apologize.
Speaker 2: I'm the one who's in charge of your operations, aren't I?
Speaker 8: Yes.
Speaker 2: You do know you're supposed to obey my orders.
Speaker 2: Understand?
Speaker 8: Yes.
Speaker 8: I'm
Speaker 2: warning you not to do it again.
Speaker 8: Yes.
Speaker 8: Hey,
Speaker 2: are you even listening to anything I'm saying?
Speaker 8: Yes.
Speaker 2: Oh, no, you don't.
Speaker 2: You're not going to get out of this by just saying yes to everything I say.
Speaker 8: I know, Miss Misato.
Speaker 8: We won, didn't we?
Speaker 8: Isn't that enough?
Speaker 2: You know, it may seem easy going
Speaker 8: along with whatever anyone else wants,
Speaker 8: but if
Speaker 2: you get into an Ava with that attitude, it'll kill you.
Speaker 8: You know, I just don't care anymore.
Speaker 2: It'd be nice if I could say you've got the right attitude,
Speaker 2: but if you think you're going to get any praise out of me,
Speaker 2: you're wrong, Shinji.
Speaker 8: That's not the point.
Speaker 8: Anyway, I'm the only one who can pilot it.
Speaker 8: I'll just have to do.
Speaker 8: I see.
Speaker 2: If getting into the Eva means nothing but pain to him,
Speaker 2: I don't think he should pilot again.
Speaker 2: Otherwise, he'll be killed.
Speaker 7: But we need pilots.
Speaker 4: Captain!
Speaker 4: Ida, go on ahead!
Speaker 4: But I can't go on and leave you behind like this!
Speaker 4: What will I do?
Speaker 4: You fool!
Speaker 4: There.
Speaker 4: Hmm?
Speaker 4: The new kid!
Speaker 4: Ikari!
Speaker 4: Hmm?
Speaker 4: Toji was real sorry about everything.
Speaker 4: His kid's sister really tore him a new one.
Speaker 4: She said that it was the robot who saved her lives.
Speaker 4: That must be pretty embarrassing,
Speaker 4: getting herself chewed out by a second grader, right?
Speaker 4: Hmm, I like it out here at night,
Speaker 4: because those noisy cicadas don't chirp.
Speaker 4: It was pretty quiet when I was a kid,
Speaker 4: but there are tons of them now.
Speaker 4: - Misato said that the ecosystem is returning
Speaker 4: to its former state.
Speaker 4: - Misato said so, hmm?
Speaker 4: I really envy you.
Speaker 4: I mean, you live with such a beautiful woman,
Speaker 4: and you get to pile up the Evangelion.
Speaker 4: Oh, man.
Speaker 4: I wish I could get inside that lovely cockpit just once.
Speaker 8: You really shouldn't, you know.
Speaker 10: Your mother would probably be worried.
Speaker 10: Huh?
Speaker 10: Oh, don't worry about my mother.
Speaker 10: I don't have one of those.
Speaker 10: Oh.
Speaker 4: I'm no different from you.
Speaker 4: Huh.
Speaker 4: You'll take something to eat, won't you?
Speaker 10: Yeah. Do you usually do things like this?
Speaker 10: Well, sure.
Speaker 10: Is it some kind of training for guerrilla warfare or something?
Speaker 10: How could I fight with toys like
Speaker 4: these? It's just for fun.
Speaker 9: - You're Shinji Akari, aren't you?
Speaker 8: - Yes.
Speaker 9: from the Nerve Security Intelligence.
Speaker 9: Under Security Clause Article 8,
Speaker 9: we're taking you to Nerve Headquarters, all right?
Speaker 9: - Yes.
Speaker 4: - And all you did was stand there?
Speaker 4: - That's easy for you to say,
Speaker 4: but they were Nerve Intelligence professionals.
Speaker 4: - So what about it?
Speaker 4: Geez, don't you have any balls at all?
Speaker 11: - Girl, pervert, ape.
Speaker 4: Only an idiot fights when he knows you can't win.
Speaker 4: Balls have nothing to do with it.
Speaker 2: - Long time no see.
Speaker 8: - Yeah.
Speaker 2: - Do you feel any better after wandering around
Speaker 2: for two days?
Speaker 8: - I don't know.
Speaker 2: - The Ava is on standby.
Speaker 2: Will you pilot it or won't you?
Speaker 8: You're not going to scold me for running away?
Speaker 8: Of course you're not. I'm no relation to you, am I?
Speaker 8: If I say that I won't pilot Unit 1, what are you going to do with it?
Speaker 2: I suppose that Rey will do it. You won't pilot it?
Speaker 8: It seems a little bit unrealistic for you to force everything on her.
Speaker 8: Don't worry. I'll pilot it.
Speaker 8: But you don't want to do it.
Speaker 8: Of course not. It's not something that comes to me naturally.
Speaker 8: But Ayanami and you
Speaker 1: and Miss Riosko...
Speaker 1: Stow that line of crap!
Speaker 8: This has nothing to do
Speaker 2: with any of us.
Speaker 2: If you don't like it, get out of here.
Speaker 2: Just forget all about Ava and us and go back where you came from.
Speaker 2: We don't need someone with that attitude piloting.
Speaker 7: You do know that the third child is leaving Tokyo 3 tomorrow, don't you?
Speaker 12: We'll reconfigure Unit 1's system for Rei.
Speaker 12: Regardless of the results of the Unit 0 reactivation experiments, we'll move on to experimenting on Unit 1.
Speaker 12: According to the Marduk Organization's report, the fourth child hasn't been found yet.
Speaker 5: Does that mean we can't get any more pilot recruits?
Speaker 8: Uh, excuse me. Where is Miss Misato? I'd like to say goodbye.
Speaker 9: You are no longer NERV personnel, therefore we can't give you that information.
Speaker 6: - Hey, Cory!
Speaker 3: - Huh?
Speaker 3: You
Speaker 6: left this stuff behind me?
Speaker 6: Oh!
Speaker 8: Uh, excuse
Speaker 4: me.
Speaker 10: Could I--
Speaker 10: Um...
Speaker 4: - I'll be back. - Oh, I'm back.
Speaker 4: Oh, I
Speaker 10: Well, thank you.
Speaker 4: Hey,
Speaker 10: Toji! Come on,
Speaker 6: say something!
Speaker 6: - Kari,
Speaker 6: look, I'm sorry about hitting you twice. Please, you gotta hit me back. - I can't
Speaker 6: do that! - You gotta, otherwise
Speaker 4: I won't be satisfied. - He's a
Speaker 4: pretty embarrassing guy, isn't he? But if it'll put an end to this dispute, why don't you go ahead and hit him?
Speaker 6: - But I...
Speaker 6: - Hurry up! You don't have much time, do you?
Speaker 8: - Okay, but only once.
Speaker 8: - Right, come on!
Speaker 3: Hey, wait!
Speaker 6: Don't
hold back.
Speaker 4: - Ooh, that hurt.
Speaker 4: - How do you know I'd be here?
Speaker 4: - It was just a hunch.
Speaker 4: We've seen lots of other classmates off before.
Speaker 4: It's getting to be a regular thing.
Speaker 6: - Of course, if you're leaving, you know, we'll have to leave this city sometime soon.
Speaker 6: But we can't really blame you for that.
Speaker 6: I mean, we saw how you suffered in the Eva.
Speaker 6: And anyway, if anyone does try to blame you,
Speaker 6: I'm gonna give him a whop on the head!
Speaker 6: Come on! Try not to look so gloomy!
Speaker 6: Take care, Ikari.
Speaker 6: Yeah, take care.
Speaker 6: Well, uh…
Speaker 9: Your time is up.
Speaker 6: Huh?
Speaker 8: - Hey!
Speaker 8: The one who deserved to be hit, not you!
Speaker 8: I'm a coward!
Speaker 3: I'm dishonest!
Speaker 1: I'm sneaky!
Speaker 1: And a wimp!
Speaker 9: Don't give us any more trouble.
Speaker 9: Jeez!
Speaker 2: Well,
Speaker 7: he's gone.
Speaker 7: Do you really think this is for the best?
Speaker 2: The hedgehog's dilemma.
Speaker 2: The closer we become, the more deeply we hurt.
Speaker 2: Now I understand.
Speaker 2: I finally understand.
Speaker 2: He can't let others know how he feels in any other way.
Speaker 11: Express linear train bound for Atsuki is arriving on track two.
Speaker 11: For your safety, please step back to the area inside the yellow lines.
Speaker 7: The train arriving on track 2 is for special government use only and departs at 420 for Atsuki.
Speaker 7: No civilians are allowed inside the fence.
Speaker 7: Please be aware that the boarding of this train by unauthorized persons is strictly prohibited.
-
Speaker 3: Hmm.
Speaker 3: Huh?
Speaker 3: The local train bound for Gora is now arriving
Speaker 11: on track four.
Speaker 11: For your own safety, please stay inside the yellow lines.
Speaker 11: If you are accompanying small children, please ensure that they are properly supervised.
Speaker 7: The train arriving on track 4 is the local shuttle to Gora, departing at 432.
Speaker 7: If this is your train, please step inside and wait until departure.
Speaker 7: The train is approaching. Please stay behind the yellow line.
Speaker 8: I... I'm home!
Speaker 2: Welcome home.
Speaker 5: Fly me to the moon
Speaker 5: And let me play
Speaker 5: Among the stars
Speaker 5: Let me see what's playing
Speaker 5: It's like on Jupiter and Mars
Speaker 5: In other words
Speaker 5: Hold my hand
Speaker 5: In other words, darling, kiss me
Speaker 5: Fill my heart with song
Speaker 5: Oh, let me sing forevermore
Speaker 5: You are all I long for, all I worship and adore
Speaker 5: In other words, please be true
Speaker 5: In other words,
I love you
Speaker 2: Re Ayanami seems cold and distant, yet she seems to have a relationship with Commander Ikari.
Speaker 2: Shinji doesn't understand how this can be, but before he can find out more,
Speaker 2: a beam shot by the fifth angel strikes Ava Unit 1 in the chest.
Speaker 2: Will this episode be
Speaker 3: Shinji's last?