Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
THE YEAR IS 2016 A.D.
THE THING THAT PEOPLE HAD LOST
IN OTHER WORDS, THE INSTRUMENTALITY
OF SOULS WAS STILL ONGOING
HOWEVER, THERE IS FAR TOO LITTLE TIME LEFT
TO MAKE MENTION OF IT ALL
THEREFORE, NOW, WE WILL TAKE
THE BOY NAMED SHINJI IKARI
AND TELL THE STORY OF THE
INSTRUMENTALITY OF HIS SOUL
IN THE CASE OF SHINJI IKARI
FEAR
"WHY?"
"REALLY?"
"I DON'T KNOW"
Exit
Play
Messages
"THAT MAKES MY LIFE WORTH SOMETHING"
"...SO"
Transfer Application
Shinji Ikari
I hate you!
"THAT'S WHY I'M HAPPY"
"BUT IT DOESN'T MAKE ME HAPPY"
"WHY DO YOU PILOT THE EVA?"
FINAL EPISODE
THE BEAST THAT
SHOUTED LOVE
AT THE HEART
OF THE WORLD
"ARE YOU AFRAID OF BEING INSECURE?"
"DO YOU WANT PEACE OF MIND?"
"DON'T HATE ME!"
REJECTION
TO CONNECT AND TO BE RECOGNIZED
"DO YOU LOVE"
"YOUR MOTHER?"
BECAUSE I'M AFRAID
"SO?"
A RESOLUTION TO THE INSECURITY
A RESOLUTION TO THE LONELINESS
"I WANT TO BE WORTH SOMETHING"
THAT'S WHY YOU PILOT THE EVA
SHINJI IKARI
"WHERE DO I EXIST?"
THAT IS WHY I
WISH FOR MY
SOUL TO BE
CLOSED OFF
"YOU'RE INSECURE"
THAT IS FREEDOM
"THAT IS REALITY"
"WHY?"
"MY IMAGE OF ME?"
South Pole Showa Base Opening Its Doors to visitors First African-American Female President
What are you, stupid?
Pull Back
TO MY FATHER, THANK YOU.
TO MY MOTHER, FAREWELL.
AND TO ALL THE CHILDREN...
CONGRATULATIONS!