Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at you, I'm smiling.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to hear you, and I'm just curious.
Speaker 1: I don't know the truth, but I still don't know the pain.
Speaker 1: But I will know that you will know that your back is the way you will see the future.
Speaker 1: The evil lord of
Speaker 2: Power supply connected. Beginning system activation.
Speaker 2: Activation voltage approaching critical level. 0.5, 0.2, rising.
Speaker 2: Initiate activation system, phase two.
Speaker 3: Pilot link up initiated.
Speaker 2: Startup system,
Speaker 4: phase two.
Speaker 5: Synapsis inserted. Nerve junctions connecting.
Speaker 5: Cardiograph
Speaker 2: transmitting.
Speaker 3: All circuits are operational.
Speaker 2: No problems with initial contact.
Speaker 3: Power supply to brachial muscles on the right and left arms.
Speaker 3: All nerve links, check out normal.
Speaker 2: The checklist is satisfactory up to 2550.
Speaker 2: Clear to 2580.
Speaker 2: Prepare for third stage connection.
Speaker 2: Counting down to absolute borderline.
Speaker 2: 0.9, 0.7, 0.5, 0.4, 0.3.
Speaker 2: The pulses are flowing backward!
Speaker 6: Something's
Speaker 2: going wrong in the third
Speaker 3: stage!
Speaker 3: Rejection occurring in the nerve center elements.
Speaker 5: Break off contact. Cut circuit links number one through number six.
Speaker 5: Negative! The signal's not being received!
Speaker 2: Unit zero's out of control!
Speaker 4: Abort the experiment. Cut off the power supply.
Speaker 2: Yes, sir!
Speaker 7: Unit zero has switched to standby power.
Speaker 3: We've got 35 seconds before it comes to a complete stop.
Speaker 8: It's
Speaker 5: gone berserk!
Speaker 2: Stay back!
Speaker 2: Auto ejection system has been activated.
Speaker 8: Damn it!
Speaker 5: *Bang
Speaker 4: *
Speaker 5: -
Speaker 5: chosen in accordance with the Marduk Report, the first child.
Speaker 5: Designated pilot for the Evangelion Unit Zero.
Speaker 5: Her past has been eradicated.
Speaker 5: All of her personal records have been erased.
Speaker 9: So do we have any idea what caused that incident during the last test?
Speaker 5: We still don't know.
Speaker 5: However, we believe that mental instability on the part of the pilot was a primary factor.
Speaker 9: Mental instability? In Ray?
Speaker 5: Yes. Her mind became much more disturbed than we had anticipated.
Speaker 9: So what did happen?
Speaker 5: I don't know.
Speaker 5: But she could have...
Speaker 5: Did something occur to you?
Speaker 5: No. It can't be that.
Speaker 10: The
Speaker 8: demolition of Block B3 has been
Speaker 10: completed.
Speaker 10: All technical department personnel must submit their data to the analysis group.
Speaker 11: So this is what the enemy looks like up close.
Speaker 5: Magnificent.
Speaker 5: Everything except the core has been left intact.
Speaker 5: This is an almost perfect sample.
Speaker 5: Thanks, this will be a great help.
Speaker 5: Okay, so have you found anything new yet?
Speaker 5: What's that mean?
Speaker 5: That's our system's code number for "cannot be analyzed."
Speaker 5: You mean you have no idea what this is?
Speaker 5: Yeah. What we do know is that the Angel is composed of a type of matter characterized by both particulate and waveform properties.
Speaker 9: But
Speaker 5: you've at least found its power source, right?
Speaker 5: Something like that. But we haven't been able to figure out how it operates at all.
Speaker 5: So we finally found something outside our experience.
Speaker 5: It's a whole new world of mysteries. For example, take a look at this.
Speaker 5: This is the angel's inherent waveform pattern.
Speaker 5: Oh!
Speaker 9: What about
Speaker 5: it?
Speaker 5: It can't be!
Speaker 5: Yes. Although
Speaker 8: composed of
Speaker 5: a different form of matter,
Speaker 5: their actual composition in terms of the arrangement and coordinates of the pattern
Speaker 5: is a 99.89% match to ours.
Speaker 9: 99.89%?
Speaker 5: Yes. Once again, we must acknowledge how limited our level of understanding really is.
Speaker 5: Okay,
Speaker 8: okay, stop.
Speaker 12: This is the core sample.
Speaker 12: What about the rest of it?
Speaker 12: There's not much left of it.
Speaker 4: I don't think we can use it as a reference.
Speaker 4: That's not a problem. Dispose of the rest of it.
Speaker 9: Yes, sir!
Speaker 9: What's wrong?
Speaker 9: Well, uh, nothing.
Speaker 9: Shinji, are you aware that when you say nothing in that tone of voice,
Speaker 9: you might as well be shouting for us to pay attention to you?
Speaker 9: Nothing draws attention like evasive actions.
Speaker 9: Uh,
Speaker 11: well, it's just that my father seems to have burned his hands.
Speaker 11: Burned them?
Speaker 11: Huh?
Speaker 5: I was just wondering how it happened.
Speaker 5: I'm not sure.
Speaker 5: Do you know?
Speaker 5: It was before you joined us.
Speaker 5: Unit Zero went berserk during the activation trials.
Speaker 5: You've heard about that.
Speaker 11: Yeah?
Speaker 5: It was bad.
Speaker 5: The pilot was trapped inside the Ava.
Speaker 5: Ray Ionami.
Speaker 5: Was she the pilot?
Speaker 5: Yes, and it was Commander Ikari who rescued her.
Speaker 5: He opened the superheated hatch with his bare hands.
Speaker 11: Bullshit! My father did that?
Speaker 5: Yes, he really did. That's how he burned his hands.
Speaker 13: Hey! Over here!
Speaker 13: - Oh, man, whoa!
Speaker 13: - Oh, man!
Speaker 2: - Oh, man!
Speaker 2: - Don't lay down there, man!
Speaker 2: I'm so sorry!
Speaker 2: - Oh, my God, those guys are looking at us!
Speaker 2: - Hey!
Speaker 13: - Yeah, they've all got such incredible breasts.
Speaker 13: - Uh-huh.
Speaker 13: - Hey, Big Shot.
Speaker 13: - What are you staring at so intently?
Speaker 13: - Uh-nothing.
Speaker 13: - Who?
Speaker 13: - He's ogling right.
Speaker 13: - I-I am not.
Speaker 13: Ah, come on! We saw you lurking!
Speaker 13: Yeah, it raised mammaries.
Speaker 13: -Ugh! -Race silky thighs.
Speaker 11: -Yeah! -Her calves.
Speaker 11: -Her... -Noddy bits!
Speaker 11: Uh, look, it's nothing like that.
Speaker 11: Then just what were you looking at?
Speaker 13: You can't fool
Speaker 8: us, Shinji.
Speaker 11: Mmm...
Speaker 11: Oh...
Speaker 11: I was just wondering why she's always alone.
Speaker 13: Huh?
Speaker 13: Uh, come to think of it,
Speaker 13: she hasn't had any friends since she started here in the seventh grade.
Speaker 13: There's just something about her that makes her hard to talk to.
Speaker 13: Like she's in her own world.
Speaker 13: She's probably just got a lousy personality.
Speaker 13: You two are both Ava pilots, right?
Speaker 13: You ought to know her better than any of us, Shinji.
Speaker 13: Know what I mean?
Speaker 13: Yeah, that's right.
Speaker 1: I suppose.
Speaker 1: But we don't talk.
Speaker 10: Ava Unit 1 is now entering the third stage cooling process.
Speaker 10: Lower all systems to Phase 3 and Cage 6.
Speaker 10: The harmonics and synchronization test results were good. All numerical conditions have been satisfied.
Speaker 8: Roger, transmit
Speaker 10: the results to Balthazar.
Speaker 10: Roger.
Speaker 10: Transmitting the full range of the entry plug's personal data files to Melchior.
Speaker 10: Data transmitting.
Speaker 3: This is Melchior. Roger. Circuits
Speaker 12: connected.
Speaker 10: Initiating third stage cooling process. CBL circulation has begun.
Speaker 12: Vent liquid waste to second purification system.
Speaker 10: T-minus 1,050 minutes until the Unit Zero reactivation experiment.
Speaker 7: What is this stuff?
Speaker 7: It's curry.
Speaker 7: You mean you're still eating this instant junk?
Speaker 7: Look, you're a guest, so you've got no right to complain.
Speaker 11: Misato, don't you want any?
Speaker 9: Oh, sorry about that.
Speaker 9: Ta-da!
Speaker 9: Slot some of that stuff on top of this stuff.
Speaker 11: You can't be serious.
Speaker 11: Go
Speaker 9: on! It's yummy to the max.
Speaker 9: Okay.
Speaker 9: Ordinary curry-flavored instant ramen can't be this good.
Speaker 9: Yeah! Come on, let's eat.
Speaker 9: Dig in, guys.
Speaker 9: The trick is to put less hot water in the soup
Speaker 9: so it forms the sludge.
Speaker 7: Masato cooked, right?
Speaker 7: You can tell?
Speaker 7: Of course.
Speaker 7: Who else could make instant soup taste so awful?
Speaker 7: Next time you invite me over, make sure it's Shinji's turn to cook.
Speaker 5: You know, Shinji, you really ought to consider moving out. You shouldn't let one bad roommate
Speaker 5: ruin your entire life, you know.
Speaker 5: But I'm used
Speaker 11: to it now.
Speaker 9: He's right, Ritsuko.
Speaker 9: Never underestimate the ability of the human animal
Speaker 9: to adapt to its environment, right?
Speaker 9: And anyway, if he doesn't move--
Speaker 9: Oh.
Speaker 9: Shinji, can I have another?
Speaker 9: Right.
Speaker 9: He's going to have to go through an awful lot of trouble
Speaker 9: in red tape.
Speaker 9: He just got his permanent security card, you know.
Speaker 8: Oh,
Speaker 5: I almost forgot again.
Speaker 5: Shinji, I need a favor.
Speaker 5: Ah, here it is.
Speaker 5: What is
Speaker 11: it?
Speaker 5: This is Rei's new security card. I keep forgetting to give this to her.
Speaker 5: Would you mind delivering this to her before you go into headquarters?
Speaker 11: Uh, sure.
Speaker 9: What's the matter? You're staring at Rei's picture, aren't you?
Speaker 9: Ah, I'm not!
Speaker 9: Oh yes you are, Shinji.
Speaker 6: I was not!
Speaker 9: I think I embarrassed him.
Speaker 9: Now you've got an excuse to go over to Ray's place, don't you?
Speaker 9: Stop teasing me!
Speaker 9: But I love teasing you. You go so ballistic.
Speaker 9: Just like Misato.
Speaker 9: I
Speaker 11: just find it strange that I know so little about her, even though we're both Eva pilots.
Speaker 11: She's
Speaker 5: a nice girl, but she's like your father.
Speaker 5: She's not very adept at...
Speaker 11: She's not very adept at what?
Speaker 5: Living, I guess.
*Drums*
Speaker 11: Hello there!
Speaker 11: I'm sorry for intruding.
Speaker 11: It's me, Shinji Ikari.
Speaker 11: I'm coming in, okay?
Speaker 11: These can't be Ray's.
Speaker 5: Hmm.
Speaker 11: Uh...
Speaker 11: Um, Ray, I...
Speaker 11: I didn't mean...
Speaker 9: Will you get off?
Speaker 11: What?
Speaker 11: Well, I was asked to...
Speaker 11: I was asked to...
Speaker 11: You know, so I...
Speaker 11: What was it?
Speaker 11: The card.
Speaker 11: Your card.
Speaker 11: It's been renewed.
Speaker 11: So I was asked to deliver it.
Speaker 11: I didn't mean for any of this to happen.
Speaker 8: Ritsuko
Speaker 11: said she forgot to give it to you.
Speaker 11: It's true.
Speaker 11: I rang your bell, but there was no reply.
Speaker 11: And the door was unlocked, so I...
Speaker 11: Hmm?
Speaker 10: Central
Speaker 11: Dogma is currently open
Speaker 10: to the public.
Speaker 10: Group 3 should proceed to direct gate 4.
Speaker 11: Here.
Speaker 11: This is your new card.
Speaker 11: Ritsuko told me to deliver this to you?
Speaker 11: Look, I'm sorry.
Speaker 11: About what?
Speaker 11: Aren't you going to have a reactivation test today?
Speaker 11: Aren't you scared, right?
Speaker 11: Aren't you afraid of piloting Unit Zero?
Speaker 11: Why?
Speaker 11: Well, I heard that you were hurt pretty bad in an earlier experiment, so I thought you might be...
Speaker 11: Aren't you Commander Ikari's son?
Speaker 11: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 11: Don't you have faith in your own father's work?
Speaker 11: No, of course not! How could I ever trust him again?
Speaker 11: What's wrong?
Speaker 8: Oh, oh.
Speaker 5: Rey! Are you alright?
Speaker 5: It was bad. The pilot was trapped inside the Ava.
Speaker 5: And it was Commander Ikari who rescued her.
Speaker 5: He opened the superheated hatch with his bare hands.
*Sounds of the
Speaker 10: to phase two.
Speaker 3: Connecting pilot to unit zero.
Speaker 10: Opening circuits. Pulse and harmonics are normal.
Speaker 10: No problems
Speaker 3: detected. We are in sync. All nerve links completed. Central nerve system elements
Speaker 3: are nominal. Recalculating. No error corrections. The
Speaker 2: checklist is satisfactory up to 2590.
Speaker 2: Approaching critical mark, 2.5 more. 1.7, 1.2, 1.0, 0.8, 0.6, 0.5, 0.4, 0.3, 0.2, 0.1 and rising. Borderline clear. Unit zero
Speaker 9: has been activated.
Speaker 12: Ikari, an unidentified object is rapidly approaching nerve central.
Speaker 12: It may be the fifth angel.
Speaker 12: Abort
Speaker 4: the test. Place all operations on first stage alert.
Speaker 4: You're not going to use Unit Zero, are you?
Speaker 4: She's not ready to fight yet. Unit One status?
Speaker 5: It can be ready in 380 seconds.
Speaker 4: Make it so.
Speaker 5: Yes, sir.
Speaker 4: Ray?
Speaker 4: Reactivation has been successfully completed. Return now.
Speaker 2: The target
Speaker 3: is passing over Tonosawa.
Speaker 3: Unit 1 is beginning launch sequence.
Speaker 3: Releasing primary lock bolts.
Speaker 11: Lock bolts released.
Speaker 3: Roger. Removing secondary restraint.
Speaker 3: Roger. The target is now insuring into Lake Ashino airspace.
Speaker 3: AVA, Unit 1 is ready for launch.
Speaker 9: Launch, AVA!
Speaker 3: We're detecting a high-energy reaction inside the target.
Speaker 1: What'd
Speaker 5: you say?
Speaker 5: The
Speaker 3: energy torus is accelerating and massing upon itself.
Speaker 5: It can't be!
Speaker 5: *Mario's
scream*
Speaker 5: Look out, duck!
Speaker 6: Huh?
*Screaming*
Speaker 8: No, Shinji!
Bring me to the moon and let me play among the stars
Speaker 6: Let me see why spring is like when Jupiter enlires
Another rose, hold
Speaker 8: my hand
Another love, darling, kiss me
Speaker 6: Fill my heart with song and let me sing forevermore
Speaker 6: You are all I love for, all my voice, a man I don't
Speaker 6: And all the love leads me to you.
Speaker 6: In all the wars
I love you.
Speaker 9: Shinji survives, but he's injured and begins to deteriorate badly
Speaker 9: to the point where Rei is to take over in the next battle.
Speaker 9: As Misato desperately tries to pinpoint the Angel's weak spot,
Speaker 9: the ultimate in heavy artillery is prepared to face the new menace.
Speaker 9: Will she succeed
Speaker 5: in time to save Ray?