Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at you,
Speaker 1: I'm smiling.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to see you,
Speaker 1: I'm not even curious.
Speaker 1: I'm still not sure about you,
Speaker 1: but I'm not sure about you.
Speaker 1: But I'm sure you'll notice that
Speaker 1: The back of the future is a great place to look for the future
Speaker 1: The cruel and cruel world of the world will soon be
Speaker 1: The dark world will soon be on the edge of the world
The
*Bad*
Speaker 2: Although there was a great deal of damage as a result, the fact that Shinji Ikari, a boy with no prior EVA experience, managed to accomplish the mission against an unknown enemy, deserves special notice.
Speaker 2: However, for the Department of Strategic Operations, it was a difficult battle that would reveal many problem areas that were in desperate need of improvement.
Speaker 3: *Gunshot
Speaker 3: so stupid. I'm gonna find the jerks who hurt my sister and teach them a lesson they'll
Speaker 3: never forget.
Speaker 4: We'd already had a lot of evacuation training at the school, so we didn't really think it was that serious.
Speaker 4: The guys were all acting like jerks as usual, like they were on a field trip, and none of the girls were afraid either.
Speaker 5: I'm not sure
*BANG*
*Gunshot*
Speaker 6: Shinji never really told me what really happened, but if I had to guess, I'd say that Rei must have tried to sacrifice herself in order to protect Unit 1 from the enemy's particle beam.
Speaker 6: The reason I'm so sure about this is Rei herself. I don't think she has much respect for her own existence.
Speaker 6: She's not just pessimistic. Hell, a lot of kids our age are like that.
Speaker 6: No, it's something much, much more. But nobody ever tells me nothing.
Speaker 6: Then...
*Ezio
Speaker 7: The United Nations combined Navy lost one third of its entire fleet in this encounter.
Speaker 7: At least the lost ships belong to your country. The damage is negligible.
Speaker 8: Quite true. It was fortunate that so much of the damage was inconsequential.
*Gunshot*
YAAAAAAAHHHHHHHHH!!!
*Squeak*
I'm sorry.
The End
*Gun
Speaker 9: Hmm, this isn't good. It's happening too early.
Speaker 8: Yes. This did not occur in accordance with our predictions of when an Angel would invade Nerv.
Speaker 8: And
Speaker 7: to make it worse, you let it intrude into Central Dogma itself.
Speaker 7: If contact had occurred, then our entire project
Speaker 8: could have ended in disaster, Ikari.
Speaker 8: The report to this committee was in error. There is no fact behind this tale of an Angel invasion.
Speaker 9: Ikari, are you saying that the Eleventh Angel's intrusion never occurred?
Speaker 9: Yes.
Speaker 8: Watch your words carefully, Ikari. Lying to this committee is perishable by death.
Speaker 8: If you wish confirmation, check the Magi's data recorders. No such incident was ever recorded.
Speaker 9: This is absurd.
Speaker 8: We all
Speaker 9: know that bearing the
Speaker 10: truth is your specialty.
Speaker 10: The time
Speaker 8: schedule is being carried out in accordance with the descriptions in the Dead Sea Scrolls.
Speaker 10: Alright, we won't discuss any possible guilt or punishment this time.
Speaker 10: However, let me remind you that you won't rewrite our scenario.
Speaker 8: I understand. Everything is proceeding according to Zayle's plan.
Speaker 11: Mountains.
Speaker 11: Heavier the mountains.
Speaker 11: But that changes.
Speaker 11: With the passage of time.
Speaker 11: Sky.
Speaker 11: Blue sky.
Speaker 11: What your eyes can't see.
Speaker 11: What your eyes can see.
Speaker 11: The sun.
Speaker 1: One.
Speaker 11: Only one.
Speaker 11: Water.
Speaker 11: It is agreeable.
Speaker 11: Commander Ikari.
Speaker 11: Flowers. So many the same.
Speaker 11: So many without purpose.
Speaker 11: Sky. Sky of red.
Speaker 11: Red the color. The color I hate.
Speaker 11: The liquid flows. It drips, ripples and pours.
Speaker 11: Blood.
Speaker 11: A scent of blood, a woman who does not bleed.
Speaker 11: From the red soil the humans come. Humans made by man and woman.
Speaker 11: City, a human creation.
Speaker 11: Ava, a human creation as well.
Speaker 11: What are humans? Are they creations of God?
Speaker 11: Humans are that which is created by humans.
Speaker 11: This is that which is mine. My life. My heart.
Speaker 11: I am a vessel for my thoughts. The entry plug. Throne of the soul.
Speaker 11: Who is this? This is me. Who am I? What am I? What am I? What am I?
Speaker 11: I am I. This object that is, is myself. That which forms is me.
Speaker 11: This is the self that can be seen and yet this is not like that which is myself.
Speaker 11: A strange feeling. My body feels as if it is melting.
Speaker 11: I can no longer see myself. My form, my shape, fades from view.
Speaker 11: Awareness dawns of someone who is not me. Who is here, there, beyond me here.
Speaker 11: Shinji...
Speaker 11: This person I know, Major Katsuraki.
Speaker 11: Dr. Akaki.
Speaker 11: People.
Speaker 11: My classmates.
Speaker 11: The
Speaker 5: pilot of
Speaker 12: Unit 2.
Speaker 11: Commander Ikari?
Speaker 11: Who are you?
Speaker 12: Who are you?
Speaker 12: So, Rei, how does it feel to be piloting Unit 1 for the first time?
Speaker 5: Smells like Ikari.
Speaker 13: The sync ratio is almost the same as with Unit Zero.
Speaker 13: Unit Zero and Unit One's personal data patterns are almost identical.
Speaker 13: That's what makes this sync experiment possible.
Speaker 13: Error margin is 0.03. Harmonics are normal.
Speaker 13: No detectable problems found for compatibility between Ray and Unit One.
Speaker 13: Okay,
Speaker 12: the test is over, Ray. You can get out now.
Speaker 12: Yes.
*BANG*
Speaker 2: Subject status?
Speaker 13: A bit jittery, but no problems found in the nerve patterns.
Speaker 2: This is his first time in Unit Zero.
Speaker 2: His first time piloting another Ava. It's only natural.
Speaker 14: That's stupid. Why should he care which Ava he's in anyway?
Speaker 14: It makes a difference to Shinji. That's how he is.
Speaker 14: I know that. He's such a dork.
Speaker 14: So why aren't you running these compatibility tests on me? Is there something wrong with me?
Speaker 14: Well, we didn't think he'd want to pilot any Ava except
Speaker 2: yours.
Speaker 14: Yeah, that's
Speaker 2: true, isn't it?
Speaker 2: I don't know if Unit 2 would even be compatible.
Beginning entry. LCL
Speaker 15: electrolyzed.
Speaker 12: Commence first connection.
Speaker 1: Shinji,
Speaker 13: how do you feel in Unit 0's entry plug?
Speaker 1: It feels kind of weird.
Speaker 15: Like incompatibility?
Speaker 1: Not like that.
Speaker 1: This thing
smells like rain.
Speaker 12: It smells like what?
Speaker 14: That's a mensch.
Speaker 12: Data received.
Speaker 12: Reconfirming.
Speaker 13: Pattern green.
Speaker 12: All restraints are nominal.
Speaker 13: Acknowledged.
Speaker 13: Now let's shift the mutual compatibility test to the second stage.
Speaker 13: Unit zero, entering second contact.
Speaker 13: How's it look?
Speaker 13: As I thought.
Speaker 13: The sync ratio is lower than that of unit one.
Speaker 13: Hmm, harmonics are all normal.
Speaker 13: But these are still good readings.
Speaker 13: These numbers mean that we can implement our current plan.
Speaker 13: You mean the tummy system? Ma'am, I'm really not sure that we should proceed.
Speaker 13: I understand your feelings on this, but we always have to be prepared for all options.
Speaker 13: It's our guarantee of survival.
Speaker 13: You know that I've always respected you, ma'am, and I still believe in our work.
Speaker 13: But I'm afraid I'm really not convinced.
Speaker 13: People who develop too many scruples will always have some difficulty working amongst others.
Speaker 13: You'll learn once you've gotten your hands dirty. You'll see.
*Gasp*
Speaker 16: Initiate third connection.
Speaker 16: Self-state of Minecraft is stable.
Speaker 13: It's Shinji missing Mama's breath.
Speaker 13: Has it been in her womb or what?
Speaker 13: Asuka, stop interrupting. You're being obnoxious.
Speaker 14: Yeah, yeah. I don't get it. Why does everyone around here always pamper him?
Speaker 13: Commence A10 nerve connections. Harmonics level plus 20.
Speaker 1: What the hell? Something's trying to get into my brain.
Speaker 1: Uh...
Uh...
Speaker 11: W-Rei?
Speaker 12: Uh...Rei Ayanami?
Speaker 12: Ah...
Speaker 12: This feeling...impression...
Speaker 12: Rei...
Speaker 12: It's hers!
Speaker 12: What's happening?!
Speaker 12: There's
Speaker 7: a problem in the pilot's nerve pulse!
Speaker 12: Mental contamination starting!
Speaker 12: Impossible! This can't happen at this plug tap!
Speaker 12: It's not FROM the plug!
Speaker 12: The intrusion is coming from the angle!
Speaker 12: Unit zero is out of control!
Speaker 12: Shut all circuits!
Speaker 12: Cut the power!
Speaker 12: Ava switched to reserve power!
Speaker 12: Ava
Speaker 3: is still activated.
Speaker 12: Shinji status!
Speaker 3: The circuit's closed.
Speaker 3: We can't monitor him!
Speaker 3: Unit
Speaker 12: zero is rejecting Shinji.
Speaker 12: Negative! The auto-ejection! It doesn't work!
Speaker 12: The same error. The same one.
Speaker 12: Is it trying to absorb Shinji?
Speaker 15: Break it back here!
Speaker 15: Break it!
Speaker 15: Activation will terminate in seven seconds!
Speaker 15: Six, five, four,
three, two, one, zero!
Speaker 2: Zero, activation terminated.
Speaker 2: Hurry up and get the pilot out of there!
Speaker 2: Did Unit Zero just try to kill Ray?
Speaker 2: Do you think this could be related to the incident that occurred when Ray was the pilot?
Speaker 2: I can't tell you much right now.
Speaker 2: The only thing I'm sure of is that we must reconfigure Unit Zero for Ray's personal data
Speaker 2: and run a new synchronization test between Ray and the Zero as soon as possible.
Speaker 2: As the director of operations, I request that it be done as soon as possible,
Speaker 2: before there are further problems.
Speaker 2: I understand that,
Speaker 13: Major Katsuragi.
Speaker 13: Right.
Speaker 13: Unit Zero wanted to attack me.
Speaker 13: That's got to be it.
Speaker 15: He said hello. Do you understand me? He said yeah. This is great. So what's the top of the house? He said room. And what's the texture of sandpaper there? This is amazing. He said rubbed. And who's
the greatest baseball player of all time?
Speaker 1: Again, I hate this ceiling.
Speaker 1: The
Speaker 16: hospital says Shinji has regained consciousness.
Speaker 6: No signs of mental contamination.
Speaker 6: But he doesn't remember what happened.
Speaker 14: Right.
Speaker 14: Misato and Kashi won't tell me anything about her.
Speaker 14: Even Shinji doesn't know anything.
Speaker 14: Just what is the first child?
Speaker 16: The Angels' invasion of headquarters was a deviation from our scheduled scenario.
Speaker 16: The committees found out about it and are applying pressure.
Speaker 16: They're buzzing around
Speaker 8: our heads like a swarm of hornets, looking for things to complain about.
Speaker 8: We hold all the tiles, all the winds and dragons. There is nothing they can do.
Speaker 8: That doesn't mean we want to keep tipping
Speaker 16: our hand.
Speaker 8: If Sele starts to interfere,
Speaker 16: there could
Speaker 8: be trouble.
Speaker 8: Everything is going according to the scenario.
Speaker 8: No problems exist.
Speaker 8: What about
Speaker 16: the Unit Zero incident?
Speaker 16: That was not in our scenario.
Speaker 16: It will have no effect. Ray's
Speaker 8: resynchronization test was successful.
Speaker 8: You're too concerned about protecting Ray, Akari?
Speaker 8: What's the status of the ATOM project?
Speaker 8: Proceeding. It's less than 2% behind schedule.
Speaker 8: Then the Lance of Longinus is...
Speaker 8: Is going according to plan. Ray is handling the operation.
We'll be right back.
Speaker 17: In other words, hold my hand
Speaker 17: In other words, darling kiss me
Speaker 17: Fill my heart with soul
Speaker 17: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 17: You are all I love for all I love
Speaker 17: I love you
Speaker 17: Innu de mo, please be true
Speaker 17: Inna de mo, I
love you
Speaker 18: With her friends getting married one after another, Misato starts to feel a little insecure
Speaker 18: Always a bridesmaid, she might just end up spending the rest of her life going to wedding showers and never finding anyone for herself.
Speaker 18: Could a reunion with Kashi be her last chance?
Speaker 18: In the next episode, the old
Speaker 5: biological clock goes tick, tick, tick.