Speaker 1: The young man like a young man
Speaker 1: You are a young man, you are a young man
Speaker 1: The wind is now on the door
Speaker 1: I'm just looking at you
Speaker 1: I'm so happy
Speaker 2: This
Speaker 3: is Ecta64 calling the
Speaker 2: end of the world.
Speaker 2: Neopat 400, confirm cumulonimbus clouds in your immediate flight path, over.
Speaker 2: This is Neopat 400, cumulonimbus clouds confirmed.
Speaker 2: Parameter indicates no hazard.
Speaker 2: We'll maintain course. Expect to arrive on schedule.
Speaker 2: This is Ecta 64. Roger it out.
Speaker 4: I'm ready. Where's Asuka?
Speaker 4: She's taken off already.
Speaker 4: It would seem that
Speaker 5: she doesn't want to face us right now.
Speaker 5: But why?
Speaker 5: A teenage girl can be difficult to understand, Shinji.
Speaker 3: By the way...
Speaker 3: Um, well...
Speaker 4: Well, go ahead.
Speaker 4: Are the rumors about Unit 4 really true?
Speaker 4: I heard that there was some kind of accident and it exploded.
Speaker 5: Yes, I'm afraid so.
Speaker 5: Unit 4 is gone, alone with the second branch of nerve.
Speaker 5: It happened while they were testing the S2 engine.
Speaker 5: But don't worry, we'll be all right.
Speaker 5: All three of our Avas are functioning properly,
Speaker 5: And our pilots
Speaker 4: and staff are in good shape, too.
Speaker 4: I also heard that Unit 3 is being brought here.
Speaker 4: You're performing the activation tests at Matsushiro, aren't you?
Speaker 5: Uh-huh.
Speaker 5: I'll be out for four days or so, but don't worry.
Speaker 5: Akashi's coming over to take care of you guys.
Speaker 4: But what about the test?
Speaker 5: Oh, Ritsuko will be supervising everything.
Speaker 5: There won't be any problems.
Speaker 4: And who will be the pilot?
Speaker 5: Well, the pilot is...
Speaker 6: Yes.
Speaker 6: Good morning, Major Katsuragi. I've come to ask for your help.
Speaker 6: I'm begging you. Please, please.
Speaker 6: You've just got to choose me as the pilot for Evangelion Unit 3. You gotta!
Speaker 7: So, Shinji still doesn't know, huh?
Speaker 7: I just can't find a chance to tell him. I'm worried.
Speaker 7: Sometimes I just can't figure out what he's
Speaker 5: thinking about.
Speaker 5: Oh,
Speaker 7: get a grip, kid. You're the one who wanted to be his guardian.
Speaker 5: Yeah, you're right, of course.
Speaker 5: Um, so, when will you acquire the new pilot?
Speaker 7: Tomorrow. There's still a few details to be ironed out.
Speaker 7: Maybe the new pilot will tell Shinji himself.
Speaker 7: Oh, I rather doubt it. This one wasn't very enthused about the prospect at all.
Speaker 7: He won't talk. He only accepted under the condition that his younger sister be transferred into our private hospital.
Speaker 6: How can Miss Otto be so cruel?
Speaker 6: I'm dying to be pilot, so why won't she use me?
Speaker 6: Even as a backup pilot, it's just not fair.
Speaker 8: Yeah.
Speaker 4: Hey, what's up?
Speaker 4: You left before me, but you're getting here late.
Speaker 8: No fight between the newlyweds today?
Speaker 9: I just didn't want to see your ugly faces!
Speaker 9: You damn three students!
Speaker 9: Oh, for dust, idiot!
Speaker 6: Ow!
Speaker 6: Ah, the precious moment of lunchtime.
Speaker 6: Hey, where's Toji?
Speaker 6: I haven't seen him.
Speaker 6: You mean he left?
Speaker 6: Without his lunch?
Speaker 6: Toji the stomach?
Speaker 4: That's impossible!
Speaker 4: Well, he's been acting different.
Speaker 4: Mr. Susahoe?
Speaker 8: Oh, it's you, Ayanami.
Speaker 8: If you're looking for Shinji, he's not here.
Speaker 8: You know, don't you, about everything?
Speaker 8: I think Asuka knows, too.
Speaker 8: So Shinji's the only one who doesn't know.
Speaker 8: You know, it's pretty rare for you to be concerned about someone else.
Speaker 10: It is? I'm not sure I understand.
Speaker 8: Oh, you have a thing about Shinji, all right.
Speaker 10: I? Maybe that
Speaker 4: is true.
Speaker 8: You do.
Speaker 4: - Hikari! - Let's have lunch
Speaker 5: together!
Speaker 5: Okay.
Speaker 5: He's over two hours late,
Speaker 7: but at last he's finally here.
Speaker 7: This is the first time I've ever waited for someone this long.
Speaker 7: That's because you never waited for guys back when you could still get a date.
Speaker 7: Oh, shut up.
Speaker 11: This was the so-called second impact.
Speaker 11: At that time, I was living in a place called Nebukawa,
Speaker 11: but the rising water levels caused by the melting of Antarctica
Speaker 11: have buried it beneath the sea.
Speaker 8: I'm sorry, newcomer, but I had to clobber you.
Speaker 8: I had to beat you to work off my own anger.
Speaker 10: Um, I'm sorry, Asuka.
Speaker 10: You usually walk home with Shinji, don't you?
Speaker 9: I only walk with Shinji because we work together.
Speaker 9: And right now I don't be like looking at him.
Speaker 9: Oh.
Speaker 10: This is about
Speaker 9: Toji, isn't it?
Speaker 9: Yeah, how'd you know?
Speaker 9: Everybody knows.
Speaker 9: The Three Stooges are the only ones who don't.
Speaker 10: Shinji seems sensitive in a naive kind
Speaker 9: of way.
Speaker 9: Shinji's a big fat dork!
Speaker 9: And he's denser than lead, too.
Speaker 9: He wouldn't know how to relate to another person if you gave him a manual!
Speaker 10: Oh, I
Speaker 9: see.
Speaker 10: Asuka?
Speaker 10: I think that Toji might be interested in Rei.
Speaker 10: Are you kidding?
Speaker 10: Toji and Wonder Girl?
Speaker 10: Well, lunch, they
Speaker 9: seem...
Speaker 9: Don't worry, Hikari.
Speaker 9: It'll never happen.
Speaker 9: If Shinji is denser than lead, then Rei Ayanami is off the atomic scale.
Speaker 9: Really?
Speaker 9: Yep.
Hmm.
Speaker 12: Can I ask you something?
Speaker 12: Okay.
Speaker 12: Just what do you see in a dumb jock like that?
Speaker 12: Is
Speaker 10: the...
Speaker 10: passionate side.
Speaker 10: What?
It was a mistake to get back with you.
How can you say that now?
There are a lot of pit holes in life,
but you just have to dig your way out.
Speaker 9: You know, Asuka...
Speaker 9: Kashi sure spends a lot of time in the tub.
Speaker 4: I wonder who's going to pilot Unit 3.
Speaker 9: What? You mean you haven't heard?
Speaker 4: Who is it?
Speaker 4: Yes.
The only reason I came back to you
so we could break up again.
Speaker 9: I don't know.
Speaker 13: Yeah, that was refreshing.
Speaker 13: Are you two fighting again?
Speaker 13: I don't believe it.
Speaker 13: Are you two always like this whenever Katsuragi's gone?
Speaker 13: It's not like
Speaker 14: that.
Speaker 14: I want to be happy, Kaji,
Speaker 14: especially since you're spending the night,
Speaker 14: but I can't.
Speaker 14: Not tonight.
Speaker 14: Not now.
Speaker 14: Not with everything.
Speaker 13: I understand.
Speaker 13: Let's go to bed.
Speaker 13: I find that's usually the best thing to do
Speaker 13: in this kind of situation.
Speaker 4: Hey, are you asleep yet, Gachi?
Speaker 13: No, not yet.
Speaker 4: Well, can you tell me what my father's like?
Speaker 13: Well, there's a surprise question.
Speaker 13: I would have thought you'd have asked about Katsuragi.
Speaker 4: It seems like you're always with my father.
Speaker 13: Commander Fuyutsuki is the one who's always with him.
Speaker 13: Have you been asking around about your father?
Speaker 13: I
Speaker 4: just haven't been around him much.
Speaker 13: So, you really don't know him.
Speaker 4: But I've learned a lot about him lately.
Speaker 4: I've learned how he feels about his work.
Speaker 4: About my
Speaker 13: mother.
Speaker 13: No, you're wrong, Shinji.
Speaker 13: You only believe that you've learned.
Speaker 13: But people really can't understand themselves, much less each other.
Speaker 13: Understanding 100% of anything is impossible.
Speaker 13: That's why we spend so much time trying to understand our own motivations
Speaker 13: and those of others. That's what makes life so interesting.
Speaker 4: So you can't understand Misato either.
Speaker 13: The kanji that we use for the word she means a woman far away, and women will always seem
Speaker 13: to be on a distant shore. The gulf that separates male and female is broader and deeper than
Speaker 13: any ocean.
Speaker 4: I just don't understand
Speaker 13: adults.
Speaker 1: T-minus 300 minutes to Unit 3 activation test.
Speaker 15: Primary power standing by.
Speaker 1: Repairs to left arm crimp log completed.
Speaker 1: Returning system in all sections of the unit.
Speaker 1: Roger. Team B, commence operation.
Speaker 15: Data link to Avangelion Unit 1 established.
Speaker 7: The system's all up and ready for full activation.
Speaker 7: Terrific. Let's get started.
Speaker 7: That was enthusiastic.
Speaker 7: You're aware that this unit will be assigned to your detachment once it's passed its tests, aren't you?
Speaker 7: Exclusive control of four Avas.
Speaker 7: If you wanted to, you could conquer the world.
Speaker 7: So, have you told Shinji yet?
Speaker 7: I'll tell him after the test.
Speaker 5: The fourth child has arrived.
Speaker 5: Squad 2, begin entry preparations immediately.
Speaker 5: Toji
Speaker 10: hasn't shown up yet, Asuka.
Speaker 10: Yeah, he may not come today.
Speaker 10: I thought we might eat together today.
Speaker 10: Do you want this?
Speaker 6: Unit 3's already arrived in Japan, hasn't it?
Speaker 4: Yeah,
Speaker 6: it got here yesterday.
Speaker 6: This sucks. Who's going to pilot it then?
Speaker 6: Told you he was absent today. Maybe it's him.
Speaker 6: I don't think so.
Speaker 6: Entry flux
Speaker 16: secure.
Speaker 16: Initiating burst connection.
Speaker 15: Transmitting pulse. Graph readout is normal.
Speaker 16: All checklists up to 1350 have been cleared.
Speaker 15: Phase 1 contact all cleared.
Speaker 7: Roger. Operation will proceed to Phase 2.
Speaker 15: Full nerve link established.
Speaker 15: Level is 10-5-5. Harmonics are reading standard.
Speaker 15: We are now approaching the absolute border.
Speaker 7: Break the nerve circuits! Abort the test!
Speaker 7: No! Mission
Speaker 3: failure! We've got high
Speaker 1: energy readings in
Speaker 14: the body!
Speaker 14: An angel!
Speaker 3: No!
Speaker 2: There's been an explosion in
Speaker 3: Matsushiro!
Speaker 3: Damage
Speaker 16: level unknown.
Speaker 2: Send the rescue squad in 3rd Battalion.
Speaker 2: We've gotta handle this before the self-defense force gets involved.
Speaker 17: Roger!
Speaker 17: We've got an unidentified object detected at the site.
Speaker 17: Its pattern is orange.
Speaker 17: We can't confirm that it's an angel yet.
Speaker 17: Go to first stage alert.
Speaker 18: All personnel, go to first stage alert.
Speaker 18: Prepare for surface-to-surface combat.
Speaker 18: All Avas, prepare for launch.
Speaker 18: First for maximum intercept potential.
Speaker 18: Air transportation to Matsushiro will go in 20.
Speaker 3: An accident
Speaker 4: in Matsushiro?
Speaker 4: It can't be.
Speaker 4: What happened
Speaker 9: to Misato?
Speaker 9: Contact hasn't been restored yet.
Speaker 4: What are we going to do? We need her.
Speaker 9: We're going to have to go for it ourselves.
Speaker 9: There aren't any other options left open for us, are there?
Speaker 4: But how can we find an angel without her?
Speaker 16: Commander Curry will command this operation.
Speaker 6: My father will?
Speaker 6: We're receiving an image of the target from the Nobe Mountain Station.
Speaker 6: Transpiring to the main monitor.
Speaker 17: As we suspected.
Speaker 17: Transmit the abort signal. Eject the unit's entry plug.
Speaker 18: It's not working, sir. Neither the abort or plug ejection codes are being accepted.
Speaker 17: What about the pilot?
Speaker 17: His heart's still beating and he's still breathing. But he's probably...
Speaker 17: I see. Then we must accept the loss of Evangelion Unit 3. Reclassify it as the 13th Angel.
Speaker 7: What?
Speaker 7: But, sir...
Speaker 17: Deploy our forces around the base of Mount Nobe. The target must be destroyed.
Speaker 2: Target is approaching. All units, prepare to engage.
Speaker 19: Huh? It can't be.
Speaker 19: Is that the
Speaker 4: Angel?
Speaker 17: Correct. That is your target.
Speaker 4: It may be our target, but it's also an Ava, isn't it?
Speaker 4: God damn him. How could it have been possessed?
Speaker 4: If that thing is an Ava, then there must be another pilot inside it, isn't there?
Speaker 3: You mean you still don't know that? The
pilot of Unit 3--
Speaker 3: Huh? Asuka?
Speaker 3: *Screams*
Speaker 19: *Screams*
Speaker 19: ASKUAAA!
Speaker 19: *Screams
*
*Screams*
Speaker 18: AVA Unit 2, cease transmitting!
Speaker 18: The pilot's ejected. Recovery teams are moving in for retrieval.
Speaker 18: Target is moving towards Unit 0's position.
Speaker 17: Ray, stop it, but avoid close range combat.
Speaker 17: I'll send Unit 1 in to support you.
Speaker 17: Yes, sir.
Speaker 10: But the pilot is...
Speaker 18: The angel is merging itself into Unit Zero's arm!
Speaker 18: Nerve contamination spreading!
Speaker 17: Sever the left arm immediately.
Speaker 18: But the pilot's nerve connections are still active!
Speaker 17: Cut it off!
Speaker 18: Right.
Speaker 4: *Screams
*
Speaker 4: There's somebody inside it, isn't there?
Speaker 4: Another kid just like me.
Speaker 19: Oh, an injury plug.
Speaker 19: I knew it.
Speaker 19: I knew there was someone in there.
Speaker 15: You don't want life support systems failing!
Speaker 15: Pilot life functions are endangered!
Speaker 15: Damn it!
Speaker 15: Cut our pilot's seek ratio down to 60%!
Speaker 17: Belay that!
Speaker 17: But Akari, if we don't, the pilot could be killed.
Speaker 17: Shinji, why aren't you fighting?
Speaker 19: I can't!
Speaker 19: There's still a person inside that thing.
Speaker 17: Irrelevant. It's an angel. Destroy our enemy.
Speaker 19: I can't. If he's alive, we've got to help him.
Speaker 19: I can't kill another human being.
Speaker 17: It's him or you.
Speaker 19: No! I'd rather die!
Speaker 17: Damn it. Shut down all of Unit 1's synchronization circuits immediately.
Speaker 18: Shut them down?
Speaker 17: Correct. Switch all control to the dummy plug system.
Speaker 17: But
Speaker 18: sir, the dummy plug isn't fully operational yet.
Speaker 18: Dr. Akagi hasn't approved its use!
Speaker 17: It's still better than the current pilot!
Speaker 17: Do it!
Speaker 17: Yes, sir.
Speaker 15: What's going on?
Speaker 15: What the hell are you doing, father?
Speaker 15: Signal reception is green.
Speaker 18: Control system
Speaker 16: switching is complete.
Speaker 15: All nerves linked to the dummy system.
Speaker 15: 32
Speaker 16: .8% of emotional elements are unclear. It can't be monitored.
Speaker 16: Sir?
Speaker 17: Irrelevant. Engage the system. Commence attack.
Speaker 17: *BANG*
Speaker 18: My god, is this what the dummy plug is for?
Gains are still increasing.
I'm gonna die.
Speaker 3: Stop it!
Speaker 3: Father!
Speaker 1: Stop
Speaker 3: this goddamn
Speaker 1: thing for God's sake!
Speaker 1: Please, please, just stop it!
Speaker 1: If I can stop, dear God, if I can stop, stop, stop, stop!
Speaker 1: Stop!
Speaker 3: Omega, stop!
Speaker 3: Stop!
Speaker 8: AV Unit 3.
Speaker 8: I mean, the target has gone completely silent, sir.
Speaker 10: Now what shall I cook?
Speaker 10: For Godama, Nozomi, and myself?
Speaker 10: But these all serve four.
Speaker 10: I sure hope he's hungry tomorrow.
Speaker 15: Over here, over here!
Speaker 15: There's a survivor here!
Third squad, erase...
Locate the entire Highway 20.
Do it now!
Order's breakfast.
Two survivors found in each.
Speaker 3: I'm alive?
Speaker 4: Kaji?
Speaker 13: You were lucky, Katsuragi.
Speaker 4: Where's Ritsuko?
Speaker 13: Don't worry.
Speaker 13: She wasn't hurt as bad as you.
Speaker 5: Oh, good.
Speaker 5: What about Ava 3?
Speaker 13: It was destroyed.
Speaker 13: As an angel.
Speaker 13: By Unit 1.
Speaker 5: I...
Speaker 5: I never told Shinji.
Speaker 5: Shinji.
Speaker 4: Shinji?
Speaker 4: Misato, you're okay?
Speaker 4: I'm sorry.
Speaker 16: God, I'm sorry.
Speaker 16: I had to tell you something.
Speaker 16: Something important, but oh, dear God, I'm sorry.
Speaker 4: Misato, I...
Speaker 4: I killed you.
Speaker 4: My dad forced me to.
Speaker 4: I begged him and begged him, but...
Speaker 19: Shinji,
Speaker 16: I'm sorry.
Speaker 16: Report from the entry plug recovery squad.
Speaker 16: The pilot's life signs are confirmed.
Speaker 19: He's alive!
Speaker 16: Shinji, the pilot of Unit 3 is...
Speaker 16: The fourth child is...
Speaker 16: Shinji?
Speaker 16: Shenji! Shenji!
Speaker 3: No!
I'm not sure