Speaker 1: You mean the super solenoid theory that Dr. Katsuragi proposed?
Speaker 1: That theory is outrageous and nothing more than a hypothesis at this
Speaker 2: point.
Speaker 2: But only
Speaker 1: the S2 theory can explain that giant's power.
Speaker 1: And we don't actually need to
Speaker 3: find this to
Speaker 1: put too much
Speaker 4: faith in their own ideas.
Speaker 4: When all the data has been verified, then I'll accept it.
Speaker 4: And they become fixated too easily.
Speaker 4: After all,
Speaker 3: they're incapable
Speaker 1: of accuracy
Speaker 3: -assessing reality.
Speaker 5: And those are the people seeking to find the
Speaker 4: truth of it.
Speaker 4: How is it quite?
Speaker 4: And in fact, they are not so noble.
Speaker 4: Discovery may be joy, but knowledge is power.
Speaker 4: All they're doing is trying to benefit themselves.
Speaker 2: Today's experiment is on an ego-friendly order to ignore that field, right?
Speaker 2: Right.
Speaker 6: We've got to suppress the surface radiation!
Speaker 2: It's way over
Speaker 6: the projected limit!
Speaker 2: It's no good!
Speaker 2: The DNA that was inserted
Speaker 6: into atoms has
Speaker 7: already been physically confused!
Speaker 3: All the heat fields are being released!
Speaker 1: The conversion system is already set!
Speaker 1: It's sinking in!
Speaker 1: I don't care if it just makes a small difference!
Speaker 1: Keep the damage to an absolute minimum!
Speaker 1: The atomic components are breaking up at the
Speaker 7: quad level!
Speaker 7: Initiate thermal damage treatment as soon as the dorm cough opens!
Speaker 7: I don't care if it's only for a tenth of a second!
Speaker 7: The
Speaker 8: conversion system is already being sold.
Speaker 8: God, how crazy!
Speaker 8: It's spinning its wings! It's breaking towards the sun!
The End
Speaker 9: Like a cruel天使
Speaker 9: A young man, be a fairy tale
Speaker 9: The blue wind is now on the door of my heart
Speaker 9: I'm just looking at you,
Speaker 9: You are smiling
Speaker 9: I am so happy to touch the touch
Speaker 9: I am so happy to be able to
Speaker 9: I don't know what you can't know
Speaker 9: I don't know what a smile
Speaker 9: But I will know that you will find your back
Speaker 9: The future will be the way to the future
Speaker 9: The endless endless endless endless
Speaker 9: The window from the end will be as soon as
Speaker 9: The hot air is on the hot air
Speaker 9: The memories of your dreams will be
Speaker 9: This sky will be the shining
Hi! I'm not in right now, so leave your message after the beep. Bye-bye.
Speaker 10: My last assignment. It's red. Just like blood.
Speaker 11: Commander Fuyutsuki
Speaker 12: was abducted?
Speaker 13: That's right. It happened about two hours ago. The Vice Commander was last seen in the 8th District.
Speaker 12: That's inside this installation. What in the hell were you idiots and intelligence doing?
Speaker 13: Someone inside this organization must have been involved.
Speaker 13: We appreciate your cooperation in this.
Speaker 12: Someone who could outwit Section 2? You don't think--
Speaker 13: Ryoji Kaji. He's the suspected mastermind behind this plot.
Speaker 12: So that's why you came for me.
Speaker 13: We believe you can help us.
Speaker 13: As your colleagues, we regret the necessity of including the Director of Operations as a suspect.
Speaker 13: But that is the nature of our profession.
Speaker 11: And of course, considering my relationship with him, it's a natural precaution.
Speaker 13: Yes, your cooperation would be appreciated.
Speaker 13: It's been a while.
Speaker 13: Are your invitations always so violent, Chairman
Speaker 4: Gill?
Speaker 4: There are a number of matters we need to discuss outside of Commander Kari's hearing.
Speaker 4: The nature of your procurement was necessary.
Speaker 4: You haven't changed at all. And how this affects me is inconsequential.
Speaker 6: The subject in question has already become an active issue.
Speaker 6: Thus, these measures were inevitable.
Speaker 6: Please understand our situation.
Speaker 6: Oh, now this is surprising.
Speaker 6: Not the committee, but sailor.
Speaker 5: Creating a new guard is not on our agenda.
Speaker 5: We hope that you will cooperate, Professor
Speaker 6: Fyutski.
Speaker 6: Professor Fyutski.
Speaker 5: Hey, Professor!
Speaker 5: Professor Fyutski!
Speaker 6: Oh, hello, boys.
Speaker 6: Hey, why don't you come down and join us for a beer at the Riverwalk?
Speaker 6: What, again?
Speaker 10: Ryoko and the other girls said they'll come if you come.
Speaker 14: Yeah, and didn't the dean say you shouldn't be so unsociable?
Speaker 14: All right, you guys win.
Speaker 14: It's nice to have a chance to have a drink outside for a change.
Speaker 6: Yeah.
Speaker 14: You know, you're a brilliant scientist,
Speaker 14: but you don't place enough value in your relationships with others.
Speaker 14: I'm sorry, sir.
Speaker 14: Somehow I doubt that.
Speaker 14: However, there's a young bioengineering student
Speaker 14: who's just written a very interesting paper.
Speaker 14: Her name is Ikari.
Speaker 14: Have you heard about her before?
Speaker 6: Ikari? No, sir.
Speaker 14: I've told her about your work, and she asked if she could meet you.
Speaker 14: She'll be calling you soon, and I'd like you to take her on as a research assistant.
Speaker 14: And her name is Akari?
Speaker 6: I'll do it, sir.
Speaker 6: I read your paper last night.
Speaker 6: There are a few things I have questions about, but it's really very intriguing.
Speaker 15: Thank you very much, sir.
Speaker 6: And your full name is Yui Akari, right?
Speaker 15: Yes, sir.
Speaker 6: So, what are your career plans?
Speaker 6: Would you like to go into corporate research or join a school's research facility?
Speaker 15: Well, I haven't really thought about it much.
Speaker 15: And in my case, there may be a third option to be considered.
Speaker 15: I'm thinking about getting married and having children.
Speaker 15: Of course, that's assuming I meet the right person.
Speaker 16: By incorporating the S2 unit into itself, it has achieved its ultimate form.
Speaker 16: Evangelion Unit 1.
Speaker 16: A living God which we created. What blasphemy!
Speaker 16: The creation of a supreme being is unacceptable.
Speaker 16: Man must not
Speaker 3: create gods.
Speaker 3: No one
Speaker 6: should possess such power.
Speaker 6: Can we
Speaker 2: trust Gendo Ikari?
Speaker 6: Gendo Rokabungi?
Speaker 6: I've heard the name before.
Speaker 2: No,
Speaker 6: I've never met him.
Speaker 6: But he does seem to be at the core of a lot of rumors, rather unsavory rumors at that.
Speaker 6: What?
Speaker 6: I was appointed his advisor.
Speaker 6: Well, I'll
Speaker 5: come bail him out.
Speaker 5: I've been hearing some interesting things about you, Professor.
Speaker 5: I've been wanting to meet you for some time.
Speaker 5: Well, getting drunk and starting a fight isn't the best introduction.
Speaker 5: I didn't have a chance to say anything before they jumped me.
Speaker 5: I'm not used to being like Professor, but I'm quite familiar with hatred.
Speaker 5: Well, your problems are none of my concern.
Speaker 5: And you're exactly the kind of person that I expected Professor Fyutski to be.
Speaker 6: My first impression of him was that he was a rogue bull on a short tether.
Speaker 6: Back then, there were still seasons in this country.
Speaker 6: It was autumn.
Speaker 6: Are you serious?
Speaker 15: Yes, sir.
Speaker 15: I've been dating Gendo Rokobungi a lot.
Speaker 6: When she told me that, I couldn't hide my shock.
Speaker 6: It's rather hard imagining you and him being together.
Speaker 15: He's really very nice.
Speaker 15: It's just that nobody really knows him quite the way I do.
Speaker 15: You ought to try, sir.
Speaker 6: In this case, I think that ignorance might be bliss.
Speaker 15: Are you upset that I told him to list you as his counselor?
Speaker 6: Well, I'll admit that he's interesting, but I just don't like him.
Speaker 6: It was generally believed that the real object of Gendo's overtures to Yui was her obvious talent.
Speaker 6: That and the support of the secret organization that was arranging funding for her projects.
Speaker 6: That organization was called Sele.
Speaker 6: In the year 2000, the second impact occurred.
Speaker 6: In the first year of the 21st century was...
Speaker 6: What can I say?
Speaker 6: It was a time I still find hard to talk about.
Speaker 1: It certainly is hot over here.
Speaker 1: I hear it's going to be over 30 degrees Celsius again today.
Speaker 1: That's not rare for Japan these days.
Speaker 1: It's been summer for almost a year now.
Speaker 1: It's rough on these old bones.
Speaker 1: Why don't you move to the ship up coast?
Speaker 1: You mean the next town over?
Speaker 1: Whoa, it stinks of oil.
Speaker 1: I just can't learn to like it.
Speaker 1: Still, I can't believe you set
Speaker 6: up shop in a place like this.
Speaker 6: I had a hell of a time finding you.
Speaker 6: They're short of doctors everywhere.
Speaker 6: It's a mockery.
Speaker 6: But it's better than nothing.
Speaker 6: You mean they're going to Antarctica now?
Speaker 1: That's right.
Speaker 1: The UN's finally commissioned a formal investigation.
Speaker 1: The group conducting it is strictly provisional, of course.
Speaker 1: But I think the world needs you there more than here, Professor Fuyutski.
Speaker 1: That's former
Speaker 6: professor.
Speaker 1: By the way,
Speaker 6: this column is blank.
Speaker 6: Who recommended me?
Speaker 6: This used to be a continent of ice.
Speaker 6: The entire thing is gone.
Speaker 6: Professor Fuyutski.
Speaker 6: Huh?
Speaker 6: I don't believe it.
Speaker 6: You're alive. I'd heard that you were with the
Speaker 5: Katsuragi research team when the disaster occurred.
Speaker 5: I was, but fortunately I returned to Japan one day before the incident happened.
Speaker 5: Is that so? Mr. Rokabungi,
Speaker 6: you're a
Speaker 3: very...
Speaker 3: Excuse
Speaker 6: me, but that's not my name now.
Speaker 6: A postcard, huh?
Speaker 5: Not a business card?
Speaker 5: Ikari? Gendo Ikari?
Speaker 5: My wife has been asking me to send this to you for a while now.
Speaker 5: She's still quite a fan of yours.
Speaker 5: Quite an honor, considering.
Speaker 5: So how is Yui doing?
Speaker 5: Why isn't she on this expedition?
Speaker 5: Oh, Yui wanted to come as well,
Speaker 5: but we have a child to consider now.
Speaker 5: There are a lot of ugly rumors
Speaker 5: about this organization you work for,
Speaker 5: Sele, or whatever it's called.
Speaker 5: I don't like the way it bullies the committee.
Speaker 5: I'm afraid that it's necessary.
Speaker 5: An organization can't have too many scruples
Speaker 5: in this day and age.
Speaker 6: It may be true that Second Impact
Speaker 6: changed a lot of things. But if this official investigation team had been composed solely
Speaker 6: of Sele personnel, there would have been trouble, were the rest of us just invited for political
Speaker 6: convenience.
Speaker 12: I hate the darkness. All it does is bring back the most horrible memories.
Speaker 17: Who is she? The only survivor of the research team. Her name is Misato Katsuragi.
Speaker 17: Katsuragi? You mean Dr. Katsuragi's daughter?
Speaker 17: Yes, but she hasn't said a word in two years.
Speaker 17: How terrible.
Speaker 17: She saw hell firsthand.
Speaker 17: Her physical wounds could be healed,
Speaker 17: but repairing the damage to her mind will take time.
Speaker 17: Indeed.
Speaker 6: The entire
Speaker 17: area
Speaker 6: has been affected.
Speaker 6: Altered atmospheric composition,
Speaker 6: the complete extermination of all life forms down to the micro-organic level,
Speaker 6: traces of an enormous cavern directly below the blast center,
Speaker 6: And then there's this giant of light.
Speaker 6: This whole incident has mysteries upon mysteries.
Speaker 6: Later, the United Nations will make an official declaration
Speaker 6: that second impact had been caused by a meteor strike on Antarctica.
Speaker 6: For someone who knew what I knew,
Speaker 6: those announcements were obvious fabrications.
Speaker 6: Sele and a man named Kiel were behind the cover-up.
Speaker 6: It became my goal, my obsession to find the real answers.
Speaker 6: The truth that was being suppressed.
Speaker 6: Even if my former student Yui was involved as well.
Speaker 15: It's been a long time.
Speaker 6: Yes, it has.
Speaker 6: Why did you conceal the existence of the giant?
Speaker 6: You knew Second Impact was gonna happen, didn't you?
Speaker 6: You could talk all you want to about how it was just luck
Speaker 6: that you returned one day before it occurred.
Speaker 6: But how do you explain the fact
Speaker 6: that you brought back all the expedition's records and findings?
Speaker 6: I know for a fact your personal files contain more than we recovered, Ikari.
Speaker 5: Hm. I'm surprised that these weren't destroyed.
Speaker 6: Sloppy housework.
Speaker 6: I checked into your estate as well.
Speaker 6: Bringing up a child and educating him is expensive.
Speaker 6: But isn't
Speaker 5: this a bit much for a civil servant?
Speaker 5: Very impressive, Professor Futski.
Speaker 5: Perhaps you should be teaching economics.
Speaker 5: I'm
Speaker 6: going to go public with the real truth about you,
Speaker 6: Sele, Second Impact, and the Dead Sea Scrolls.
Speaker 6: What you've been doing here is completely inexcusable.
Speaker 5: As you wish.
Speaker 5: But first, there's something I'd like to show you.
Speaker 5: How far down will we be going?
Speaker 5: Worried, Montresor? A little bit.
Speaker 5: Oh my god.
Speaker 5: Oh, we didn't make this.
Speaker 5: Although 89% of it was buried,
Speaker 5: something or someone excavated this cavity.
Speaker 5: This was originally a giant sphere?
Speaker 5: Exactly like that underground cavity at the South Pole?
Speaker 5: The data is virtually identical, yes.
Speaker 5: And do you intend to let that tragedy be repeated again?
Speaker 5: Is that it?
Speaker 5: I'll let you determine that for yourself.
Speaker 5: But either way, every resource of the human race will be poured into this Geo front.
Speaker 7: Professor Fiyutski!
Speaker 6: Dr. Akagi? You're here too?
Speaker 6: Yes.
Speaker 7: This is the ideal place for advancing our research towards creating the ultimate biocomputer system.
Speaker 7: I'm going to name them the Magi.
Speaker 6: The Magi? The Three Wise Men of the East?
Speaker 6: Is this what you wanted to show me?
Speaker 7: No, it's over this way.
Speaker 7: Ritsuko, I'll be right back.
Speaker 6: Unbelievable.
Speaker 6: Is this the Giant of Light?
Speaker 6: No.
Speaker 7: In Gehern, we refer to the second impact giant as Atom.
Speaker 7: But this isn't that one.
Speaker 6: Then, what is this?
Speaker 7: This is what man has created from Atom.
Speaker 7: Ava.
Speaker 5: Ava?
Speaker 5: Project E, the Atom Revival Project.
Speaker 5: And that is Evangelion Unit Zero, our system prototype.
Speaker 5: Prototype? Prototype of what?
Speaker 5: Fyutski, will you join us in creating a new genesis for mankind?
Speaker 8: Uh, ma'am?
Speaker 8: Oh, I'm sorry. I zoned out. Let's proceed with Rey's repeat test.
Speaker 8: I haven't seen
Speaker 11: Major Katsuragi today.
Speaker 8: Neither have
Speaker 11: I.
Speaker 11: Uh, Katsuragi?
Speaker 11: Yeah, Misato Katsuragi. Pleased to meet ya.
Speaker 8: Dear Mother, I have just become acquainted with a girl named Katsuragi.
Speaker 8: Most people tend to keep their distance from me once they find out who I am,
Speaker 8: which forces me to remember how important your name is around here.
Speaker 8: But Misato is different.
Speaker 8: She's very open and honest, even with me.
Speaker 8: I also understand that she's the only survivor from the original research team.
Speaker 8: She used to be mute,
Speaker 7: but she talks almost constantly now, like she's trying to make up for lost time.
Speaker 7: Dear Ritsuko, I'm underground so much these days that I feel like a mole.
Speaker 7: And I'm getting royally sick and tired of living on the boxed lunches they provide here.
Speaker 7: That should improve, though. Up on the surface, they've started construction on Tokyo 3.
Speaker 8: Misato hasn't shown up at college for the last few days, and I've finally forced her to tell me why.
Speaker 8: Talk about stupid! She spent the whole week having sex with her new boyfriend.
Speaker 8: a whole week.
Speaker 8: I think there's another side to her I haven't seen before,
Speaker 8: and it disturbs me.
Speaker 8: Well, she introduced me to him today,
Speaker 8: and he's handsome all right,
Speaker 8: but his sloppy grooming and attitude really
Speaker 7: bother me.
Speaker 7: You've always been a little boy shy, Ritzko dear.
Speaker 7: I think it's because you only had a mother
Speaker 7: and no men in your life,
Speaker 7: and I'm afraid that I never reeled you in
Speaker 7: as often as I should have.
Speaker 7: I'm ashamed to admit it,
Speaker 7: but I've only acted like a mother
Speaker 7: when it suited my whims,
Speaker 7: which wasn't often.
Speaker 6: Another day like every other.
Speaker 6: Why does the loss of autumn make me feel so sad?
Speaker 6: You know, if these secret Dead Sea Scrolls that Sele possesses are correct,
Speaker 6: a third impact within the next decade is inevitable.
Speaker 15: But that's why Sele and Geharan exist.
Speaker 15: To prevent that final tragedy.
Speaker 6: It's your ideas that I believe in, not Sele's.
Speaker 15: Because you know that the act of unleashing that seal could be quite dangerous.
Speaker 6: I've already given Akari the data.
Speaker 6: It's not something one individual can accomplish, after all.
Speaker 6: And there will be no repeat of my earlier stunt.
Speaker 6: I've already received a warning of sorts on that.
Speaker 6: It would appear that getting rid of me would be quite easy, it seems.
Speaker 15: But that applies to all of us.
Speaker 15: It's so easy.
Speaker 15: to destroy something.
Speaker 6: But there's no reason for you
Speaker 6: to become a test subject.
Speaker 15: I'm simply following the flow
Speaker 15: that's presented itself.
Speaker 15: That's why I'm at Zele after all.
Speaker 15: For Shinji.
Speaker 9: Why
Speaker 3: is there a child in here?
Speaker 6: That's Director Ikari's
Speaker 7: son.
Speaker 6: Ikari, this isn't a daycare center.
Speaker 6: This is an important event.
I'm sorry, Professor. I'm the one who brought Shiji here.
Speaker 6: But Yui, this is your experiment today.
Speaker 15: That's why I brought him. I want to show him how great the future
will be.
Speaker 7: Those words would prove to be Yui's last.
Speaker 7: A freak accident wiped her from this existence, just as I had hoped it would.
Speaker 7: What a disgusting woman I am.
Speaker 7: But Ritsuko, after that day, Director Akari changed completely.
Speaker 6: Where have you been all week?
Speaker 6: I understand your grief, but you must know that your life no longer belongs to you alone.
Speaker 5: I know.
Speaker 5: Fyutsuki, as of today we will begin the new project.
Speaker 5: I have already made the proposal to Chairman Keele.
Speaker 5: You mean it's approved?
Speaker 5: Yes. That which has never been achieved.
Speaker 5: The path to becoming one with God.
Speaker 5: Human
Speaker 8: instrumentality.
Speaker 8: Dear Mother, congratulations on the completion of your Magi theorems.
Speaker 8: I have good news, too.
Speaker 8: It's been decided that I will officially join Gehearn.
Speaker 8: I'll start working on Project Eden next month.
Speaker 8: Who's
Speaker 1: there?
Speaker 8: Dr. Ritsuko Akagi.
Speaker 8: Technological Development Section.
Speaker 8: Here's my ID.
Speaker 8: I came to see how the new Command Center installation was coming along,
Speaker 8: but I got lost.
Speaker 1: I see. The Commander and Dr. Akagi will see you in the command center.
Speaker 7: Are you alright?
Speaker 1: Yes. I have no
Speaker 5: regrets concerning my work.
Speaker 7: You're lying. You still can't forget about Yui, can you?
Speaker 7: But that's acceptable to me.
Speaker 5: And this is Gehern headquarters.
Speaker 7: Good morning, Director.
Speaker 7: Did you bring your child today?
Speaker 7: Oh, wait. I could have sworn you had a son.
Speaker 5: Oh, no. This isn't Shinji.
Speaker 5: I've decided to take care of an acquaintance's child.
Speaker 5: Her name is Rei Iannami.
Speaker 8: Hello Rei, I'm Ritsuko.
Speaker 8: She resembles someone.
Speaker 7: Yui.
Speaker 7: All the records containing Rei Iannami have been deleted.
Speaker 7: They're all blank. What's going on here?
Speaker 7: Magi Caspar, Magi Balthazar, Magi Malkior.
Speaker 7: The Magi are the three aspects of myself.
Speaker 7: Myself as a scientist, myself as a mother, and myself as a woman.
Speaker 7: Three aspects that combine to make one whole.
Speaker 8: The three faces of Mother.
Speaker 7: And all that's left to do is turn the power on.
Speaker 7: Mm-hmm.
Speaker 7: I'll be leaving early today.
Speaker 7: Misato just got back in town.
Speaker 7: Oh, yes. I'd heard that she'd just joined Gehearn.
Speaker 7: In Germany, if I recall.
Speaker 7: Uh-huh. She's with the third branch now.
Speaker 7: So, she's having a long-distance relationship?
Speaker 7: It didn't work out.
Speaker 7: They broke up, but they always seemed like such a perfect couple.
Speaker 7: The interaction of men and women isn't very logical.
Speaker 7: You're always so cool and analytical about these things.
Speaker 7: Aren't you afraid that you might lose your chance at happiness?
Speaker 8: First, I have to find a definition of happiness.
Speaker 8: It's been a while since I went out.
Speaker 8: Well, have a good one.
Speaker 8: See you later.
Speaker 7: Did you need me for something, Ray?
Speaker 18: I lost my way, Doctor.
Speaker 7: Is that so?
Speaker 7: Well, do you want to come with me then?
Speaker 18: No, thanks.
Speaker 7: But how will you get home all by yourself?
Speaker 18: That's not your business, old hag.
Speaker 18: Old hag?
Speaker 18: I can find my way home by myself, old hag.
Speaker 7: You shouldn't call someone an old hag, Rei.
Speaker 18: But you are an old hag, aren't you?
Speaker 7: I'm getting mad. Commander Akari will spank you for this, you love--
Speaker 7: The commander
Speaker 18: is the one who calls you that.
Speaker 18: He says that old hag is annoying. That old hag is no use anymore.
Speaker 19: Old hag
Speaker 18: is
Speaker 19: no use anymore.
Speaker 19: Old hag is no use anymore.
Speaker 18: - The old hag is no use.
Speaker 18: - The commander's someone that calls you that.
Speaker 19: - He says that old hag is annoying.
Speaker 19: That old hag is no use anymore.
Speaker 7: - You little bitch!
Speaker 7: You're replaceable too, did you know that, Ray?
Speaker 7: You're just as replaceable as me!
Speaker 6: The Instrumentality Committee dissolved the Gohern Research Organization.
Speaker 6: In order to execute the project that Gohern had conceived,
Speaker 6: a new, special organization called NERV was formed.
Speaker 6: All of Gohern's existing personnel were transferred into NERV,
Speaker 6: all except one, the one that had rendered such remarkable service to the Magi system,
Speaker 6: Dr. Akagi.
Speaker 6: Well, I guess it's time to go.
Speaker 10: *Clears
Speaker 13: Here. Thank you for your cooperation.
Speaker 7: Is it over now?
Speaker 13: Yes, it is. A solution to the problem has been found.
Speaker 15: Where is he?
Speaker 13: I wouldn't know that.
Speaker 6: Oh,
Speaker 10: hi. You're a little late, aren't you?
Speaker 12: I'm home.
*Gunshot*
Speaker 20: Katsuragi, it's me.
Speaker 20: I'm sure you're listening to this message, especially after
I caused you all so much trouble.
Sorry.
Please tell Ritsu I'm sorry too.
Speaker 20: And there's one more thing to trouble you with.
Speaker 20: I've been growing a certain flower.
Speaker 20: I'd appreciate it if you could water it for me.
Speaker 20: Shinji knows where it is.
Speaker 20: Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Speaker 20: Don't hesitate.
Speaker 20: Move ahead.
Speaker 20: If I can see you again, I will say...
Speaker 20: the words that I could not say eight years ago.
Speaker 9: Bye.
Speaker 9: This message was recorded at 2.03pm.
Speaker 2: Fool.
Speaker 2: You were always such a fool.
Oh, God damn it!
Speaker 19: All I could do was run.
Speaker 19: Run away from Misato.
Speaker 19: There was nothing I could say.
Speaker 19: I was just a child.
*music*
Thank you.
Speaker 11: The reality of having lost to Shinji has driven Asuka to the depths of despair.
Speaker 11: White Megana's frustration has led to attacks of panic and now mental exhaustion and bouts of paranoia.
Speaker 11: A psychological assault from a new angel delivers a final blow to Asuka's psyche,
Speaker 11: trapping her in a psychological pitfall constructed from her own worst nightmares.
Speaker 11: As the harshness of this new reality continues to tear their worlds apart,
Speaker 11: Shinji is unable to offer her any words of comfort.
Speaker 11: It all happens in the next episode. At least be
Speaker 3: human.
.