Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
REASON FOR EXISTING, RAISON D'ÊTRE
THE REASON WHY ONE IS ALLOWED TO BE HERE
IN THE CASE OF SHINJI IKARI
THE BOY WISHED FOR DEATH OF HIS OWN WILL
THE BOY GRANTED HIS WISH
THE FINAL ANGEL IS GONE
BUT SHINJI IKARI IS TORMENTED
WHY DID YOU KILL HIM?
EVEN THOUGH HE WAS ALSO HUMAN?
EVEN THOUGH HE WAS HUMAN, LIKE YOU?
THAT'S WHY YOU KILLED HIM
UNCERTAINTY
HAUNTING UNCERTAINTY
WHAT ARE YOU AFRAID OF?
WHY DO YOU PILOT THE EVA?
THAT'S WHY YOU PILOT THE EVA?
SO, YOU PILOT THE EVA FOR EVERYBODY,
FOR OTHERS?
THE SECOND CHARACTER
IN THE CASE OF ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
SEPARATION ANXIETY
ATTACHMENT BEHAVIOR
THE THIRD CHARACTER
IN THE CASE OF REI AYANAMI
REI AYANAMI
"IS THAT WHAT TIES ARE?"
"THAT IS WHAT TIES ARE"
"BECAUSE YOU'RE AFRAID"
"YOU ARE AFRAID"
"IT FRIGHTENS YOU, DOESN'T IT?"
AND THEN...
THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF MANKIND BEGINS
EPISODE 25
THE WORLD ENDING
ONCE AGAIN, SHINJI IKARI
THAT WAS THE BEGINNING OF THE
INSTRUMENTALITY OF PEOPLE
WHAT PEOPLE ARE LACKING
THE LOSS IN THEIR HEARTS
IN ORDER TO FILL THAT VOID IN THEIR HEARTS
THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF HEARTS
AND SOULS BEGINS
RETURNING ALL THINGS TO NOTHINGNESS
THE INSTRUMENTALITY OF PEOPLE HAD BEGUN
THAT IS WHAT GIVES RISE TO THE
HUNGER IN OUR HEARTS
THIS IS WHAT GIVES RISE TO FEAR AND INSECURITY
IN THE CASE OF MISATO KATSURAGI
"YOU WANT TO BE A GOOD GIRL?"
"WHY?"
"REALLY?"
"AM I HAPPY?"
"WHAT IS HAPPINESS?"
WHAT COULD IT BE THAT SHE WANTS?
IN THE CASE OF ASUKA LANGLEY SOHRYU
WHAT DOES SHE WANT?
THAT IS REALITY
THIS IS REALITY
AND THE JOURNEY TOWARDS INSTRUMENTALITY...
...WILL CONTINUE
PREVIEW
FINAL EPISODE
THE BEAST THAT SHOUTED LOVE
AT THE HEART OF THE WORLD