Speaker 1: The young man
Speaker 1: I just look at you just as you look at me
Speaker 1: You are so happy to see you
Speaker 1: I can't even know you
Speaker 1: I'm not sure you are
Speaker 1: But you'll notice that your back is not
Speaker 1: The world's
The End
May I have your attention? As of 12:30 p.m. today, a special state of emergency has been declared for the Kanto and Chuba regions surrounding the Tokai district.
All residents must evacuate to their designated shelters immediately. Repeat.
As of 12:30 p.m. today, a state of emergency has been declared for the Kanto and Chuba regions surrounding the Tokai district.
Speaker 2: All residents must evacuate to their shelters immediately.
Speaker 3: Damn! Why did I have to lose him at a time like this?
Speaker 3: Why now?
Speaker 3: We're sorry.
Speaker 3: Due to the state of special emergency,
Speaker 3: no lines are currently available.
Speaker 3: This is a recording.
Speaker 4: Ugh. It's no use.
Speaker 4: This is dumb.
Speaker 4: I shouldn't have come here.
Speaker 4: Ah.
Speaker 4: I guess we won't be meeting here.
Speaker 4: Maybe I should find a shelter.
Speaker 4: Huh?
Speaker 3: An identified intruder is still coming towards us.
Speaker 5: We've got it on visual. I'm putting it on the main screen.
Speaker 6: It's
Speaker 5: been 15 years.
Speaker 6: Yes. Well, now we know for sure.
Speaker 6: The angels are back.
Speaker 7: Every single missile hits a target!
*Screaming*
*Gunshot
*gunshot*
Speaker 2: It's not possible! That was a direct hit!
Speaker 2: The tank battalion's been wiped out! Guided missiles and artillery fire seem to have no effect at all!
Speaker 2: Dammit! We've hit it with everything we've
Speaker 6: got and we're not even touching it!
Speaker 3: Looks like an AT field,
Speaker 6: hmm?
Speaker 6: Yes, conventional weapons are no match for the Angels.
Speaker 6: *phone
rings*
Speaker 6: I understand,
Speaker 5: sir. We'll execute backup plan at once.
Speaker 8: Now wait a second.
Speaker 8: No! They're gonna use an end tomb mine!
Speaker 8: Get down!
*Evil Scream*
Speaker 2: We did it!
Speaker 2: Well, Ikari, it looks like you won't be getting a shot at it.
Speaker 3: Shockwave approaching.
Speaker 3: Are you all right?
Speaker 3: Yeah.
Speaker 3: But my mouth is full of dirt.
Speaker 3: You'll be all right.
Speaker 3: Come on.
Speaker 3: Ready to push?
Speaker 3: Go!
Push!
Speaker 7: Yeah!
Speaker 3: Yeah!
Speaker 3: Thanks, Shinji.
Speaker 3: You're pretty useful.
Speaker 3: Thank you, but I should thank you, Miss Katsuragi.
Speaker 3: Ah, Misato is fine.
Speaker 3: So Shinji Ikari, we meet at last.
Speaker 3: Uh, yeah.
Speaker 2: What's the status of the target?
Speaker 3: We're unable to confirm.
Speaker 9: The E-impulse knocked everything out.
Speaker 2: It must be dead! It took the full blast!
Speaker 9: External sensors restored.
Speaker 7: Energy rating at the epicenter!
Speaker 2: It can't be!
Speaker 2: External cameras online.
Speaker 2: Oh!
Speaker 2: What the?
Speaker 2: That was our last resort.
Speaker 5: No effect at all.
Speaker 5: It's a demon!
Speaker 3: Yes, don't worry. His safety is my top priority.
Speaker 3: Look, can you get a car train ready for us?
Speaker 3: An express, of course.
Speaker 3: Well, I did volunteer to pick him up,
Speaker 3: so it's only my duty to make sure he gets there.
Speaker 3: See ya.
Speaker 3: *Sigh
*
Speaker 3: This stinks
Speaker 3: and we needed a working car, right?
Speaker 3: Uh, I am a government official after all,
Speaker 3: so everything's gonna be perfectly fine, okay?
Speaker 3: Okay.
Speaker 10: I don't
Speaker 3: think anyone will buy that
Speaker 10: excuse.
Speaker 3: You're no fun.
Speaker 3: You know, you're not as cute as I thought you were.
Speaker 3: Hm,
Speaker 10: is that so?
Speaker 3: Ooh, angry? I'm sorry.
Speaker 3: You're just a boy after all.
Speaker 10: You're not as mature as I thought you'd be either.
Hey, look out!
Speaker 2: As we suspected, it's regenerating itself.
Speaker 6: Without that ability, it couldn't operate without support units.
Speaker 6: Well, quite
Speaker 2: impressive. It can upgrade its operational parameters.
Speaker 6: And it's also getting smarter.
Speaker 6: It should renew its attack any minute now.
The gates are now closing.
Please get clear.
Speaker 3: Nerve?
Speaker 3: Uh-huh.
Speaker 3: It's a secret organization controlled by the U.N.
Speaker 3: And that's where my father works?
Speaker 3: Well, yeah.
Speaker 3: You do know what he does, don't you?
Speaker 10: All my teachers told me was that it was important to the future of mankind.
Speaker 5: Command of this operation is being entrusted to you.
Speaker 5: Don't betray our trust.
Speaker 5: Yes, sir.
Speaker 5: Mr.
Speaker 2: Ikari, we've already seen that our weapons seem to have no effect on these things.
Speaker 2: That's why we're giving you a chance.
Speaker 5: Are you sure that you can beat them?
Speaker 5: That is why nerve exists.
Speaker 5: I pray you're right.
Speaker 2: The target is
Speaker 9: still stationary.
Speaker 9: Estimated current ability to intercept is only 7.5%.
Speaker 6: The wind forces are exhausted.
Speaker 6: What are you going to do?
Speaker 6: Activate Unit 1.
Speaker 6: Activate it?
Speaker 6: But we have no pilot.
Speaker 6: Not anymore.
Speaker 6: Another spare is being delivered.
Speaker 10: Misato, are we going to see my father?
Speaker 10: Of
Speaker 3: course.
Speaker 3: Of course we are.
Speaker 10: Father.
Speaker 3: Oh, yeah.
Speaker 3: Did your dad send you an ID card?
Speaker 3: Yeah.
Speaker 7: Yeah.
Speaker 10: This is it.
Speaker 3: Oh, thanks.
Speaker 3: Here, start reading
Speaker 10: this,
Speaker 3: okay?
Speaker 10: Nerve. My father's agency.
Speaker 10: Am I going to be working for him?
Speaker 10: What am I saying?
Speaker 10: He wouldn't have sent me a letter unless he needed me for something.
Speaker 3: Sounds like you don't get along with your dad.
Speaker 3: You sound just like me.
Speaker 10: Huh?
Speaker 10: Oh! Awesome!
Speaker 3: It's a real Geofront!
Speaker 3: That's right! This is our secret underground base, Nerve Central.
Speaker 3: This city is the key to rebuilding our world. A fortress for all mankind.
Speaker 3: What on earth? Isn't this the right way?
Speaker 3: It's because of these things that I hate to wear a skirt around here.
Speaker 3: I wonder where in the heck Ritsuko is.
Speaker 3: I'm sorry, I'm not used to this place.
Speaker 3: We passed this spot twice already.
Speaker 3: Well, don't worry about it. They make these transit things to be used, you know.
Speaker 3: With the chairperson of E-Project, Technical Division 1, Dr. Ritsuko Akagi,
Speaker 3: please contact Captain Misato Katsuragi of Operations Division
Speaker 9: 1 immediately.
Speaker 9: I don't believe it. Is she lost again?
Speaker 3: Hi there, Ritsuko.
Speaker 9: Hmm.
Speaker 9: Why are you wasting my time, Captain?
Speaker 9: Don't you know we're short on time and manpower?
Speaker 9: Sorry.
Speaker 3: So, is this the boy?
Speaker 3: Right. According to the Marduk report, he's the third child.
Speaker 9: Pleased
Speaker 3: to meet you.
Speaker 3: Sure.
Speaker 3: I'm afraid he's just like his father.
Speaker 3: The gruff and unfriendly part, that is.
Speaker 6: Handle the rest of this.
Speaker 10: Their first meeting in three years.
Speaker 10: Sir?
Speaker 10: Hmm?
Speaker 10: Looks like the
Speaker 1: target's starting to move
Speaker 2: again.
Speaker 2: I see. Let's go to battle stations, Level 1.
Speaker 1: Battle stations, Level 1. Prepare for ground level intercept.
Speaker 9: There we go. It sounds pretty serious.
Speaker 9: So how's Unit 1 coming?
Speaker 9: It's currently undergoing refrigeration, using the B-type equipment.
Speaker 9: Does it really work? It's never worked before, has it?
Speaker 9: The possibility of activation is 0.000000001%.
Speaker 9: Around here we just call it the 09 system.
Speaker 9: Does that mean it doesn't work?
Speaker 9: Don't be insulting. It's 09, as in Oni. A Japanese devil.
Speaker 3: Hmm.
Speaker 3: Well, anyway, I suppose it's a bit late to be saying "Sorry it doesn't work."
Speaker 10: Hey! Why is it so dark in here?
Speaker 10: What?
Speaker 10: It's a face! A giant robot!
Speaker 9: You won't find this in there.
Speaker 9: What?
Speaker 9: This is man's ultimate fighting machine.
Speaker 9: The synthetic life form known as Evangelion, Unit 1.
Speaker 9: Built here in secret, it is mankind's last hope.
Speaker 9: Is this my
Speaker 10: father's work?
Speaker 6: Correct.
Speaker 6: It's been a while.
Speaker 10: Father...
Speaker 6: We're moving out.
Speaker 10: Moving
Speaker 9: out?
Speaker 3: But Unit Zero's still in cryostasis!
Speaker 3: Wait a minute! You're gonna
Speaker 9: use Unit One?
Speaker 9: There's no other way.
Speaker 9: Now wait! Rei can't do it yet, can she?
Speaker 9: We don't have a pilot!
Speaker 9: We just received one.
Speaker 9: You're serious?
Speaker 9: Shinji Ikari?
Speaker 9: You will pilot it.
Speaker 3: But even Rei Ayanami took seven months to synchronize with her Eva.
Speaker 3: It's impossible for him to do it. He
Speaker 9: just got here.
Speaker 9: He just has to sit in the seat. We don't expect more than that.
Speaker 9: But...
Speaker 9: Listen, defeating that angel is our ultimate priority.
Speaker 9: If we have someone who has a chance at synchronizing with an Eva, then we've got to risk it.
Speaker 9: You do understand that, don't you, Captain Katsuragi?
Speaker 10: Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 10: Why did you send for me?
Speaker 10: You
Speaker 6: know why I sent for you.
Speaker 6: So,
Speaker 10: you're asking me to take this thing and go out there and fight?
Speaker 6: Correct.
Speaker 10: How could you do this to me? I thought you didn't want me. Why? Why did you have to call me now, Father?
Speaker 6: Because I have a use for you.
Speaker 10: But
Speaker 7: why? Why me?
Speaker 6: Because there is no one else who can.
Speaker 10: No, I can't!
Speaker 10: I've never even seen anything like this before!
Speaker 10: There's no way I can do this!
Speaker 6: You will be instructed.
Speaker 10: But still!
Speaker 11: There's no way!
Speaker 11: I can't pilot that thing!
Speaker 6: If you're going to do it, do it now.
Speaker 6: If not, then leave.
Speaker 6: It's close. It must sense us.
Speaker 9: Shinji, we don't have much time.
Speaker 3: Get inside.
Speaker 3: This is all wrong. I came all this way.
Speaker 10: Why did I come?
Speaker 3: Why, Shinji? Exactly why did you come here?
Speaker 3: You mustn't run away. You must confront your father, and you must confront yourself.
Speaker 10: I know that! But
Speaker 3: I just
Speaker 10: can't!
Speaker 6: Fiyutsuki!
Speaker 6: Sir!
Speaker 6: Wake up, Rei.
Speaker 6: Can we use her?
Speaker 6: She's not dead yet.
Speaker 6: Understood.
Speaker 6: Ray?
Speaker 10: Yes?
Speaker 6: Our spare is unusable. You will do it again.
Speaker 9: Yes, sir.
Speaker 9: Reconfigure Unit 1 system for Ray, then activate.
Speaker 9: Roger. Calling
on current program for beginning activation.
Speaker 10: I knew it! I'm not needed after all.
*Tonk*
Speaker 7: *Oh...*
*Cough*
Speaker 7: Look out!
Speaker 3: The hava activated itself!
Speaker 3: It ripped right out of the right armrestrape!
Speaker 3: No, that's not possible!
Speaker 3: The entry plug wasn't even inserted!
Speaker 3: That just can't happen!
Speaker 3: You mean it reacted without any kind of interface?
Speaker 3: Was it Millie to protect something? To protect him?
Speaker 3: It's him!
Speaker 10: I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away. I mustn't run away!
Speaker 10: I'll do it! I'll pilot it!
Speaker 10: Cooling process completed.
Speaker 2: Right arm repairs completed. Cage now in position for docking.
Speaker 3: Signal plug Terminator now being ejected.
Speaker 2: Roger. Inserting entry plug.
Speaker 2: Clubs locked in place.
Speaker 2: Genetic unit one.
Speaker 10: What is this stuff?
Speaker 9: Don't worry.
Speaker 9: Once your lungs are filled with LCL, your blood will be oxygenated directly.
Speaker 9: It's okay. You'll get used to--
Speaker 3: I'm gonna be sick.
Speaker 3: Stop complaining! You're a boy, you know!
Speaker 5: Connecting main power! All circuits transmitting.
Speaker 10: Roger! Connecting secondary contacts.
Speaker 10: A-10 nerve connection
Speaker 9: normal.
Speaker 9: Configure the language logic interface for Japanese.
Speaker 9: All preliminary contacts
Speaker 7: established.
Speaker 3: Performance
Speaker 7: nominal.
Speaker 9: Bi-directional circuits are open.
Speaker 3: Synchronization ratio at 41.3%.
Speaker 3: Amazing!
Speaker 3: Harmonics seem to be normal.
Speaker 3: I see no disturbances.
Speaker 3: Let's do it!
Speaker 3: Begin launch sequence!
Speaker 3: Beginning launch sequence!
Removing primary lock bolts.
Removal confirmed.
Removing the umbilical bridge.
Removing secondary lock bolts. Removing primary restraints. Removing secondary restraints.
Speaker 6: Releasing safety locks number 1 through 15. Internal batteries
Speaker 2: fully charged.
Speaker 2: External battery outlet closed.
Speaker 10: Roger. Move AVA Unit 1 to the launch pad.
Speaker 9: Launch path clear. All systems green.
Speaker 9: Evangelion ready for launch.
Speaker 9: Understood. Can we really do this?
Speaker 6: Of course. Unless we defeat the Angels, we have no future.
Speaker 6: -Hikari, are you absolutely certain?
Speaker 7: -Ava Launch!
Speaker 7: *Screams*
Speaker 10: *Sigh*
Speaker 3: Shinji, don't get killed out there.
Speaker 11: In other words, darling, kiss me
Speaker 11: Fill my heart with song
Speaker 11: And let me sing forevermore
Speaker 11: You are all I long for
Speaker 11: All I worship and adore
Speaker 11: In other words, please be true
Speaker 11: In other words, I
love you
Speaker 3: The Ava triumphs, but this angel is only the beginning.
Speaker 3: Worried about Shinji's mental state, Misato brashly decides to move him in with her.
Speaker 3: However, Shinji's mind only becomes more shut off from the rest of the world.
Speaker 3: It all happens in the next episode, and I'll be slipping you a little extra as well.