Zankoku na tenshi no you ni
Just like the cruel angel
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
2D4U PRESENTS:
Aoi kaze ga ima
Even though the untested breeze...
mune no doa o tataitemo
...taps at the door to your heart
Watashi dake o tada mitsumete hohoenderu anata
You just look solely at me and smile
Sotto fureru mono motomeru koto ni muchuu de
So intent on seeking out that gentle touch
Unmei sae mada shiranai itaike na hitomi
Such innocent eyes, still ignorant of their destiny
Dakedo itsuka kizuku deshou
But someday, you are sure to realize...
sono senaka ni wa
...that upon your back
Haruka mirai mezasu tame
You have the wings with which to fly...
no hane ga aru koto
...towards the distant future
Zankoku na tenshi no teeze
The cruel angel's thesis
Madobe kara yagate tobidatsu
Soon, you will take flight from the windowsill
Hotobashiru atsui patosu de
With your torrent of ardent pathos
Omoide o uragiru nara
If you are to betray our memories
Kono sora o daite kagayaku
You, who embrace these heavens and shine
Shounen yo shinwa ni nare
Young boy, become a legend
EPISODE SIX
DECISIVE BATTLE,
NEW TOKYO-3
1/1 Scale Balloon Dummy
Automated Model 12 Self-Propelled Mortar
Department of Operations, Nerv Headquarters
Analysis Room 2
REPLAY IMAGE
Japan Standard Time
Remaining Estimated Time
APPROXIMATED
GRAPHICS
PRESENT TIME
Cage 7, Nerv Headquarters
Emergency Room, Central Hospital,
Nerv Headquarters
Nerv Commander's Office
Eva Positron Rifle
(Prototype 20 with Toroidal Accelerator)
Requisition Order
Tsukuba Technology Laboratory Headquarters, Strategic SDF
Special Units Hangar 4
Giant Power Outage Today All Across Japan
Suzuhara Residence
Horaki Residence
New Tokyo-2
New Makurazaki, Kagoshima Prefecture
At dawn today,
a large-scale
power outage
all across the nation.
Betsukai, Hokkaido
Ube, Yamaguchi Prefecture
Mitaka Ward, Old Tokyo
New Tokyo-3
Control Room, General Operations
Command Center, Nerv Headquarters
New Odawara, Kanagawa Prefecture
Technology Department Division 3, Nerv Headquarters
(In charge of electromagnetic and light wave hardware)
Hangar 8, Nerv Headquarters
Eva Anti-Heat and Light Wave Defensive Equipment
(Makeshift Specs)
Cage 7 Control Room
Surgical Ward 3, Central Hospital
No School Today
New Tokyo-3 Public Middle School 1 Principal
8:11 PM
Near Asahi Falls on Mt. Futago
Eva Positron Sniper Rifle
(Nerv Specs - Formerly Strategic SDF Lab's Automated Positron Rifle)
...a large-scale power outage all across...
Type 14 Large Mobile Command Car
Japan Standard Time
Inside Command Car
Safe Empty
Armed
Loaded
TO BE CONTINUED
PREVIEW
THAT WHICH IS MANMADE