Speaker 1: The young man like a young man
Speaker 1: You are a young man, you are a fairy tale
Speaker 1: The wind is now on the door, but I just see you, I'm smiling.
Speaker 1: I'm so happy to see you, but I'm so happy to see you.
Speaker 1: But I'll tell you that I'll find the way behind
Speaker 1: I will be shining in the sky
Speaker 1: I will be a fairy tale
Speaker 2: Correct. I have already made the necessary arrangements with the committee.
Speaker 2: The cargo left port yesterday. It's making its way over here.
Speaker 3: Wow! A MiG-55D transport helicopter!
Speaker 3: I never thought I'd actually get a chance to fly on one of these hot mamas!
Speaker 3: Man, it's great having a famous buddy like you, right, Shinji?
Speaker 3: Huh?
Speaker 3: Yeah, I thought you must be getting sick of being cramped up in the mountains,
Speaker 3: So I thought it'd be kinda nice
Speaker 4: to invite you guys to come along with me on this little date.
Speaker 4: What? Are
Speaker 3: you saying that this is really a date we're having, Misato?
Speaker 3: And I bought this cap especially for today, just for you.
Speaker 3: I'll never take it off.
Speaker 3: So, where are we going?
Speaker 4: Oh, we're just taking a cruise on that cute little boat down there.
Speaker 3: Oh my god!
Speaker 3: One, two, three, four, five aircraft carriers and four battleships!
Speaker 3: What a fleet!
Speaker 3: That's your cute little boat?
Speaker 3: She's gorgeous! That's the pride of the UN
Speaker 4: combined fleet,
Speaker 3: the super carrier over the rainbow!
Speaker 3: It's enormous.
Speaker 4: Personally, I'm surprised it's such a crusty old relic and still float.
Speaker 3: Nah, it's not so bad. It's a vintage model from just before the second impact.
Speaker 5: Damn, give me a break. It looks like they've brought the power cables for that children's toy of theirs.
Speaker 5: Give me a break.
Speaker 3: *Dramatic
Speaker 6: music
Speaker 6: - Stop,
Speaker 3: damn you! That's
Speaker 3: my special hat! Stop it, someone! Come on,
Speaker 3: stop it!
Speaker 6: - What?
Speaker 6: - Well, hello,
Speaker 4: Misato. How have you been? - Just fine. Goodness,
Speaker 4: you've grown some, haven't you? - Uh-huh.
Speaker 7: And
Speaker 4: I'm not just taller.
Speaker 7: My figure spilled out as well.
Speaker 4: - Let me introduce you. This
Speaker 4: is the designated pilot of Eva
Speaker 4: Unit 2, the second child, Asuka Langley
Speaker 4: Soryu.
Speaker 7: *Sigh*
Speaker 5: - Hmm, nerve.
Speaker 5: From your antics on the dick, I was quite sure you were the leader of this Boy Scout troop.
Speaker 5: Obviously, I was mistaken.
Speaker 4: - Thank you for all your gracious hospitality, Admiral.
Speaker 5: - Oh no, thank you for giving me the opportunity to babysit so many more children.
Speaker 4: - And thank you for your assistance in the marine transport of AVA Unit 2.
Speaker 4: Here are the specifications for the emergency power supply.
Speaker 5: Hmph, you've wasted a trip. I'd never approve any request to activate that toy while at sea in the first place.
Speaker 4: Think of it as being prepared for an emergency. The HAVA is quite valuable, sir.
Speaker 5: So valuable that the entire Pacific Fleet has to be pulled for guard duty?
Speaker 8: Exactly when did the UN recommission us into a bloody cargo service?
Speaker 8: If my memory serves me correctly, it was just after a certain organization was established.
Speaker 8: Guarding a toy? What a ridiculously
Speaker 5: grandiose assignment for the entire Pacific Fleet!
Speaker 5: It's
Speaker 4: still not enough. Not when you consider the importance of the EVA.
Speaker 4: Sign these transfer documents, please.
Speaker 4: Not
Speaker 5: yet. EVA Unit
Speaker 4: 2 and
Speaker 5: its pilot have been entrusted to us by the Third Branch in Germany.
Speaker 5: You're just not gonna waltz in and do as you please, Captain Katsuragi.
Speaker 4: When will you transfer them to us?
Speaker 5: Once we've unloaded in New Yokosuka.
Speaker 5: The ocean is our jurisdiction. You will follow our orders here.
Speaker 4: I understand. However, I should remind you that in an emergency,
Speaker 4: Nerves military authority overrides your own.
Speaker 4: She's awesome.
Speaker 4: She sounds just like Ritsuko.
Speaker 4: Kaji!
Speaker 5: Mr. Kaji, I
Speaker 4: must insist that
Speaker 5: you stop inviting yourself onto the bridge.
Speaker 5: Oh, sorry about that.
Speaker 4: Please excuse
Speaker 6: us.
Speaker 4: Transport us
Speaker 6: to new Yoko Suka as order.
Speaker 8: Damn, those children are mankind's salvation?
Speaker 8: I suppose the times are changing, sir.
Speaker 8: I understand that Congress has pinned its hopes on that robot as well.
Speaker 8: On that child's plaything? What idiots!
Speaker 5: If they've got the money to blow on that, they ought to give us a little more.
Speaker 4: What are you doing here?
Speaker 5: Accompanying
Speaker 9: her. I'm on a business trip of sorts.
Speaker 4: Talk about careless. I should have anticipated something like this.
Speaker 4: Hey! Watch
Speaker 6: where
Speaker 7: you're touching!
Speaker 6: I can't help
Speaker 9: it!
Speaker 9: Hmm.
Speaker 9: So, do you have a boyfriend right now?
Speaker 4: I don't think that's any of your business, is it?
Speaker 9: I'm hurt.
Speaker 9: Ow.
Speaker 9: So, I understand that you're living with Katsuragi.
Speaker 4: Uh, yeah?
Speaker 9: Tell me something.
Speaker 9: Is she still so wild in bed?
Speaker 9: What?
Speaker 4: What?
Speaker 4: What are you
Speaker 10: implying by that?
Speaker 9: No, she hasn't changed at all, has she, Shinji?
Speaker 10: Um, I guess.
Speaker 10: But how did you know what my name was?
Speaker 9: Well, I ought to know you.
Speaker 9: You're pretty famous in the defense business, you know.
Speaker 9: The famous third child who piloted an Eva in his first battle with no training.
Speaker 9: Oh, that.
Speaker 4: I was just lucky.
Speaker 9: Luck is a part of your destiny. It's your talent.
Speaker 9: Well, I'll see you later.
Speaker 7: Okay.
Speaker 7: It's a bad dream. It's a nightmare.
Speaker 9: So, what do you think about Shinji Ikari?
Speaker 7: Oh, the great third child.
Speaker 7: He's boring.
Speaker 9: And yet, his synchronization ratio was well over 40% in combat with no prior training.
Speaker 9: My God!
Speaker 9: That admiral's attitude gets on my nerves.
Speaker 4: He's full of himself, all right.
Speaker 4: Too much pride's bound to make him cynical.
Speaker 4: That Mr. Kaji is pretty, um,
Speaker 9: interesting.
Speaker 7: He hasn't changed at all, that chauvinistic pig!
Speaker 7: Hey, third child.
Speaker 7: You're coming with me.
*Squeak*
Speaker 7: That's really an interesting color. I didn't know it was red.
Speaker 7: That's not all that's different about Unit 2.
Speaker 7: Uh-huh.
Speaker 7: Unit 0 and 1 were the prototype and test type respectively.
Speaker 7: The fact that Unit 1 synchronized with an untrained pilot like you is proof of that.
Speaker 7: However, Unit 2 is a little different.
Speaker 7: My Unit 2 is the world's first real Evangelion!
Speaker 7: Created for actual combat conditions, it's the final production model!
Speaker 7: What
Speaker 6: was that? An explosion?
Speaker 6: Undersea shockwave!
Speaker 7: And it sounded close! Look!
Speaker 7: What's that?
Speaker 7: It can't be... angels!
Speaker 7: Angels? You mean a real one?
Speaker 7: This is really bad. We've got to go back and find Misato.
Speaker 7: Oondava.
Speaker 8: All ships, head out and take evasive actions.
Speaker 8: Radio room, status report.
Speaker 8: The silver lanes got silent. Titus Andronicus can't locate the target.
Speaker 8: The Biloxi Blues is taking in
Speaker 4: water.
Speaker 4: Damn
Speaker 1: it
Speaker 8: all. What the hell is going on?
Speaker 4: Hello, nerve delivery.
Speaker 4: Would you like to order data on this enemy and countermeasures to use against it?
Speaker 11: This is a combat situation. Get the hell off my bridge!
Speaker 4: This is just my opinion, but I'd say that must be an angel.
Speaker 4: All ships, fire at will!
Speaker 4: It's pointless.
Speaker 9: An AT field can't be penetrated with this kind of firepower.
Speaker 4: But what is this angel doing here?
Speaker 4: Is it after Unit 2?
Speaker 4: *Mumbling*
Speaker 7: Mom, I'm schnell!
Speaker 1: Where are you taking me?
Speaker 7: Just wait here a second.
Speaker 1: I don't believe this.
Speaker 7: Get back!
Speaker 7: Don't laugh, you deviant!
Speaker 7: Why do all boys have to be such a bunch of perverted jerks?
Speaker 7: Perversa idioten!
Speaker 7: Ugh!
Speaker 10: Let's go, Asuka.
Speaker 5: Why won't it sink?
Speaker 5: Only an Ava can beat it.
Speaker 5: What?!
Speaker 5: Something...
Speaker 6: Well,
Speaker 7: put it on!
Speaker 7: Uh...
Speaker 7: Don't stand there!
Speaker 7: Get moving!
Speaker 7: Okay, but what do we need these flight suits for, Asuka?
Speaker 7: Are you dense? We're going to defeat that angel with my unit, too!
Speaker 7: No way! Does Misato know about this?
Speaker 7: I'll get her permission after the fact.
Speaker 7: There, get ready for an amazing display of piloting, third child.
Speaker 7: Just sit down and don't bug me.
Speaker 4: This is odd. The Angel seems to be looking for something.
Speaker 2: I wasn't expecting to see an Angel. This isn't how it's supposed to be.
Speaker 2: That's why Unit 2 is there. And I've generously provided a second pilot as a reserve.
Speaker 2: If worse comes to worst, you can always escape by yourself.
Speaker 9: Of course I can.
Speaker 7: Erzähl, Einlass.
Speaker 7: Anfang der Bewegung, bestätigt.
Speaker 7: Anfang des Nervenanschlusses, bestätigt.
Speaker 7: Anfang nächste der Herzmonitor, bestätigt.
Speaker 7: Syncro start, nun!
Speaker 7: It's a program error!
Speaker 7: It's thought noise! I told you not to disturb me!
Speaker 7: What do you mean?
Speaker 7: You're thinking in Japanese, aren't you?
Speaker 7: If you must think, do it in German!
Speaker 7: Uh, well, I'll try. Uh, Strudel? Brotwurst?
Speaker 6: Don't go off! Never
Speaker 7: mind!
Speaker 7: We'll start over again. Switch language to Japanese.
Speaker 7: Evangelion, Unit 2, go!
Speaker 11: Communication from the Othello! Ava Unit 2 is activating!
Speaker 11: Say
Speaker 4: what?
Speaker 4: Alright, Asuka!
Speaker 11: Abort! Stop the Ava activation sequence!
Speaker 4: Don't listen to that moron, Asuka! Go for it!
Speaker 4: What are you doing?
Speaker 11: That A-line is put around my jurisdiction!
Speaker 11: You're violating my authority!
Speaker 4: Who gives a damn about your procedures?
Speaker 4: This is an emergency!
Speaker 4: I'll
Speaker 11: have you all--
Speaker 11: Oh, dear lord.
Speaker 8: Unit 2 is still using the B-type equipment.
Speaker 8: What?
Speaker 4: If we fall into the ocean, we're done for.
Speaker 7: Then
Speaker 4: we won't do that.
Speaker 4: Shinji, are you in there too?
Speaker 4: Yes, ma'am. Hi!
Speaker 11: They're just kids!
Speaker 4: This is our chance, right--
Speaker 4: Asuka, take off!
Speaker 7: Go!
Speaker 7: Let's do it.
Speaker 7: Where is it?
Speaker 7: That way!
Speaker 7: We've got just 58 seconds left.
Speaker 7: I'm well aware of that.
Speaker 7: Misato, get the external power supply socket onto the flight deck.
Speaker 7: I'm on it!
Speaker 11: What's she doing now?
Speaker 7: Right, let's play hopscotch.
Speaker 7: Hopscotch?
Speaker 3: The power supply is in place.
Speaker 4: Reactor connection completed.
Speaker 11: All hands, prepare for impact.
Speaker 11: This is nuts!
Speaker 7: Ava Unit 2 coming in for landing!
Speaker 3: Oh, what a waste!
Speaker 3: The target
Speaker 7: is approaching rapidly!
Speaker 7: Angel! Approaching from 9 o'clock!
Speaker 7: Switching to external power!
Speaker 7: Switch completed!
Speaker 7: We don't have any guns!
Speaker 7: The progressive knife ought to do it!
Speaker 7: *BANG
Speaker 4: *
Speaker 11: Looking good, Oscar!
Speaker 11: This isn't a game! Look what you're doing on my flight deck!
Speaker 6: Look!
Speaker 7: It's sinking!
Speaker 7: Oscar, it's impossible to fight underwater using the B-type equipment!
Speaker 7: Well, you know what they always say:
Speaker 7: You don't know until you try.
Speaker 4: Oh, man.
Speaker 4: How much cable is left?
Speaker 8: 1,200 meters.
Speaker 8: What are you going to do?
Speaker 4: We'll deal with it.
Speaker 4: We've got to do something.
Speaker 4: The cable's about to run out!
Speaker 3: Get brace for the shock!
Speaker 3: Vedant!
Speaker 3: Ava has lost the target! I've got to change the disc!
Speaker 3: A Yak-38 costume!
Speaker 3: Hey, Katsuragi!
Speaker 3: Kaji!
Speaker 9: I've got to make a delivery, so I'll just be taking off.
Speaker 9: Well, let's go.
Speaker 3: Take care of the rest of this, Captain.
Speaker 3: There!
Speaker 7: He ran away.
Speaker 3: Admiral, the target is approaching Ava again.
Speaker 7: Here it comes again.
Speaker 7: Right, I'll finish it off this time.
Speaker 7: Hey, what's wrong?
Speaker 7: It's not working.
Speaker 7: It's B-type equipment.
Speaker 7: What are you gonna do?
Speaker 7: What am
Speaker 6: I?
Speaker 7: You're the famous third child, aren't you?
Speaker 7: Do something!
Speaker 7: Look!
Speaker 7: Steve!
Speaker 7: It's an
Speaker 3: angel.
Ava too has entered the target's body!
Speaker 3: Does that mean that Ava's been eaten?
Speaker 3: This is like Marlon fishing.
Speaker 4: Fishing?
Speaker 7: That's it! Fishing!
Speaker 7: Oh man, it just goes from bad to worse!
Speaker 7: Oh shut up you pessimist!
Speaker 7: And
Speaker 6: get off my lap, you
Speaker 7: pervert!
Speaker 7: But we've got to free ourselves!
Speaker 4: Asuka, do you read me?
Speaker 4: Don't let that
Speaker 7: angel get away!
Speaker 7: Huh?
Speaker 4: Well, Admiral?
Speaker 4: What
Speaker 5: now?
Speaker 5: I'm
Speaker 4: going to need your cooperation.
Speaker 5: A point-blank assault by the two surviving battleships?
Speaker 4: Correct.
Speaker 4: We'll sink these two evacuated battleships
Speaker 4: in line with the umbilical cable as a trap.
Speaker 4: When the Ava opens the angel's mouth,
Speaker 4: both ships will rush into the opening.
Speaker 4: Once inside the angel,
Speaker 4: the ship's computers will be activated via remote control.
Speaker 4: They will then fire all of their bow turret cannons and self-destruct,
Speaker 4: destroying the target.
Speaker 4: Preposterous!
Speaker 4: Preposterous, perhaps, but not completely impossible.
Speaker 5: I understand.
Speaker 3: All hands abandon ship! I repeat, all hands abandon ship!
Speaker 5: What about the Evangelion?
Speaker 4: Don't worry about them. They'll be perfectly fine.
Speaker 7: - Hey, don't out-break my aim without my
Speaker 4: permission! Shinji,
Speaker 4: Asuka, do you understand the operation? I'll do
Speaker 4: the best job I can!
Speaker 1: All ships,
Speaker 4: open the Kingston valve. Scuttle
Speaker 4: at point Z. Reverse the
Speaker 4: cable!
- Ava
Speaker 3: is started
Speaker 3: to service! T-Money
Speaker 3: 7 need to contact!
Speaker 7: Hey, are you rubbing against me on purpose?
Speaker 7: Cut it out, dork!
Speaker 7: Will you quit complaining?
Speaker 7: We've got to open its mouth or we'll be fish food.
Speaker 7: T
Speaker 3: -minus 60 to contact.
Speaker 1: How's its mouth?
Speaker 1: It's still not
Speaker 3: open.
Speaker 1: Both battleships are sinking towards the target.
Speaker 1: Ava continues to serve us.
Speaker 1: T-minus 50 to contact.
Speaker 7: It's stuck.
Speaker 7: There's no time left.
Speaker 7: - Ah!
Speaker 7: -
Speaker 4: - Target has passed beneath the tempest.
Speaker 4: - There's
Speaker 7: no time left.
Speaker 7: - Do it!
Speaker 7: - Now don't get any strange ideas.
Speaker 7: - Like what?
Speaker 7: - Let's just concentrate on getting out of here.
Speaker 4: - Works for
Speaker 1: me!
Speaker 3: - T minus 20 to contact.
Speaker 6: - Ah!
Speaker 3: - Ah!
Speaker 3: - T minus 15 to
Speaker 1: contact.
Speaker 1: Open, open, open, open, open, open!
Fire!
*Evil Scream
Speaker 4: Cut it out.
Speaker 3: At least we collected a lot of valuable data.
Speaker 3: I see.
Speaker 6: Hmm.
Speaker 3: Misato.
Speaker 3: Huh?
Speaker 3: This data really is important.
Speaker 3: Oh.
Speaker 3: Whoa!
Speaker 4: Nice figure!
Speaker 4: They broke their synchronization ratio records.
Speaker 4: Just for seven seconds. It must have been due to the danger.
Speaker 7: Wait! Wait!
Speaker 4: Hey! Where's Kaji?
Speaker 4: Gee, he took a powder. He's probably back at the headquarters by now, that
Speaker 9: jerk!
Speaker 9: My goodness, that was a rather eventful trip, wasn't it?
Speaker 9: Was it caused by this? I wonder.
Speaker 9: Well, it's already restored itself this far. It's frozen, but it's still alive.
Speaker 9: Quite amazing.
Speaker 9: This is the Keystone of Human Instrumentality Project, isn't it?
Speaker 2: Correct. This is the first human being.
Speaker 2: This is Adam.
Speaker 2: She may have looked
Speaker 9: cute, but she was a real female dog, if you know what I mean.
Speaker 3: Well, at least we won't have to see her again.
Speaker 9: Yeah, but Mr. Big Shot here still gotta go work with her every day. I feel sorry for him.
Speaker 6: Huh?
Speaker 6: Look!
Speaker 7: I'm Asuka Langley Soryu. Charmed, huh?
Speaker 10: In other words, darling kiss me
Speaker 10: Fill my heart with song and let me sing forever more
Speaker 10: You are all I long for all I worship and adore
Speaker 10: In other words, please be true.
Speaker 10: In other words,
Speaker 4: I love you.
Speaker 4: When a disastrous battle proves that Asuka and Shinji need to work on their ability to function as a team,
Speaker 4: Misato comes up with a plan to make their dysfunctions functional.
Speaker 4: Drama ensues in the next exciting episode.
Speaker 4: And of course, there'll be lots of
Speaker 6: fan service.
Speaker 6: Don't miss it.