Speaker 1: Like a poor man,
Speaker 1: You're a young man,
Speaker 1: You're a fairy tale.
Speaker 1: The blue wind is now
Speaker 1: Even if you're a door, you're smiling
Speaker 1: I'm so happy that you're looking for a moment
Speaker 1: I'm still wondering if you're not sure
Speaker 1: 痛いけな瞳
Speaker 1: だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
Speaker 1: 遥か未来目指すための羽があること
Speaker 1: 残酷な天使のテゼ 窓辺からやがて飛び立つ
Speaker 1: Hottobashiru atui pattosude
Speaker 1: Omoyde wo uragiru nara
Speaker 1: Kono sora wo daite kagayaku
Speaker 1: Shounenmu yoshi uwa ni nare
Speaker 2: Hey, have you seen her yet?
Speaker 3: Oh yeah! Yeah!
Speaker 2: Seen what?
Speaker 2: You dork! You
Speaker 3: haven't seen the overseas student yet?
Speaker 2: The overseas student? A foreigner?
Speaker 2: Yeah!
Speaker 3: She's in the 8th grade, Class A! She just transferred here!
Speaker 2: Oh,
Speaker 4: she's hot!
Speaker 4: Her name's Asuka Langley Soryu. Did you know that?
Speaker 4: Yeah, she's just cute.
Speaker 5: Since she was raised over there but born here, do you think she'll already have a boyfriend?
Speaker 4: No, no, no.
Speaker 6: I
Speaker 4: bet
Speaker 5: she broke up in Germany
Speaker 4: and she's here in a foreign land with a heart that can't be mended.
Speaker 4: All right.
Speaker 6: My gosh. Did you hear all that gossip? Asuka, Asuka, Asuka.
Speaker 2: They're totally clueless.
Speaker 6: Thanks. Come again.
Speaker 2: At least your pictures don't reveal her personality.
Speaker 5: Hello.
Speaker 5: Guten Morgen.
Speaker 5: - Good Shinji!
Speaker 5: - G-Guten
Speaker 7: Morgan.
Speaker 7: - Hey,
Speaker 8: why so
Speaker 5: gloomy?
Speaker 5: I'm the most popular girl in school.
Speaker 5: You should appreciate your good fortune.
Speaker 5: - Gah!
Speaker 5: - Hey, the other one's here too, isn't she?
Speaker 5: - Other one?
Speaker 5: - What are you stupid?
Speaker 5: I'm talking about the first child, of course.
Speaker 1: - Oh, Ayanami.
- Hm?
Speaker 5: Hello!
Speaker 5: You must be Rei Ayanami, the pilot of the prototype.
Speaker 5: I'm Asuka!
Speaker 5: Asuka Langley Soryu!
Speaker 5: I'm the designated pilot of Ava 2.
Speaker 5: Let's be good friends!
Speaker 5: What for?
Speaker 5: Because it would be convenient!
Speaker 5: You know what I mean!
Speaker 5: If I'm ordered to, I will do it.
Speaker 5: Freakazoid.
Speaker 2: It takes one to know one.
Speaker 2: I wonder if only weirdos are chosen to be Eva pilots.
Speaker 4: Oh!
Speaker 4: You've lost some weight.
Speaker 4: You're enduring an unrequited love.
Speaker 9: Really? You're so very sure, are you?
Speaker 4: A woman with a mole like a tear on her cheek is destined to a life full of heartache and sorrow.
Speaker 9: If you're trying to put the moves on me, I'm afraid you can't.
Speaker 9: Not while that face is pressed against the
Speaker 4: glass anyway.
Speaker 10: It's been quite a while, Kashi.
Speaker 4: It's been a while, all right.
Speaker 10: You know, you're not as discreet as I remember you.
Speaker 10: He ain't never been discreet in his life.
Speaker 10: You finished handing over Unit 2, haven't you?
Speaker 10: What are you still doing here?
Speaker 4: I received orders this morning that I'll be staying around so, Gorgeous, we can hang around again.
Speaker 10: Just like we used to.
Speaker 10: Don't flatter yourself.
Speaker 10: Enemy attack?
Speaker 11: We've just received this report from the battlecruiser Haruna.
Speaker 11: Have detected huge submerged object off the Kyi Peninsula.
Speaker 1: Sending data.
Speaker 11: Got it. The data has been analyzed.
Speaker 11: The wavelength pattern confirms it. It's an angel.
Speaker 11: All personnel, go to first stage alert.
Speaker 11: 50
Speaker 10: %
Speaker 10: The recent battle has severely damaged Tokyo 3's intercept system.
Speaker 10: Only 26% of our defense capability has been restored.
Speaker 10: In addition, our operational capability for actual combat is virtually nil.
Speaker 10: Therefore, we're going to have to intercept the target at the water's edge right before it makes land.
Speaker 10: Units 1 and 2 will mount a coordinated attack in a series of waves.
Speaker 10: In other words, close in and take turns.
Speaker 10: Roger!
Speaker 10: This
Speaker 5: sucks! My first fight over Japan and she won't let me handle it solo! Why do I have to bring you?
Speaker 1: SOP! That's just procedures, you know!
Speaker 1: Well, let
Speaker 5: me tell you something first, third child! Just don't get in my way!
Speaker 5: Hmm, his selection as a pilot must have been a joke, right?
Speaker 5: *BANG*
Speaker 7: Beginning attack!
Speaker 5: I'll handle this angel!
Speaker 5: Cover my back, Shinji!
Speaker 5: C-Cover you?
Speaker 5: Yeah!
Speaker 5: Ladies first!
Speaker 5: Dammit!
Speaker 5: Don't you talk to me like that, you dumb rookie!
Speaker 7: In charge!
Speaker 7: What?
*Squeak
Speaker 12: *BANG
Speaker 8: *
Speaker 8: This is all your fault! You totally screwed up my debut battle!
Speaker 5: What are you talking about? You're the one who charged in there acting like an idiot.
Speaker 5: Idiot?
Speaker 8: How dare you call me that, you pathetic excuse for a combat pilot! You're just a jerk!
Speaker 8: Me?
Speaker 3: You were in such a rush to show off, you disregarded procedure.
Speaker 5: What was that? You look like a drowned rat!
Speaker 5: You can't say that
Speaker 12: kind of thing to me!
Speaker 12: Nerve abandoning operation and transferred command to UN Secondary Force.
Speaker 11: We've been completely humiliated.
Speaker 12: At 11:05 AM, the UN forces made an attack with an in-tomb mine.
Speaker 11: We'll have to redraw the map again.
Speaker 11: They
Speaker 12: succeeded in burning off 28% of the target's structural substance.
Speaker 5: Well, it kinda looks dead.
Speaker 11: This is merely temporary. The second attack is just a matter of time.
Speaker 11: Well, at least
Speaker 4: we've got time to regroup, and you can't ask for more than that.
Speaker 4: Alright,
Speaker 11: you two. Just what do you think your job is?
Speaker 5: Piloting Ava?
Speaker 5: Wrong!
Speaker 11: It's to beat the Angels!
Speaker 11: Nerve does not exist to make grotesque public spectacles like this.
Speaker 11: Therefore, the two of you will learn to work together.
Speaker 5: Why should we?
Speaker 11: Enough.
Speaker 5: Why does everyone get so angry here?
Speaker 4: Adults have a thing about credibility.
Speaker 5: Um, where's
Speaker 9: Misato?
Speaker 4: Clearing things up.
Speaker 4: It's the duty of the person in charge to take responsibility for anything that goes wrong.
Speaker 9: Oh, look what we have here.
Speaker 9: Here are the protests and damage reports from all of the bureaus concerned.
Speaker 9: This is a bill from the UN, and you've got a complaint from public relations as well.
Speaker 9: I hope you have fun reading them all.
Speaker 10: I already know what they say.
Speaker 10: If you're going to fight, please don't do it here, right?
Speaker 10: I'd say that was a good guess.
Speaker 10: I'll do it after we kill this angel. I will destroy it.
Speaker 10: That would be a nice start.
Speaker 10: I think you should know that Commander Foyutsuki isn't exactly happy with this whole situation.
Speaker 10: I'm afraid you could be busted back to lieutenant or even lower.
Speaker 10: I guess it was just good luck within bad luck that Commander Ikari wasn't here.
Speaker 10: If he'd been here, you'd have already been fired.
Speaker 10: So you've brought me some ideas to help save my job, haven't you, dear friend?
Speaker 10: Like this one?
Speaker 10: Ah, I thank you, Dr. Ritsugu Akagi.
Speaker 10: It's good to have a friend you can count on.
Speaker 10: That's nice.
Speaker 10: But I'm not the one who'll be saving your backside this time.
Speaker 10: This is Mr. Kaji's idea.
Speaker 10: Kaji?
Speaker 10: Hmm.
Speaker 1: I'm home!
Speaker 1: Not that anyone's here, of course, but...
Speaker 1: WHAT?!
Speaker 1: What is this?!
Speaker 5: Don't be so
Speaker 1: rude!
Speaker 1: These are my personal belongings!
Speaker 1: You?!
Speaker 1: Wh-but-but
Speaker 5: what in the
Speaker 7: blazes are you doing in my house?!
Speaker 7: Why
Speaker 5: are you still here?
Speaker 7: Still here?!
Speaker 5: Don't Hmm,
Speaker 5: yeah, you've been dumped for the new model.
Speaker 7: Huh?!
Speaker 7: Misato
Speaker 7: will be living with
Speaker 5: me. Of course,
Speaker 5: that's a much more logical choice when you consider my superior abilities.
Speaker 5: Although honestly, I'd rather live with Kaji.
Speaker 5: Say, just why our Japanese houses so small anyway?
Speaker 5: I couldn't even get half my stuff in my new room!
Speaker 1: And Japanese sure
Speaker 5: don't have any sense of privacy.
Speaker 5: How can they live in a
Speaker 10: room without locks?
Speaker 10: Unbelievable!
Speaker 5: It's weird.
Speaker 5: The Japanese way is to consider
Speaker 10: the needs of others before one's own.
Speaker 5: Misawa!
Speaker 10: How's it going?
Speaker 10: You two are going to get along real well.
Speaker 7: - What? - Just what do you mean?
Speaker 10: - This is part of your new training.
Speaker 10: - Say what?
Speaker 10: - There is only one way to destroy the seventh angel.
Speaker 10: Execute a simultaneous two point attack
Speaker 10: on each target's core while the angel is separated.
Speaker 10: In other words, an attack on both halves by two Avas
Speaker 10: with perfectly synchronized timing.
Speaker 10: Coordination between the two of you
Speaker 10: will be vital to the success of the mission.
Speaker 10: To that end, I want the two of you
Speaker 10: to live together from now on.
Speaker 10: No way! A boy and a girl should never sleep under one roof after the age of seven!
Speaker 10: The angel is currently regenerating itself. It will begin its second assault in six
Speaker 8: days.
Speaker 8: But it's impossible.
Speaker 10: We have a way of making it possible.
Speaker 10: The master attack pattern will be choreographed using this music.
Speaker 10: If you follow
Speaker 7: it
Speaker 10: exactly, you will be able to work in sync and completely destroy both targets.
Speaker 10: We begin now.
Speaker 7: We attack in six days.
Speaker 10: Hmph!
Speaker 12: - Coming.
Speaker 6: - You betrayed us.
Speaker 6: You're dressing alike again too.
Speaker 6: - I can't believe this.
Speaker 7: - Neither can we.
Speaker 6: It's all Misada's fault.
Speaker 6: We have to eat, breathe, and sleep together.
Speaker 7: - You're living in sin,
Speaker 8: that's
Speaker 7: awful.
Speaker 7: - No, it's not like that.
Speaker 7: - Just
Speaker 8: what is it like?
Speaker 8: - Hi everybody.
Speaker 2: - Huh?
Speaker 2: - Um, would you like to explain all of this to us?
Speaker 2: - Geez, Shinji, you should've told us
Speaker 2: about that part first.
Speaker 2: - So how
Speaker 10: are their coordination drills
Speaker 10: coming along, Miss Misato?
Speaker 10: - Not very well, as you can see.
Speaker 10: - Scheisse!
Speaker 10: - You will so
Speaker 5: much for synchronization,
Speaker 5: I can never sink down the pathetic level
Speaker 5: this animated turnip
Speaker 8: lives at.
Speaker 8: If you ask me,
Speaker 5: the whole idea
Speaker 8: is impossible.
Speaker 5: - Then you're giving up.
Speaker 5: But you don't have anyone else, do you?
Speaker 5: - Rei? - Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 5: Why
Speaker 10: don't you try?
Speaker 10: Yes, ma'am.
Speaker 10: Well, it looks like I should alter the operation
Speaker 10: to pair Shinji and Rei.
Speaker 10: What?
Speaker 13: No.
Speaker 13: No!
Speaker 13: No, I can't stand this!
Speaker 13: I can't take it anymore!
Speaker 13: Wait, Asuka!
Speaker 2: So even the devil can cry.
Speaker 13: Uuuh! Shinji-kou!
Speaker 13: Go apologize!
Speaker 13: Huh?
Speaker 13: You made her cry, you jerk! Go find her and tell her you're sorry!
Speaker 5: Um...
Speaker 5: Don't say anything.
Speaker 5: I know. I have to pilot the Eva. I've got no choice.
Speaker 5: I'll do it.
Speaker 5: No matter what, I'll put Ray and Misato to shame!
Speaker 5: But still, you don't have to squash them.
Speaker 5: You're being too simplistic, even if you are a male.
Speaker 5: I must avenge myself. My pride.
Speaker 5: It's a matter of honor now. Can't you understand that?
Speaker 5: Where's Misato?
Speaker 5: At work.
Speaker 3: She called earlier.
Speaker 3: She'll be there all night.
Speaker 5: So, that means we're all alone tonight, huh?
Speaker 5: This is the impenetrable wall of Jericho, third child.
Speaker 5: What?
Speaker 5: Take one step over this wall and you'll be a dead man.
Speaker 5: And now it's time to go to bed, children.
Speaker 5: Ugh!
Speaker 8: Why do Japanese sleep on the floor? This is so stupid!
*Gunshot*
Speaker 7: Oh, my God.
Speaker 7: Oh, no.
Speaker 10: You're just a child yourself.
Speaker 10: No, somebody might see us.
Speaker 4: Who's watching?
Speaker 10: Somebody--
Speaker 10: Forget it, Kashi.
Speaker 10: There's nothing between us anymore.
Speaker 10: Don't ever do that again.
Speaker 4: But your lips didn't say no.
Speaker 4: Tell me, which one should I trust?
Speaker 4: Your lips or your words?
Speaker 9: Oh, thanks.
Speaker 9: Well, looks like you've got troubles.
Speaker 10: Hmm?
Speaker 10: Yeah, a few.
Speaker 10: So,
Speaker 9: is it work, or a man, or both?
Speaker 10: A lot of things.
Speaker 9: Hmm.
Speaker 10: Still in love, huh?
Speaker 10: Don't be ridiculous!
Speaker 10: Get real.
Speaker 10: Who'd want that idiot?
Speaker 10: I may have been just a kid,
Speaker 10: but getting involved with him was still the stupidest
Speaker 10: and most idiotic thing I've ever done in my entire life.
Speaker 10: I meant that he may still like you.
Speaker 10: Did I scare you?
Speaker 10: I'll
Speaker 9: show you scary.
Speaker 9: You're only proving my hypothesis.
Speaker 9: Why don't you just go with your feelings, Misato?
Speaker 9: It's not like it's still eight years ago, you know.
Speaker 9: Nothing's changed.
Speaker 10: Not a bit.
Speaker 10: He's still immature.
Speaker 10: I've got to get to work.
Speaker 10: Tomorrow's D-Day, you know.
Speaker 6: The target has broken through the final defense line at Gora.
Speaker 10: Here it comes. We won't fail this time.
Speaker 10: Spread your AT fields as soon as the music starts.
Speaker 10: Then
Speaker 5: follow the operation choreography. Are you two ready? Roger!
Speaker 2: The target has entered the mountains.
Speaker 5: Just remember the moves, Shinji. Full power, maximum performance.
Speaker 5: I know that. We'll be finished in 62 seconds.
Speaker 2: It's coming. Target entering ground zero.
Speaker 10: Detach external power.
Speaker 10: Ava, launch.
Speaker 12: *Squeak*
Speaker 12: Huh?
Speaker 12: Both Avas are okay.
Speaker 12: Ah, jeez!
Speaker 12: Pathetic.
Speaker 7: *Scream*
Speaker 5: What are you doing on my Unit 2?!
Speaker 5: What are you talking about? You're the one who fell on me!
Speaker 5: You're the one who lost time first!
Speaker 5: Doom Cop! You're always so slow!
Speaker 5: What were you doing staying up so late last night?
Speaker 3: Image training for
Speaker 10: today's battle!
Speaker 10: Oh,
Speaker 5: image training? I just bet!
Speaker 5: Liar! I know you
Speaker 7: tried to kiss me while I
Speaker 5: was sleeping!
Speaker 5: You cheat! You were awake!
Speaker 5: Oh my gosh! I was just kidding! Did you really kiss me?
Speaker 5: Oh!
Speaker 3: No! No! No! I didn't! I stopped!
Speaker 5: Haventimate!
Speaker 5: I
Speaker 3: can't
Speaker 5: believe it!
Speaker 5: Is you calling for your mother in
your sleep and sleepwalking that caused her?
What kind of person?
Speaker 11: Those darn kids are embarrassing us again.
Speaker 11: Yeah.
Speaker 7: Now, darling kiss
me
Feel my heart's weak soul
And let it sit forevermore
You are all I know
For all I want is at the door
And now I want
Let me do
In the world
I love you
Speaker 14: When an unhatched angel is discovered in the caldera of the Osama volcano,
Speaker 14: especially equipped Ava must descend into the fires of hell itself to do battle.
Speaker 14: Don't miss the next exciting episode, Magma Diver.
Speaker 14: And don't worry, there'll be lots of fan service too.