.
So, this is Dr. Katsuragi's super solenoid theory.
This whole thing just seems so untenable.
That's why it's a theory and not a principle.
Not to mention that it's
already been proven,
even
if it was by accident.
We have proof of its existence.
Well, the S2 theory is the only feasible explanation of the source of that monster's power.
Yeah, well, I'll believe it when the data is actually verified.
What's the status of the lines of longevity?
Man, I wish the smoking corner wasn't so far away.
Be happy they gave us a corner.
Originally they said the whole facility was going to be non-smoking.
No way they
could kiss my bucket.
Bye, I can't function without nicotine.
God,
it's freezing.
The food sucks.
This place truly is the armpit of the world.
Aw, jeez, not the A lunch menu again.
I
would kill for some good Osaka sushi right now.
Cut that surface light!
It's exceeding the projected growth limitations!
Atoms genetic structures
are undergoing fusion!
The AT field is spread to maximum
capacity!
God,
put the lance back!
It's no good!
The magnetic field is too weak!
It's sinking!
Do whatever you can to minimize the damage!
Commence the subatomic structure analysis.
Hurry up!
When the guff opens, commence heat dissipation!
A tenth of a second is long enough!
It's walking!
Incredible!
The anti-AT field is causing too much interference.
The energy is escaping!
Surface team has given us a visual confirmation on walking.
Transformation measures have been initiated.
Commence countdown!
The wings are going to spread!
Evacuate to the surface!
*crying*
Ritsuko must be thinking I'm pretty disgusting.
Appearing to give in to our sexual desires makes for a more realistic appearance.
A good deception.
To deceive the intelligence department?
Or the commander in Ritsuko.
Or me.
No, no. Others.
You wanna fool the others?
You never show interest in others, but you want their attention.
You really are just like my dad.
Hmph.
So, tomorrow I'll be in Japan.
Misato said she'll come to pick me up at noon.
I guess I won't be seeing you for a while.
How dull.
Once you get to Japan, I'm sure you'll have lots of new boyfriends.
In fact, I heard the third child is a boy.
I don't care about any stupid little kids.
My heart belongs to you, Kaji.
Mama! Mama! They chose me!
I'm an elite pilot now. I'm the best in the whole world.
I must keep this a secret, but I'll only tell you, Mama.
Everybody's so nice to me now. I don't feel lonely anymore.
I'm okay now, even without my papa around.
Look at me! Look at me, Mama! Look, Mama!
Asuka, your sink ratio has dropped an entire eight points. I need you to concentrate.
I'm trying to!
Asuka's sink ratio is getting lower and lower. What do you think it means, ma'am?
It means trouble. We don't have a spare. Let's concentrate our efforts on fixing Unit Zero.
Good morning, Commander. Did you bring you a child today?
Oh, wait. I could have sworn you had a little boy.
Oh, no. This isn't my son Shinji. I've decided to take care of the child of an acquaintance. Her name is Rei Ayanami.
Well, hello there, Rei.
It's no use. This is dumb. I shouldn't have come here.
Maybe I should find a shelter or something.
Ah!
I'm sorry.
*crying*
and whether I live or die makes no great difference.
The one truth the Lilin have never been able to grasp
is that death may be the only absolute freedom there ever was.
What are you?
Garu, I don't understand what you're talking about.
Nothing makes any sense.
This is my wish.
I want you to destroy me.
Otherwise, you will be destroyed.
Only one life form can be chosen to evade the destruction and seize the future.
future.
*Sounds of the
The signal's not working!
His field's not up! It's not unfolding!
It's not up?!
Status report!
The head is damaged!
Extend of damage unknown!
We're
having trouble maintaining activation!
We're not getting any readings on the pilot!
It's completely out of control!
My god... Berserker...
*Sigh*
It's neutralizing the face space.
No, it's breaking through it!
Eva's true form.
They should have delivered all your stuff by now, Shinji.
Don't mind the mess. I just moved in here myself, you know.
Hey, come in.
Oh, I don't want to intrude.
Shinji, this is your home now.
I'm... I'm home.
Welcome home.
Who is she?
The only survivor of the research team.
She hasn't said a word in two years.
How terrible.
She saw hell firsthand.
Physical wounds could be healed,
but repairing the damage to her mind could take time.
Her name is
Katsuragi.
Misato,
you said?
Yep. Misato Katsuragi, pleased to meet you.
Dear Mother,
I have just become acquainted with a girl named Katsuragi.
I understand she is the sole survivor from the original research team.
She used to be mute, but she talks almost constantly now,
like she's trying to make up for lost time.
Do I want to be good?
I have to be a good girl.
Because I have no daddy.
Because I have to be good and not bother my
mommy.
But I don't want to become like my mom.
When my father is not here, she always
cries.
I can't cry.
I can't depend on anyone else.
So I have to be good.
Maybe my father won't hate me if I be good.
But I hate my father, and I hated being a good girl.
I hate it. I'm tired of it.
Misato used to go out with Kaji?
I don't really like her. Her lifestyle is a little bit much.
Misato Katsuraki.
She's not a bad person.
So much has happened since I came.
Before this, I lived with my teacher.
It was calm and boring in those days.
I wasn't really doing anything.
But I was fine with that.
There was really nothing that I had to do.
Did you hate dealing with people?
More or less.
But
I didn't
really care as much.
However, I really hated my father.
You know, I can't help but wonder why Shinji agreed to pilot again.
It seems that he simply does what he's told to do.
I suppose that's just his way of getting through life.
Position target in the center.
Pull the switch.
I mustn't run away.
I mustn't run away! I mustn't run away!
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAA!
Today the fourth Angel attacked out of the blue.
Unit One intercepted the Angel and destroyed it.
Shinji, wake up!
How long are you going to avoid school?
It's been five days now.
Unit 1 is already completely repaired.
You're the pilot. Are you going to just leave it sitting there?
Shinji!
It's been raining for the past four days in a row.
Work on the sample analysis has been postponed due to the weather.
Other than that, nothing else to write about.
Well, the sun finally came out for a while today.
But overall, it was partly cloudy.
Nothing else to write about today.
I like it out here at night.
Because those noisy cicadas don't chirp.
It was pretty quiet when I was a kid.
But there's tons of them now.
Misato said that the ecosystem was returning to its former state.
Misato said so, huh?
I really envy you.
I mean, you live with such a beautiful woman.
And you get to pilot the Evangelion.
The Eva is on standby.
Will you pilot
it?
Or won't you?
You're not going to scold me for running away?
Of course you're not. I'm no relation to you, am I?
If I say that I won't pilot Unit 1, what are you going to do with it?
I suppose that Ray will do it. So you won't pilot it?
It seems a little bit unrealistic for you to force everything on her.
Don't worry. I'll pilot it.
But you don't want to do it.
Of course not. It's not something that comes to me naturally.
But Ayanami and you and Ms. Ritsuko...
Stole that line of crap! This has nothing to do with any of us!
If you don't like it, get out of here!
Just forget all about Eva and us and go back where you came from!
We don't need someone with that attitude piloting.
Of course, if you're leaving, we'll have to leave this city sometime soon.
But we can't really blame you for that. I mean, we saw how you suffered in the Ava.
And anyway, if anyone does try to blame you, I'm gonna give them a bop on the head.
I'm the one who deserved to be hit, not you!
I'm a coward!
I'm dishonest!
I'm sneaky!
And a wimp!
Shinji, you mustn't run away.
You must confront your father.
And you must confront yourself.
Shinji,
are you sure about this?
I don't mind living alone. And besides, I'm alone anyway.
It's awesome! The buildings are growing!
Of course, if you're leaving, we'll have to leave this city sometime soon.
But we can't really blame you for that. I mean, we saw how you suffered in the Eva.
And anyway, if anyone does try to blame you, I'm gonna give them a bop on the head!
This is our
city,
and it's the city you saved.
I forgot to tell you something.
You did something very good and very noble today.
You should be proud.
Good night, Shinji.
Hang in there.
*Gasp*
We believe that mental and physical exhaustion were causing a strain on the third child's health.
He was given four days leave.
His status has returned to normal.
No further problems.
I... I'm home.
Welcome
home.
Good morning, Ikari.
Good morning.
What are we working on today?
Pachelbel's Cannon.
Cello's so easy.
All you have to do is play arpeggios.
*cough*
*Sigh*
Mama... Mama...
So,
you're just a kid yourself.
Well, hello, Miss Sato. How have you
been?
Just fine. Goodness, you've grown some, haven't you?
Uh-huh. And I'm not just taller. My figure's filled out as well.
Let me introduce you. Shinji,
this is the designated pilot of EVA Unit 2, the second child.
Asuka Langley Soryu.
You are extremely afraid of any kind of initial contact, aren't you?
Are you that afraid of other people?
I know that by keeping others at a distance, you avoid a betrayal of your trust.
But while you may not be hurt that way, you mustn't forget that you must endure the loneliness.
Man can never completely erase this sadness, because all men are fundamentally alone.
Pain is something that man must endure in his heart.
And since the heart feels pain so easily, some believe life is pain.
So, what do you think about Shinji Ikari?
Oh,
the great third child? He's boring.
And
yet his synchronization ratio was over 40% with no prior training.
Sync ratio zero.
Hey, third child!
Can't be the second child anymore.
You're coming with me.
That's really an interesting color. I didn't know it was red.
Units zero and one were the prototype and test type respectively.
The fact that unit one synchronized with an untrained pilot like you is proof of that.
However, Unit 2 is a little different.
My Unit 2 is the world's first real Evangelion!
Created for actual combat conditions,
it's the final production model!
Whoa! What was that?
Undersea shockwaves!
And it sounded close.
*Sings*
Hello! Guten Morgen, Shinji!
Guten Morgen.
Hey, third child. Why the gloomy face?
I'm the most popular girl in school.
You should appreciate your good fortune.
Hey, the other one's here too, isn't she?
Other one?
What are you, stupid?
I'm talking about the first child, of course.
Oh, Rei Ayanami.
You must be Rei Ayanami, the pilot of the prototype.
I'm Asuka,
Asuka Langley Soryu.
I'm the designated pilot of EVA Unit 2. Let's be good friends.
What for?
Because it would be so convenient. You know what I mean.
If I'm ordered 2, I will do it.
Freakazoid.
How are their coordination drills going?
Not very well, as you can see.
*Sigh*
Sheist! Well, so much for synchronization!
I could never sink down to the level of this animated turnip!
If you ask me, the whole idea is impossible!
Rain?
Yes ma'am?
Why don't you try it?
*Gasp*
I have no reason left to live.
Nobody cares about me anymore.
I am not a doll.
Synchrograph minus 12.8? It's barely over the starting indicator.
That's pathetic. That's a worse score than yesterday.
Asuka
isn't feeling well today. It's her period.
Synch ratios aren't influenced by physical changes.
The problem's deeper in her subconscious.
You know, Asuka's pride has been badly damaged.
It's hard
to blame her after she was defeated so badly.
What's worse is that she feels as if she was beaten by Shinji.
*Squeak*
If you don't
open your mind to her, your Eva will not move.
You're saying this is my fault?! I blocked myself?!
Yes, the Eva has its own mind.
It's just a big toy.
Then you don't know.
Huh! Now I know something's going on when Wonder Girl starts talking to me.
What's up? Are you happy that I'm having trouble with my Eva now?
Well, don't worry, 'cause when the next angel comes, our invincible Shinji will ride out and destroy it!
We sweet little girls won't have to fight anymore!
They only need stupid Shinji! I thought it was bad when he was nice,
but when an emotionless wind-up doll like you starts being sympathetic, I'm doomed.
I am not a doll.
You are! You do anything you're ordered to, don't you?
You'd kill yourself if your commander ordered you to, wouldn't you?
Of course.
Good morning.
Hey, Big Shot, what are you staring so intently at?
Uh, nothing.
Not
that my ass,
he's ogling Ray.
I am not.
Oh, come on.
We
saw you looking.
Yeah, at Ray's mammaries.
Ah!
Ray's silky thighs, her calves, her
naughty bits.
Look, it's nothing like that.
Then just what
were you looking at?
Yeah, come on, fess up, Shinji.
I was just wondering why she's always alone.
Come to think of it, she hasn't had any friends since she started here in the seventh grade.
You two are both Ava pilots, right?
You ought to know her better than any of us, Shinji.
Know what I
mean?
Yeah, that's right.
I suppose,
but we don't talk.
She's a nice girl, but she's like your father.
She's not very adept at...
She's not very adept at what?
Living, I guess.
Hello there.
I'm sorry for intruding.
It's me, Shinji Ikari.
I'm coming in, okay?
Really?
These can't be rays.
Ray, I...
I didn't mean to...
No! What?
*cough*
Will you get off?
Oh,
sorry!
What?
Well, I was asked to...
Well, I was asked to, you know, so I...
What was it?
The card! Your card!
It's been renewed.
So I was asked to deliver it.
I didn't mean for any of this to
happen.
Aren't you afraid of piloting Unit Zero?
Why?
Well, I heard that you were hurt pretty bad in an earlier experiment.
So I thought you might be...
You are Commander Ikari's son, aren't you?
Mm-hmm.
It's his project.
Shouldn't you trust him?
No, of course not!
How
could I ever trust him again?
What?
Ayanami.
Pilot Ikari, I've been sent here to brief you on the Operation Yoshima timetables.
The operation will begin at midnight, 0100 hours.
Prior to that, Pilot Ikari and Ayanami will arrive at the cage by 1730.
At 1800, Unit 0 and Unit 1 will activate.
At 1805, both units will be deployed.
They will arrive at the temporary base at Mount Futago at 1830.
There they will await further orders.
Your meal.
I don't feel like eating anything.
We will depart in 60 minutes.
Do I really have to pilot Ava again?
Yes, you do.
I don't want to. I don't want to go through it again.
Then you can just stay here in bed.
What do you mean?
I will pilot Ewa Unit 1.
Dr. Akagi is already prepared to rewrite the personal data files for Unit 1.
Ritzko is IT'S
GONE, RESERK! STAY BACK!
Goodbye.
Ayanami, just why do you pilot this thing?
Because I'm bonded to it.
You're bonded?
Yes, it's a bond.
You mean to my father?
To all people.
You're very strong, Rei.
I have nothing else.
Goodbye.
Ayanami!
Are you alright?
Don't ever say that.
That you have nothing else.
Please, just don't say that.
And don't say goodbye when you leave on a mission.
It's just too sad.
Why do you cry like that?
I'm very sorry.
I don't know what I should feel or do at a time like this.
Why don't you just try smiling?
Ayanami, with no rifle.
I will go.
If I die, I can be replaced.
An
end to mine!
Ray!
AT field full power.
A dream?
Yeah, don't tell me you don't dream, either.
We must finish this before Sele has time to act.
After all, it's not acceptable to lose Unit 2 at this time.
But you can't just use the Lance of Longinus without getting Sele's approval first.
You can rest today. We'll take care of everything.
But, um, I'm feeling just fine now.
Well, that's good for you.
Ray! Invasive action!
Ray Ayanami, age 14.
The first of the test subjects chosen in accordance with the Marduk Report.
The first child.
Designated pilot for the Evangelion Unit Zero.
Her past has been eradicated.
while her personal records have been erased.
Target invasion of Unit Zero continuing!
Unit Two, take the heat off of
Rey!
Haver Unit Two, lift off!
What are you doing?
Asuka, move out now!
What's wrong?
The pilot sink ratio is under 10%!
Asuka!
It just won't move.
I will go in Unit Two.
This is pain.
Pain?
No, it's different.
Loneliness.
Yes.
This is loneliness.
Am I the one crying?
Ray!
I want Evangelion Unit 1 taken out of cryostasis.
Launch it immediately.
What?
Do it.
Yes, sir.
Why for her?
Am I so worthless you couldn't do
this for me?
Spread your AT field to full! Get Bri out of there now!
Roger.
It smells like Ikari.
Ikari!
Is this my mind and soul? To unite as one with Ikari?
You will not.
Her AT field's been reversed!
I must stay. If I leave Unit Zero, the AT field will cease to be. I will not
let it...
Rey! Don't do it!
The same weather day after day.
Somehow the disappearance of autumn makes this country seem more melancholy.
If the scenario described in Sele's secret Dead Sea Scrolls is correct,
then the third impact will occur in a little over ten years from now.
That's why they created Sele and Gehern, to keep that from happening.
Your intentions are noble.
I wish I could say the same for Sele.
Professor Fyutski, opening the seal in this world would be catastrophic.
Ikari is in charge of the project now,
but it takes more than one person to accomplish something like that.
What happened last time must never be repeated.
I've been sent a warning.
Apparently those bastards would have no qualms about making me disappear.
You or any
of the other survivors.
It's so easy to erase someone.
All the more reason for you not to become the next test subject.
Everything has its place in the flow of life.
That's why I'm a member of Seilei.
For Shinji's sake.
It's been three years since we were last here.
That's when I ran away.
I haven't come back here since then.
I just don't believe that my mom is really resting here.
I don't even remember her face.
Burying memories is a man's way of surviving.
But there are some things a man should never forget.
Yui taught me that one irreplaceable thing, Shinji.
That is the reason I come here to confirm that commitment.
You don't have a picture of her.
No photographs.
Even this grave is an artifice.
Nothing remains.
That's just like my teacher said.
You cast everything away.
Everything is kept in my heart.
And I'm fine with that.
You've always been so cool and analytical about these things.
Aren't you afraid you're going to lose your chance at happiness?
First, I have to find a
definition of happiness.
Gosh, it's been a while since I went out.
Well, have a good one.
Did you need me for something, Ray?
I lost my way, Doctor.
Oh, is that so?
Well, you want to come with me then?
No thanks.
Well, how will you get home all by yourself?
Mind
your business, old hag.
Old
hag?
I can find my way home by myself, old hag.
You shouldn't call someone an old hag, Rey.
But you are an old hag, aren't you?
I'm getting mad.
Commander Akari will spank you for this, you
little--
The commander is the one who calls you that.
He says that old hack is annoying, that old hack is no use anymore.
You little bitch!
It's reactivated!
Oh my god!
This is impossible! It must be wrong!
How can Shinji's sync ratio with Unit 1 be over 400%?
It's finally happened. It's aware.
I'm here.
It's eating the angel.
The S2 engine. She's taking it into herself.
*cough*
It's breaking free!
Free of what?
Those plates weren't just armor, they were also restraints.
Those bindings allowed us to control it, but now, the Eva is removing the web that binds it to our will.
The beast inside the Eva is free at last!
Unit 1's been awakened and set free.
Sele sure won't stay quiet for this.
Was this part of your scenario, Commander Ikari?
It has begun.
Indeed, this is the beginning.
I'm still alive.
Ainami!
I'm so glad.
I can't believe you're alive.
Why isn't my father here?
Anyway, thank you for saving my life.
For doing what?
You saved me.
by sacrificing Unit Zero.
Oh.
Did I save you?
Don't you remember?
I don't
know.
I think I'm probably the
third one.
Oh my god!
It's Ray!
They're all Ray!
You mean the dummy plugs are--
Uh-huh.
These make up the cores of the dummy plugs.
They're what makes the system work.
What are they?
These?
These are empty vessels, nothing but spare parts, spare rays.
Mankind found a god, and man in his folly tried to make the god his toy.
For that arrogance, mankind was punished.
That happened 15 years ago, and the god that man found was lost.
But man continues to attempt to resurrect the god,
And from that god, Adam, man, attempted to make a man who was like a god himself.
And that was Eva.
What? Evas are human?
Yes. Inside the empty shell of each Eva is a human soul.
But the only vessel which can hold a soul is Ray.
These things are empty husks.
They have no souls, no right to live.
The room of Goth is empty.
Stop this! Do you have any idea what you're doing?
Yes, I do. I'm destroying them. These aren't human. Just things with human forms.
You're late!
Sorry, sorry.
Shall we begin?
Sure.
*Sigh*
Reclassify Unit 3 as the 13th Angel.
But the pilot is...
It can't
be.
Is that the angel?
Correct. That is your target.
Shinji, why aren't you fighting?
I
can't!
There's still a person inside that thing!
Irrelevant. It's an angel. Destroy our enemy.
I can't!
If he's still alive, we've got to try and help him!
I just can't kill another human being!
It's him or you!
No! I'd rather be dead!
God! Shut down all of the synchronization circuits in Unit 1 immediately!
Shut them down?
Correct. Switch all control to the dummy plug system.
But
sir, the dummy plug isn't fully operational yet. Dr. Akagi hasn't approved its use!
It's still better than the current pilot! Do it!
Ugh...
What's going on? What the hell are you doing, father?!
Toji was real sorry about everything.
His kid's sister really tore him a new one.
She said it was the robot that saved our lives.
No!
*crying*
Please! Please just stop it!
Make it stop!
Dear God, make it stop!
Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop! Stop!
Father, no!
What shall I cook?
I sure hope he's hungry tomorrow.
Shinji...
I'm... sorry.
The pilot of Unit 3 is...
The fourth child is...
Toji.
Shinji.
Shinji!
Can you tell me what my father's like?
Well, there's a surprise question.
I would have thought you'd ask about Katsuragi.
It seems like you're always with my father.
Commander Fiyutsuki is the one who's always with him.
Have you been asking around about your father?
I just haven't been around him much.
So you really don't know him?
But I've learned a lot about him lately.
I've learned how he feels about his work, about my mother.
No, you're wrong, Shinji.
You only believe that you've learned,
but people can't even really understand themselves, much less each other.
Understanding 100% of anything is impossible.
That's why we spend so much time trying to understand our own motivations and those of others.
That's
what makes life so... interesting.
So you can't understand Misato either.
The kanji that we use for the word she means a woman far away.
And women will always seem to be on a distant shore.
A gulf that separates male and female is deeper than any ocean.
What were you doing in Kyoto?
I wasn't in Kyoto.
Don't try to fool me.
You'll get your fingers burned if you get too involved in this.
That's the advice of a friend.
I'd rather be burned by the heat of my passion for you.
Should I buy you some fireworks, then?
Hello!
You never
change, do you?
Of course I change.
The simple act of living is to embrace change.
Homeostasis and
transistasis.
Homeo
-what?
The
force to maintain the present status and the force for constant change.
All living creatures are an organic battleground for the two conflicting forces.
Like men and women.
Katsuragi, it's me.
I'm sure you're listening to this message, especially after I caused so much trouble.
Sorry.
Please tell Ritsu I'm sorry, too.
And there's one more thing to trouble you with.
I've been growing... flowers.
I'd appreciate it if you could water them for me.
Shinji knows where they are.
Katsuragi, the truth is with you.
Don't hesitate.
Move ahead.
And if I can see you again, I will say the words I could not say eight years ago.
Bye.
You fool.
You were always such a fool.
Hi.
You're a little late, aren't you?
Stop saying such moronic things, you irresponsible jerk!
Why won't you listen to me?
Kaji is dead!
Liar.
The song is good.
Singing brings joy and revitalizes the human soul.
I think that song is the highest achievement of the Lillin culture.
Don't you agree, Shinji Ikari?
How do you know my name?
Everyone knows your name.
I don't mean to sound rude, but you're rather ignorant of your own position.
Really?
Who are
you?
I am Kwaru.
Kwaru Nagisa.
I am like you.
I am one of the selected children.
The fifth child.
You're the fifth child?
Um, Mr. Nagisa...
Call me Kwaru, Mr. Ikari.
Mr. Ikari?
Oh, no.
You can call me Shinji.
It is time. Let us go, Adam's dark shadow, servant of the Lillan.
Ava Unit 2 is
active!
That's impossible. Where's Asuka?
She's in
room 303! I've confirmed it!
Who the hell's inside there?
It's unmanned! The entry plug hasn't even been inserted into Unit 2!
Unmanned? So the fifth child isn't there?
AT field detected in Central Dogma!
EVA 2?
No! The pattern is blue! It's not one of ours!
It's an
angel!
That means that Ritzko is...
The target has passed Defensive Layer 4, and is still descending!
It's no good! We can't cut the power
to the linear motor car!
Evacuate
the area! Seal all shutters and bulkheads surrounding Central Dogma!
We must buy ourselves more time!
Oh dear God in heaven, Sele has delivered an angel to us.
The old man wants to advance his schedule using us as his tools.
Those
who forget the past are doomed to repeat it.
Unless man accepts and atones for his sins, he will never evolve.
The powers possessed
by Adam and the angels were never meant to be abused this way.
We must take the fate of the future into our own hands.
Unit 1 will be our instrument.
Unit 2 has broken through the armored shutters.
The target has been ensured at the second barrier, sir!
Send Unit 1 in to pursue it.
Right!
Under all circumstances, the last Angel must be kept from entering Terminal Dogma.
But why did the Angel take Unit 2?
You don't think it's going to attempt to fuse with Unit 2, do you?
Or will it bring about our total destruction?
No, no, no! It's not possible! I won't believe that Kauru's an angel! It's a lie!
It's a fact, Shinji. You must accept it. Prepare for combat, do you understand?
Shinji, you are late.
Evil Unit 1 descending via Route 2. It's about to make contact with the target.
You betrayed me. You betrayed the trust that I placed in you! You betrayed me just like my father did!
Unit 1 has
reached the fourth layer. It's about to confront the target.
That's him!
I have been waiting for you, Shinji.
Kauru!
Asuka, I'm sorry!
The Eva series was born for man's antithesis, and yet the Lilin will utilize that which they
hate most of all in order to survive?
I do not understand.
Kauru!
Stop!
Why is this happening?
Your
Evas and I are composed of the very same matter.
Born from Adam, I can synchronize with it easily as long as there is no dominant soul.
And Unit 2's soul is now hiding itself.
Thus, Eva Unit 2 is mine.
You've got your own AT field?
Yes, at least that is what you, Lillian, call this thing.
This is the light of my soul, a sacred territory in which no one may intrude.
Aren't you, Lillian, aware that your so-called AT field is merely that wall that encloses your mind?
I don't understand what you're talking about!
*Grunts*
Both Avas have penetrated the final layer!
If Unit 1's signal cuts off or disappears, or if any other change should occur for the worst...
I've got it covered, Major. I'm ready to destroy this entire compound. It's better than letting Third Impact take place.
I'm sorry.
It's alright. Dying beside you wouldn't be a bad way to go out.
Thank you.
This is mankind's fate. The thread of human hope is spun with the flax of sorrow.
What the hell is that?
It's another AT field! The strongest we've ever detected!
It's shutting out everything! Light, magnetism, subatomic particles!
It's blocking everything out?
It can't sense anything! The target, Unit 1, Unit 2, they're all gone!
We lost communication with the pilot!
Karu, no!
Karu!
Terminal safety has been penetrated.
They've reached it. Heaven's door is open.
Then the Angel has finally reached its goal.
Get ready.
*Screams*
What's that? What's going on?
It's
another AT field! A field as strong as the first one has appeared around Terminal Dogma.
I don't believe it! It's breaking through the other AT field!
What is it? Another Angel?
I don't know! I can't confirm it! My God! It totally disappeared!
Disappeared? The angel?
Adam, that from which we came.
Must one who was born from Adam return to Adam, even though it will destroy man?
Wait, but this is not... Lilith.
I see. I understand now. The Lilin. Lilith.
I thank you, Shinji. I wanted you to take Unit 2 from me.
Otherwise, with her protection, I would have been able to survive much longer.
Karu, but why?
It
is my destiny to live forever, though it will destroy the Lilin.
However, it is possible for me to be killed, and whether I live or die makes no great difference.
The one truth the Lillian have never been able to grasp is that death may be the only absolute freedom there ever was.
What are you?
Karu, I don't
understand what you're talking about.
Please, don't make me do this.
This is my wish.
I want you to destroy me.
Otherwise, you will be destroyed.
Only one life form can be chosen to evade the destruction and seize the future.
and you are not the existence which should die.
You need the future.
It is what you live for.
I thank you, Shinji Ikari.
My life was meaningful because of you.
Misato and Ayanami scare me.
Help me.
Help me, Asuka.
Hey.
Quit fooling around.
Come on.
Asuka, wake up.
This isn't funny anymore.
Asuka, wake up!
Asuka!
Help me.
Asuka, please help me.
I need you.
Please, Asuka, help me.
Call me an idiot like you always do.
Just say something, damn it.
Please, wake up!
I'm so fucked up.
All access to and from headquarters has been restricted.
We're on
first level alert.
That doesn't make sense. I thought Kwaru was the last angel.
He was. All the angels have been defeated.
So if we're all safe, then what are we doing on first level alert?
What's going to happen to Nerve and the Evas?
I wish Dr. Akagi was here.
Well,
I think Nerve is probably just going to be disbanded.
And I don't even want to think about what they're planning to do with us.
All we can do is wait and see.
So mankind, a race of flawed and incomplete separate entities, has reached the end of its evolutionary potential.
The Instrumentality Project will manufacture the evolution of man's separate entities into a single consummate being.
And the Committee won't use Nerve or Atom.
They'll use the Evas.
Just like Kaji said they would.
The time is at hand.
Without the Lance of Longinus, we cannot use Lilith to complete the project.
Our only hope is to proceed using Lilith's only true offspring, Eva Unit One.
That was not part of Sele's original plan.
Creating the Evangelion was the pinnacle of mankind's existence.
Humanity must evolve and shape this brave new world.
That was why we created the Eva series.
We need not cast aside our human form to use Evangelion as our own private arc.
It's merely part of the process to free us all for rebirth.
The fate of destruction is also the joy of rebirth.
Through the sacrament of death, God, humanity, and all living beings will be united and reborn as one.
Death creates nothing.
Your death will create an opportunity.
Mankind exists because it has the will to live.
After all, that's why she chose to remain in the Ava.
So... that's what really happened during the second impact.
They're on to me.
No wait. Something else.
Showtime.
Transfer the left circuits to the emergency communication systems. Use satellite feed if you have to.
Correct. What's the right side status?
Negative. All outgoing network lines are being systematically cut off.
They're going after the Magi.
Data upload from external
terminals. Sir, it looks like they're trying to hack into the Magi.
Just as I thought. Is the uplink coming from the Magi 2 and Matsushiro?
No. There are five Magi systems working together. I've identified Germany, China, and the US.
So Sele is pooling all its resources. Five Magi working against one. Not good odds.
The fourth firewall has been
breached!
Locking the main database! Negative! The system is being overtaken!
They've breached the next level! The backup system didn't even slow them down!
This is bad.
If they capture the Magi, it's all over for us.
Let me guess. They need help with the Magi's self-defense system.
That's right. Report to the Second Command Center, where you will be briefed by Lieutenant Ibuki.
He
expects the woman he abandoned to jump when he calls. Arrogant bastard.
Talk to me, Hyuga.
Tokyo-2 is launched. Special Order A-801.
What's that supposed to mean?
Nerves, legal protection, and jurisdiction have been revoked. Command has been transferred to the Japanese government.
They only gave us one warning.
It's a mess up here. They tried to take over the Magi, but we've been able to minimize most of the damage so far.
Ibuki here. Dr. Akagi is currently installing additional defense programs.
Huh?
Ritsuko?
Am I doing something stupid?
The interaction between men and women is so illogical.
Isn't that right?
Mother.
How much longer?
We should make it.
Dr. Akagi is amazing.
One more minute and she'll
be at page 020
in the manual.
Just hacking into the Magi?
Yeah, right.
Doubt they're going to let us off that easily.
The Magi was just foreplay.
Sele is planning to launch an all-out offensive against headquarters and take the two Evas by force, aren't they?
Of course. We have both Adam and Lilith.
No wonder the old bastards are so nervous.
External feed to the Magi has been halted. A Da Nang B-type defense program is in place.
External access has been cut off for the next 62 hours.
Well, Mother, I'll see you soon.
Ikari has installed a Type 666 firewall on the Magi's external feed circuits.
That's very difficult to breach.
Apparently we will have to forgo acquisition of the Tokyo Three Magi.
I had hoped to settle this peacefully, but he leaves me no choice.
Launch the invasion forces immediately.
Showtime, ladies.
All units move out.
We've lost the
The radar feed from sectors 8 through 17.
A large detachment of special force units has invaded the outer defense perimeter.
Two more units are in the Gotemba sector.
After
all we've been through, our final enemy is our fellow man.
All
personnel go to level one battle stations.
Battle stations?
This isn't an angel attack.
We can't kill humans.
I wish those bastards felt the same way.
Huh? What's happening? Hey!
What's wrong?
Transmission from the southern hub has been interrupted.
Uh...
Southern Hub Station has gone silent.
The West Side attack is just a decoy.
If they're really after the Evas, they'll go after the pilots first.
Tell Shinji to stand by in Unit 1, got it?
Roger.
Where's
Asuka?
She's still in recovery.
Get her suited up and get her in Unit 2!
Asuka's barely conscious. There's no way she'll be able to synchronize.
If they find her, they're going to kill her. If we put her in Unit 2, at least she'll be safe.
Understood, ma'am. Cease Pilot's medical treatment and prepare her for launch.
As soon as Asuka's in there, stow
Unit 2 at the bottom of the lake.
It's not the best hiding place, but it's better than the cage. Where's Rey?
Unable to locate. Pilot of Unit 0 is missing.
They will kill her. Find her now.
Launching Unit 2 via Gate Number 8. The airway will remain at a depth of 70 meters.
Get ready to deploy Unit 1! Station it in the geo-front!
We can't! Shinji isn't there!
Oh dear god.
The number three underground barricade has been destroyed.
Enemy forces have begun evading level two.
There's nothing
more that we can do to hold them off.
Our defeat has become inevitable.
Professor Friutski, take care of this please.
Yes, Commander. Please give my regards to Yui.
Internal monorail track
57 has been destroyed!
This is brutal.
I'd rather be fighting the angels.
Of course we don't normally fight human enemies.
Sever those cables!
Start with the red ones!
- Hit 'em again.
-
- Level
3 block B has been invaded! - There's
no stopping them! - Enemy presence
confirmed in block F. The main bypass
is under fire!
- Seal off
levels 1 through 3. Order a full
retreat. Release Bakelite
infusion in all passages through section 803. - Right!
Well, that should buy us some time.
Major Katsuragi, Route 47 is completely blocked.
The third unit can't move forward.
Shinji is totally cut off.
All non-combat personnel should avoid engaging the enemy.
These guys are pros, so if you can't retreat to Central Dogma, you're better off just surrendering.
Take care of things here for me.
Right.
This is harder
than we thought.
We never get the easy jobs.
This is insane.
The center was made to withstand angel attacks, not invading armies.
Safety off.
Yeah, we could barely hold off terrorists.
If the
JSSDF decides to mount an all-out invasion, we're totally screwed.
Slowly
but surely they've been cutting our defense budget.
I wouldn't be surprised if they've been planning this from the very beginning.
I wouldn't be surprised either.
*Gasp
*
*Gasp*
Release the safety.
I can't! I just can't shoot this thing, Aoba!
Of course you can! You've had basic training!
But
I shot at targets, not at other human beings!
Idiot! You kill or you die!
Rey.
I knew I'd find you here.
The time has come. Let's go.
Level 1 has been secured.
Over.
Roger that.
We are moving in on the Magi in the Level 2 Command Center.
We are currently engaged in combat.
Please, Jesus, please, please, Jesus.
Command the
cooling of the Pitma Bulge sector immediately.
Terminate EVA pilots on site. Execution of non-combat personnel has been authorized.
Yanagihara and Shinjo units, proceed to lower level.
We've located the third child,
commencing termination.
Sorry kid, nothing personal.
Hey, no offense taken.
Let's get you to Unit 1. Come on.
What's the status of Detachment 7? Have you reached the cage?
Over?
Roger that! We have the purple unit surrounded. The Bakelight infusion was not a problem.
The red unit has been launched. We're attempting to
establish which launch route was used. Over.
Damn. They're trying to prevent contacts between Shinji and Unit 1.
We're running out of time.
This is it, Shinji. Do you want to run away, or do you want to pilot the Eva?
It's your call.
If you sit there and do nothing, then you're already dead.
Help me, Asuka. Help me.
Hiding behind the skirts of a little girl at a time like this?
Snap out of it!
Giving up halfway is worse than never trying at all.
Come on!
Get up!
Move it!
I... I want to die.
Just leave me here.
Stop talking like a stubborn little brat!
Like it or not, you're still alive.
Get moving and do something.
You can die later.
Unimportant.
Securing Terminal Dogma is your number one priority.
Understand?
They've destroyed just about everything else.
Why don't they just nuke us and get it over with already?
Hey, if we weren't sitting on top of the original Magi system,
they probably would have blown us to bits by now.
I guess that would explain why they haven't used any explosives yet.
I just hope they don't start using BC weapons.
Things could get pretty ugly.
That or in two minds.
*Clears*
Speak of the devil. Damn
haven't you ever heard of moderation?
That was a little much
Why can't they possibly want Eva this badly?
They plan to initiate third impact using the Eva series instead of the Angels.
Fifteen years ago, second impact was intentionally engineered by mankind,
because it was the only way to minimize the potential damage.
They had to reduce Adam to an embryonic state before the other Angels awoke.
You see, Shinji, mankind was spawned from a being called Lilith, just like Adam was.
We are the 18th angel.
The other angels are just different possibilities, what we could have become.
They're humans who rejected our human form.
Sadly, we cannot coexist together, even though we are fundamentally the same creatures.
Listen, Shinji, you're going to have to destroy the rest of the Eva series.
It's the only way to stay alive.
The phone lines are all dead.
Yes, sir. Missile impact
was confirmed three minutes ago.
This instrumentality project Nerve was secretly researching,
trying to initiate third impact and destroy all of mankind.
The whole thing makes me sick.
Humanity is probably the only creature capable of hating its own kind.
Well then, I suppose all we have left to do is to destroy Nerve headquarters.
Should Germany or China begin redevelopment?
No.
We won't make the same mistake twice.
Make sure no one can touch it for the next 20 years. Like old Tokyo.
Surface heat has dissipated. High-pressure steam discharges have also stopped.
All detachments positions have been confirmed.
Dogma Level 3 and the purple unit are currently secured.
What about the red one?
It's in the lake about 70 meters down, Commander.
We can't determine whether or not the pilot is alive or dead.
I'm still alive.
*cough*
*Screaming*
Don't wanna die x3
I don't wanna die I don't wanna die I don't wanna die I don't wanna die
I DON'T WANNA DIE
Mama, You've been here all along?
Mama?
What the hell is that?
Dear God!
Schwein hunt!
Mama! Mama! Now I understand!
The meaning of the AT field!
You were always protecting me!
Always watching over me!
Always! We were always together, Mama!
Epa Unit 2 has activated! Asuka is okay! She's alive!
Asuka!
The cable! Focus on the cable! Use whatever you can to sever it!
Scheist.
Even without my umbilical cable attached, I've still got 12,000 plates of fortified armor!
And I've got my AT field!
There's no way I can lose!
Eat this, ah schnook!
That loathsome Evangelion.
Once again our plans will go unrealized. It seems we'll have to fight fire with fire.
The Eva series has been completed.